<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_HUNS_BLEDA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Bleda[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Also known as Buda. Hun ruler and brother of Attila the Hun.[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c. 390 - 445[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]As nephews to Ruga, Bleda and his younger brother Attila succeeded him to the throne. His reign lasted for eleven years until his death.[NEWLINE][TAB]By 432, the Huns were united under Ruga. His death in 434 left his nephews Bleda and Attila (the sons of his brother Mundzuk) in control over all the united Hun tribes. At the time of their accession, the Huns were bargaining with Byzantine emperor Theodosius II's envoys over the return of several renegade tribes who had taken refuge within the Byzantine Empire. The following year, Bleda és Attila met with the imperial legation at Margus and, all seated on horseback in the Hunnic manner, negotiated a successful treaty: the Romans agreed not only to return the fugitive tribes (who had been a welcome aid against the Vandals), but also to double their previous tribute of 350 Roman pounds (ca. 114.5 kg) of gold, open their markets to Hunnish traders, and pay a ransom of eight solidi for each Roman taken prisoner by the Huns. The Huns, satisfied with the treaty, decamped from the empire and returned to their home, perhaps to consolidate and strengthen their empire.[NEWLINE][TAB]For the next five years, the Huns stayed out of Roman sight as they tried to invade the Persian Empire. A defeat in Armenia caused them to abandon this attempt and return their attentions to Europe. In 440, they reappeared on the borders of the Roman Empire, attacking the merchants at the market on the north bank of the Danube that had been established by the treaty. Bleda and Attila threatened further war, claiming that the Romans had failed to fulfill their treaty obligations and that the Bishop of Margus had crossed the Danube to ransack and desecrate the royal Hun graves on the Danube's north bank. They crossed the Danube and laid waste to Illyrian cities and forts on the river. Their advance began at Margus, for when the Romans discussed handing over the offending bishop, he slipped away secretly to the Huns and betrayed the city to them.[NEWLINE][TAB]Theodosius had stripped the river's defenses, this left Bleda and Attila a clear path through Illyria into the Balkans, which they invaded in 441. The Hunnish army, having sacked Margus and Viminacium, took Singidunum and Sirmium before halting. A lull followed in 442, and, during this time, Theodosius recalled his troops from North Africa and ordered a large new issue of coins to finance operations against the Huns. Having made these preparations, he thought it safe to refuse the Hunnish kings' demands.[NEWLINE][TAB]Bleda and Attila responded by renewing their campaign in 443. Striking along the Danube, they overran the military centers of Ratiaria and successfully besieged Naissus with battering rams and rolling towers (military sophistication that was new to the Hun repertory), then, pushing along the Nisava, they took Serdica, Philippopolis and Arcadiopolis. They encountered and destroyed the Roman force outside Constantinople and were only halted by their lack of siege equipment capable of breaching the city's massive walls. Theodosius admitted defeat and sent the court official Anatolius to negotiate peace terms, which were harsher than the previous treaty: the Emperor agreed to hand over 6,000 Roman pounds (ca. 1,963 kg) of gold as punishment for having disobeyed the terms of the treaty during the invasion; the yearly tribute was tripled, rising to 2,100 Roman pounds (ca. 687 kg) in gold; and the ransom for each Roman prisoner rose to twelve solidi.[NEWLINE][TAB]Their demands met for a time, the Hun kings withdrew into the interior of their empire. Sometime during the peace following the Huns' withdrawal from Byzantium (probably around 445), Bleda died and Attila took the throne for himself. While it has been speculated throughout history that Attila murdered him on a hunting trip, it is unknown exactly how he died. However there is an alternative theory that Bleda attempted to kill Attila on a hunting trip, but Attila being a skilled warrior defeated Bleda.[NEWLINE][TAB]According to medieval chronicles, the city Buda (now part of Budapest) was named after Bleda, which is, why Bleda is often referred to as Buda in Hungarian literature.</English>
		<French>[H1]Bleda[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Also known as Buda. Hun ruler and brother of Attila the Hun.[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c. 390 - 445[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]As nephews to Ruga, Bleda and his younger brother Attila succeeded him to the throne. His reign lasted for eleven years until his death.[NEWLINE][TAB]By 432, the Huns were united under Ruga. His death in 434 left his nephews Bleda and Attila (the sons of his brother Mundzuk) in control over all the united Hun tribes. At the time of their accession, the Huns were bargaining with Byzantine emperor Theodosius II's envoys over the return of several renegade tribes who had taken refuge within the Byzantine Empire. The following year, Bleda és Attila met with the imperial legation at Margus and, all seated on horseback in the Hunnic manner, negotiated a successful treaty: the Romans agreed not only to return the fugitive tribes (who had been a welcome aid against the Vandals), but also to double their previous tribute of 350 Roman pounds (ca. 114.5 kg) of gold, open their markets to Hunnish traders, and pay a ransom of eight solidi for each Roman taken prisoner by the Huns. The Huns, satisfied with the treaty, decamped from the empire and returned to their home, perhaps to consolidate and strengthen their empire.[NEWLINE][TAB]For the next five years, the Huns stayed out of Roman sight as they tried to invade the Persian Empire. A defeat in Armenia caused them to abandon this attempt and return their attentions to Europe. In 440, they reappeared on the borders of the Roman Empire, attacking the merchants at the market on the north bank of the Danube that had been established by the treaty. Bleda and Attila threatened further war, claiming that the Romans had failed to fulfill their treaty obligations and that the Bishop of Margus had crossed the Danube to ransack and desecrate the royal Hun graves on the Danube's north bank. They crossed the Danube and laid waste to Illyrian cities and forts on the river. Their advance began at Margus, for when the Romans discussed handing over the offending bishop, he slipped away secretly to the Huns and betrayed the city to them.[NEWLINE][TAB]Theodosius had stripped the river's defenses, this left Bleda and Attila a clear path through Illyria into the Balkans, which they invaded in 441. The Hunnish army, having sacked Margus and Viminacium, took Singidunum and Sirmium before halting. A lull followed in 442, and, during this time, Theodosius recalled his troops from North Africa and ordered a large new issue of coins to finance operations against the Huns. Having made these preparations, he thought it safe to refuse the Hunnish kings' demands.[NEWLINE][TAB]Bleda and Attila responded by renewing their campaign in 443. Striking along the Danube, they overran the military centers of Ratiaria and successfully besieged Naissus with battering rams and rolling towers (military sophistication that was new to the Hun repertory), then, pushing along the Nisava, they took Serdica, Philippopolis and Arcadiopolis. They encountered and destroyed the Roman force outside Constantinople and were only halted by their lack of siege equipment capable of breaching the city's massive walls. Theodosius admitted defeat and sent the court official Anatolius to negotiate peace terms, which were harsher than the previous treaty: the Emperor agreed to hand over 6,000 Roman pounds (ca. 1,963 kg) of gold as punishment for having disobeyed the terms of the treaty during the invasion; the yearly tribute was tripled, rising to 2,100 Roman pounds (ca. 687 kg) in gold; and the ransom for each Roman prisoner rose to twelve solidi.[NEWLINE][TAB]Their demands met for a time, the Hun kings withdrew into the interior of their empire. Sometime during the peace following the Huns' withdrawal from Byzantium (probably around 445), Bleda died and Attila took the throne for himself. While it has been speculated throughout history that Attila murdered him on a hunting trip, it is unknown exactly how he died. However there is an alternative theory that Bleda attempted to kill Attila on a hunting trip, but Attila being a skilled warrior defeated Bleda.[NEWLINE][TAB]According to medieval chronicles, the city Buda (now part of Budapest) was named after Bleda, which is, why Bleda is often referred to as Buda in Hungarian literature.</French>
		<German>[H1]Bleda[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Auch als Buda bekannt. König der Hunnen und älterer Bruder von Attila dem Hunnen[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lebte:[\BOLD] 390 - 445[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Als Neffen Rugas folgten ihm Bleda und sein Bruder Attila auf den Thron. Er herrschte 11 Jahre bis zu seinem Tod.[NEWLINE][TAB]432 einigte Ruga die Hunnen. Nach seinem Tod übernahmen seine Neffen Bleda und Attila (die Söhne Mundzuks, Bruder von Ruga) die Herrschaft über die vereinigten Stämme der Hunnen. Etwa zu der Zeit ihrer Machtübernahme verhandelten die Hunnen mit dem Gesandten des Kaisers Theodosius II. von Byzanz über die Rückkehr einiger abtrünniger Stämme der Hunnen, die nach Byzanz geflohen waren. Im Darauffolgenden Jahr trafen sich Bleda und Attila in Margus mit der Gesandtschaft und handelten, wie es bei den Hunnen Sitte war auf Pferden sitzend, erfolgreich einen Vertrag aus: Die Römer waren nicht nur damit einverstanden, die abtrünnigen Stämme zurückzuschicken (die eine willkommene Verstärkung gegen die Vandalen waren), sondern auch den bisherigen Tribut von 350 römischen Pfund (etwa 114,5kg) Gold zu verdoppeln, ihre Märkte für hunnische Kaufleute zu öffnen und für jeden römischen Gefangenen 8 Solidus Lösegeld zu zahlen. Die Hunnen waren zufrieden, verließen das Kaiserreich und kehrten heim um ihre Macht zu sichern und auszubauen.[NEWLINE][TAB]In den nächsten 5 Jahren blieben die Hunnen dem Römischen Reich fern, da sie mit einem Feldzug gegen das Persische Reich beschäftigt waren. Eine Niederlage in Armenien zwang sie jedoch den Feldzug abzubrechen und lenkte ihre Aufmerksamkeit wieder auf Europa. 440 erschienen sie wieder an den Grenzen des Römischen Reiches und griffen Händler auf dem Markt am Nordufer der Donau an, der im Rahmen des Vertrages gegründet wurde. Bleda und Attila beschuldigten das Römische Reich den Vertrag verletzt zu haben und den Bischof von Margus die Donau überquert und die Gräber der hunnischen Könige am Nordufer der Donau geplündert und entweiht zu haben und drohten mit weiterem Krieg. Die Hunnen überquerten die Donau und verwüsteten illyrische Städte und Befestigungsanlagen entlang der Donau. Ihr Vormarsch begann bei Margus: während die Römer noch über die Auslieferung des beschuldigten Bischofs diskutierten, schlich sich dieser zu den Hunnen und verriet die Stadt an sie.[NEWLINE][TAB]Theodosius hatte zuvor die Verteidigung an der Donau ausgedünnt und ließ Bleda und Attila so einen Weg durch Illyrien bis zum Balkan, den sie 441 angriffen. Die hunnische Streitmacht plünderte Margus und Viminacium und besetzten Singidunum und Sirmium, dort machten sie Halt. Eine Waffenruhe folgte 442 und Theodosius rief seine Truppen aus Nordafrika zurück und ließ neue Münzen ausgeben um weitere Schritte gegen die Hunnen zu finanzieren. So vorbereitet, war er der Ansicht, dass er die Forderungen der Hunnen gefahrlos ablehnen konnte.[NEWLINE][TAB]443 setzten Bleda und Attila ihren Feldzug fort. Sie schlugen am Donauufer zu, überrannten den Militärstützpunkt bei Ritiaria und belagerten erfolgreich Naissus mit Rammböcken und Belagerungsturm (die neue Belagerungswaffen im Repertoire der Hunnen waren). Dann marschierten sie entlang der Nisava vor und nahmen Serdica, Philippopolis und Arcadiopolis ein. In der Nähe von Konstantinopel trafen sie auf die römischen Verteidigungskräfte und rieben sie auf. Erst mangels ausreichender Belagerungsausrüstung mussten sie bei Konstantinopel, dessen starke Mauern sie nicht durchbrechen konnten, ihren Feldzug beenden. Theodosius erkannte seine Niederlage an und schickte den Gesandten des Hofes, Anatolius, um Frieden zu schließen. Die Bedingungen waren jedoch strenger als zuvor: der Kaiser hatte 6000 römische Pfund (etwa 1963kg) Gold wegen der Verletzung des früheren Vertrages zu entrichten, der jährliche Tribut wurde verdreifachte sich auf 2100 römische Pfund (etwa 687kg) Gold und das Lösegeld stieg auf 12 Solidus an.[NEWLINE][TAB]Ihre Forderung wurden erfüllt und die hunnischen Könige zogen sich in ihr Reich zurück. Irgendwann im auf den Feldzug gegen Byzanz folgenden Frieden, wahrscheinlich 445, starb Bleda und Attila wurde zum Alleinherrscher. Obwohl vermutet wird, dass Attila Bleda während einer Jagd tötete, sind die genauen Umstände seines Todes nicht sicher. Eine alternative Theorie geht davon aus, dass Bleda versuchte seinen Bruder zu ermorden, jedoch konnte Attila ihn besiegen.[NEWLINE][TAB]Laut mittelalterlichen Chroniken geht der Name der steht Buda (heute ein Stadtteil Budapests) auf Bleda zurück, deshalb wurde die Figur des Königs Bleda in der ungarischen Literatur als Buda bekannt.</German>
		<Italian>[H1]Bleda[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Also known as Buda. Hun ruler and brother of Attila the Hun.[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c. 390 - 445[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]As nephews to Ruga, Bleda and his younger brother Attila succeeded him to the throne. His reign lasted for eleven years until his death.[NEWLINE][TAB]By 432, the Huns were united under Ruga. His death in 434 left his nephews Bleda and Attila (the sons of his brother Mundzuk) in control over all the united Hun tribes. At the time of their accession, the Huns were bargaining with Byzantine emperor Theodosius II's envoys over the return of several renegade tribes who had taken refuge within the Byzantine Empire. The following year, Bleda és Attila met with the imperial legation at Margus and, all seated on horseback in the Hunnic manner, negotiated a successful treaty: the Romans agreed not only to return the fugitive tribes (who had been a welcome aid against the Vandals), but also to double their previous tribute of 350 Roman pounds (ca. 114.5 kg) of gold, open their markets to Hunnish traders, and pay a ransom of eight solidi for each Roman taken prisoner by the Huns. The Huns, satisfied with the treaty, decamped from the empire and returned to their home, perhaps to consolidate and strengthen their empire.[NEWLINE][TAB]For the next five years, the Huns stayed out of Roman sight as they tried to invade the Persian Empire. A defeat in Armenia caused them to abandon this attempt and return their attentions to Europe. In 440, they reappeared on the borders of the Roman Empire, attacking the merchants at the market on the north bank of the Danube that had been established by the treaty. Bleda and Attila threatened further war, claiming that the Romans had failed to fulfill their treaty obligations and that the Bishop of Margus had crossed the Danube to ransack and desecrate the royal Hun graves on the Danube's north bank. They crossed the Danube and laid waste to Illyrian cities and forts on the river. Their advance began at Margus, for when the Romans discussed handing over the offending bishop, he slipped away secretly to the Huns and betrayed the city to them.[NEWLINE][TAB]Theodosius had stripped the river's defenses, this left Bleda and Attila a clear path through Illyria into the Balkans, which they invaded in 441. The Hunnish army, having sacked Margus and Viminacium, took Singidunum and Sirmium before halting. A lull followed in 442, and, during this time, Theodosius recalled his troops from North Africa and ordered a large new issue of coins to finance operations against the Huns. Having made these preparations, he thought it safe to refuse the Hunnish kings' demands.[NEWLINE][TAB]Bleda and Attila responded by renewing their campaign in 443. Striking along the Danube, they overran the military centers of Ratiaria and successfully besieged Naissus with battering rams and rolling towers (military sophistication that was new to the Hun repertory), then, pushing along the Nisava, they took Serdica, Philippopolis and Arcadiopolis. They encountered and destroyed the Roman force outside Constantinople and were only halted by their lack of siege equipment capable of breaching the city's massive walls. Theodosius admitted defeat and sent the court official Anatolius to negotiate peace terms, which were harsher than the previous treaty: the Emperor agreed to hand over 6,000 Roman pounds (ca. 1,963 kg) of gold as punishment for having disobeyed the terms of the treaty during the invasion; the yearly tribute was tripled, rising to 2,100 Roman pounds (ca. 687 kg) in gold; and the ransom for each Roman prisoner rose to twelve solidi.[NEWLINE][TAB]Their demands met for a time, the Hun kings withdrew into the interior of their empire. Sometime during the peace following the Huns' withdrawal from Byzantium (probably around 445), Bleda died and Attila took the throne for himself. While it has been speculated throughout history that Attila murdered him on a hunting trip, it is unknown exactly how he died. However there is an alternative theory that Bleda attempted to kill Attila on a hunting trip, but Attila being a skilled warrior defeated Bleda.[NEWLINE][TAB]According to medieval chronicles, the city Buda (now part of Budapest) was named after Bleda, which is, why Bleda is often referred to as Buda in Hungarian literature.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[H1]Bleda[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Also known as Buda. Hun ruler and brother of Attila the Hun.[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c. 390 - 445[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]As nephews to Ruga, Bleda and his younger brother Attila succeeded him to the throne. His reign lasted for eleven years until his death.[NEWLINE][TAB]By 432, the Huns were united under Ruga. His death in 434 left his nephews Bleda and Attila (the sons of his brother Mundzuk) in control over all the united Hun tribes. At the time of their accession, the Huns were bargaining with Byzantine emperor Theodosius II's envoys over the return of several renegade tribes who had taken refuge within the Byzantine Empire. The following year, Bleda és Attila met with the imperial legation at Margus and, all seated on horseback in the Hunnic manner, negotiated a successful treaty: the Romans agreed not only to return the fugitive tribes (who had been a welcome aid against the Vandals), but also to double their previous tribute of 350 Roman pounds (ca. 114.5 kg) of gold, open their markets to Hunnish traders, and pay a ransom of eight solidi for each Roman taken prisoner by the Huns. The Huns, satisfied with the treaty, decamped from the empire and returned to their home, perhaps to consolidate and strengthen their empire.[NEWLINE][TAB]For the next five years, the Huns stayed out of Roman sight as they tried to invade the Persian Empire. A defeat in Armenia caused them to abandon this attempt and return their attentions to Europe. In 440, they reappeared on the borders of the Roman Empire, attacking the merchants at the market on the north bank of the Danube that had been established by the treaty. Bleda and Attila threatened further war, claiming that the Romans had failed to fulfill their treaty obligations and that the Bishop of Margus had crossed the Danube to ransack and desecrate the royal Hun graves on the Danube's north bank. They crossed the Danube and laid waste to Illyrian cities and forts on the river. Their advance began at Margus, for when the Romans discussed handing over the offending bishop, he slipped away secretly to the Huns and betrayed the city to them.[NEWLINE][TAB]Theodosius had stripped the river's defenses, this left Bleda and Attila a clear path through Illyria into the Balkans, which they invaded in 441. The Hunnish army, having sacked Margus and Viminacium, took Singidunum and Sirmium before halting. A lull followed in 442, and, during this time, Theodosius recalled his troops from North Africa and ordered a large new issue of coins to finance operations against the Huns. Having made these preparations, he thought it safe to refuse the Hunnish kings' demands.[NEWLINE][TAB]Bleda and Attila responded by renewing their campaign in 443. Striking along the Danube, they overran the military centers of Ratiaria and successfully besieged Naissus with battering rams and rolling towers (military sophistication that was new to the Hun repertory), then, pushing along the Nisava, they took Serdica, Philippopolis and Arcadiopolis. They encountered and destroyed the Roman force outside Constantinople and were only halted by their lack of siege equipment capable of breaching the city's massive walls. Theodosius admitted defeat and sent the court official Anatolius to negotiate peace terms, which were harsher than the previous treaty: the Emperor agreed to hand over 6,000 Roman pounds (ca. 1,963 kg) of gold as punishment for having disobeyed the terms of the treaty during the invasion; the yearly tribute was tripled, rising to 2,100 Roman pounds (ca. 687 kg) in gold; and the ransom for each Roman prisoner rose to twelve solidi.[NEWLINE][TAB]Their demands met for a time, the Hun kings withdrew into the interior of their empire. Sometime during the peace following the Huns' withdrawal from Byzantium (probably around 445), Bleda died and Attila took the throne for himself. While it has been speculated throughout history that Attila murdered him on a hunting trip, it is unknown exactly how he died. However there is an alternative theory that Bleda attempted to kill Attila on a hunting trip, but Attila being a skilled warrior defeated Bleda.[NEWLINE][TAB]According to medieval chronicles, the city Buda (now part of Budapest) was named after Bleda, which is, why Bleda is often referred to as Buda in Hungarian literature.</Spanish>
		<Hungarian>[H1]Bleda[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Más néven Buda. Hun uralkodó és Attila hun király testvére.[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Élt:[\BOLD] 390 - 445[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Háttér:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Ruga unokaöccseiként õ és testvére Attila követték a trónon. Tizenegy éven át uralkodott, 445-ben bekövetkezett haláláig.[NEWLINE][TAB]432-ben, Ruga egyesítette a Hunokat. Halála után, unokaöccsei Bleda és Attila (Ruga testvére Mundzsuk fiai) átvették az egyesített hun törzsek uralkodását. Hatalomátvételük idején, a Hunok tárgyalták Bizánc császár II. Theodosius küldöncével, elpártolt hun törzsök visszatérésükrõl, akik Bizáncba menekültek. A következõ évben, Bleda és Attila Margusban találkozták a császári küldöttséggel és, hun szokás szerint lován hátán tárgyalva, sikeresen megállapodták egy szerzõdést: a Rómáik nem csak abba beegyezték, hogy visszaküldjék az elpártolt törzseket (akik hasznos erõsítések voltak a Vandálok ellen), hanem hogy megduplázzak is az eddigi 350 római pond (kb. 114,5 kg) arany sarcot, megnyitják a piacukat hun kereskedõknek és hogy minden római fogolyért fizessenek nyolc solidust váltságdíjként. A hunok ezzel megelégedtek, elhagyták a császárságot és visszatértek otthonukba, hogy megszilárdítsák és erõsítsék hatalmukat.[NEWLINE][TAB]A következõ öt évben, a hunok távol maradták a Rómáiktól, mivel hadjáratot indították a Perzsa birodalom ellen. Örményországi vereségük után, a hadjáratnak véget vettek és újra Európára terelték figyelmüket. 440-ben újra megjelentek a Római Birodalom határain, kereskedõket támadva a Duna északi parti piacon, amelyet a szerzõdés során nyitották. Bleda és Attila további háborúval fenyegettek, arra hivatkozva, hogy a Rómáik nem tartottak be a szerzõdés rendelkezéseit és hogy a Margusi püspök átlépte a Dunát és megfosztogatta és megszentségtelenítette a hun királyok sírjait a Duna északi partján. A Hunok átlépték a Dunát és feldúltatták illír városokat és erõdítményeket a folyó közelében. Elõnyomulásukat Margusnál kezdték: miközben a Rómáik a sértõ püspök átadáson vitatkozták, õ elsomfordált a Hunokhoz és aláárulta nekik a várost.[NEWLINE][TAB]Theodosius korábban ritkította a védelmét a Dunán, így szabad pályát engedett  Bleda és Attilának Illírián keresztül a Balkánba, amelyet megtámadták 441-ben. A hun hadsereg kifosztotta Margust és Viminaciumot és elfoglalták Singidunumot és Sirmiumot, majd megállták. Egy harci szünet bekövetkezett 442-ben és Theodosius visszahívta hadseregét Északafrikából és kiadott új érméket, hogy fizetni tudjon Hunok elleni intézkedéseket. Így elõkészítve azt gondolta, hogy biztonságos visszautasítani a Hunok követelményeket.[NEWLINE][TAB]Bleda és Attila 443-ben fojtották hadjáratukat. Ütköztek a Duna parton, majd lerohanták a katonai támaszpontokat Ritiariánál és sikeresen ostromolták Naissust, faltörõ kosokat és ostrombástyákat használva (amelyek új ostromeszközök voltak a Hunok repertoárban). A Nisava mentén elõrenyomulták és elfoglalták Serdicát, Philippopolist és Arcadiopolist. Összecsapták a római véderõvel és elpusztították õket Konstantinápoly közelében, majd csak az elegendõ ostromeszközök hiánya megállította õket, amelyek nélkül nem voltak képesek áttörni Konstantinápoly erõs falain. Theodosius beismerte a vereségét és átküldte az udvari küldöncét, Anatoliust, hogy kössön békét. A feltételek azonban szigorúbb voltak, mint korábban: a császár 6000 római pond (kb. 1963 kg) aranyat fizetet az elõzõ szerzõdés megsértése ért, az évi sarc megháromszorozott 2100 római pond (kb 687 kg) aranyra és a váltságdíj emelkedett 12 Solidusra.[NEWLINE][TAB]A követelésük teljesítettek és a hun királyok visszatértek birodalmukba. Valamikor a Bizánc elleni hadjárat követõ béke alatt, valószín&#x171;leg 445-ben, Bleda meghalt és egyeduralkodó lett Attila. Bár a találgatások szerint Attila ölte meg Bledát egy vadászaton, halálának körülményeit nem ismerjük biztosan. Létezik egy alternatív nézet is, mely szerint Bleda próbálta megölni Attilát, de Attila legyõzte testvérét.[NEWLINE][TAB]A középkori krónikák szerint Buda város róla kapta a nevét. Ezért Bleda király alakja a magyar irodalomban Buda néven vált ismertté.</Hungarian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_HUNS_BLEDA</Tag>
		<English>Bleda</English>
		<French>Bleda</French>
		<German>Bleda</German>
		<Italian>Bleda</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bleda</Spanish>
		<Hungarian>Bleda</Hungarian>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>

