<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Alex Mantzaris (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - New -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_EGYPT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Ptolemaic Kingdom</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Empire</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Empire</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Empire</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Empire</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_EGYPT_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Ptolemaic Kingdom</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Kingdom</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Kingdom</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Kingdom</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Kingdom</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT><TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_EGYPT_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Ptolemaic Empire</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Empire</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Empire</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Empire</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Ptolemaic Empire</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_EGYPT_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Province of Egypt</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Province of Egypt</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Province of Egypt</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Province of Egypt</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Province of Egypt</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_EGYPT_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Egypt</English>
		<French>
			<Text>v</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Egypt</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Egypt</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Egypt</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_EGYPT_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Egyptian</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Byzantin</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Byzantinisch:byzantinischen:byzantinische</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter:Neuter:Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Bizantino:Bizantina:Bizantini:Bizantine</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Bizantino:Bizantinos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_EGYPT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Ptolemaic dynasty, sometimes also known as the Lagids or Lagides, from the name of Ptolemy I's father, Lagus) was a Macedonian Greek royal family which ruled the Ptolemaic Empire in Egypt during the Hellenistic period. Their rule lasted for 275 years, from 305 BC to 30 BC. They were the 32nd and last dynasty of ancient Egypt. The Ptolemaic dynasty is sometimes called the Thirty-fourth dynasty of Egypt too. All the male rulers of the dynasty took the name Ptolemy. Ptolemaic queens, some of whom were the sisters of their husbands, were usually called Cleopatra, Arsinoe or Berenice. The most famous member of the line was the last queen, Cleopatra VII, known for her role in the Roman political battles between Julius Caesar and Pompey, and later between Octavian and Mark Antony. Her apparent suicide at the conquest by Rome marked the end of Ptolemaic rule in Egypt.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAGADHA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Magadhan Kingdom</English>
		<French>Magadhan Kingdom</French>
		<German>Magadhan Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Magadhan Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Magadhan Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAGADHA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Magadhan</English>
		<French>Magadhan</French>
		<German>Magadhan</German>
		<Italian>Magadhan</Italian>
		<Spanish>Magadhan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAGADHA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Magadha</English>
		<French>Magadha</French>
		<German>Magadha</German>
		<Italian>Magadha</Italian>
		<Spanish>Magadha</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAGADHA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Magadha</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Magadha</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Magadha</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Magadha</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Magadha</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCYTHIANS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Saka Kingdom</English>
		<French>Saka Kingdom</French>
		<German>Saka Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Saka Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Saka Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCYTHIANS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Saka</English>
		<French>Saka</French>
		<German>Saka</German>
		<Italian>Saka</Italian>
		<Spanish>Saka</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCYTHIANS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Saka Kingdom</English>
		<French>Saka Kingdom</French>
		<German>Saka Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Saka Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Saka Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCYTHIANS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Saka Kingdom</English>
		<French>Saka Kingdom</French>
		<German>Saka Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Saka Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Saka Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AVARS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Avar Qaghanate</English>
		<French>Avar Qaghanate</French>
		<German>Avar Qaghanate</German>
		<Italian>Avar Qaghanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Avar Qaghanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AVARS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Avar</English>
		<French>Avar</French>
		<German>Avar</German>
		<Italian>Avar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Avar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AVARS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Avar Qaghanate</English>
		<French>Avar Qaghanate</French>
		<German>Avar Qaghanate</German>
		<Italian>Avar Qaghanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Avar Qaghanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AVARS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Avar Qaghanate</English>
		<French>Avar Qaghanate</French>
		<German>Avar Qaghanate</German>
		<Italian>Avar Qaghanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Avar Qaghanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HEPHTHALITES_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Hephthalite Kingdom</English>
		<French>Hephthalite Kingdom</French>
		<German>Hephthalite Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Hephthalite Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hephthalite Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HEPHTHALITES_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Hephthalite</English>
		<French>Hephthalite</French>
		<German>Hephthalite</German>
		<Italian>Hephthalite</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hephthalite</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HEPHTHALITES_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Hephthalite Kingdom</English>
		<French>Hephthalite Kingdom</French>
		<German>Hephthalite Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Hephthalite Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hephthalite Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HEPHTHALITES_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Hephthalites</English>
		<French>Hephthalites</French>
		<German>Hephthalites</German>
		<Italian>Hephthalites</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hephthalites</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NANYUE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Nan Yue</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Nan Yue</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Nan Yue</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Nan Yue</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Nan Yue</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NANYUE_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Nan Yue</English>
		<French>Nan Yue</French>
		<German>Nan Yue</German>
		<Italian>Nan Yue</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nan Yue</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NANYUE_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Nan Yue</English>
		<French>Nan Yue</French>
		<German>Nan Yue</German>
		<Italian>Nan Yue</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nan Yue</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NANYUE_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Nan Yue</English>
		<French>Nan Yue</French>
		<German>Nan Yue</German>
		<Italian>Nan Yue</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nan Yue</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NANYUE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Nanyue (Vietnamese: Nam Viet) was an ancient kingdom that consisted of parts of the modern Chinese provinces of Guangdong, Guangxi, and Yunnan and northern Vietnam. Nanyue was established in 204 BC at the final collapse of the Qin Dynasty by Zhao Tuo, who was the military commander of Nanhai Commandery at the time, and initially comprised the Nanhai, Guilin, and Xiang Commanderies. In 196 BC, Zhao Tuo made tributary obeisance to the Emperor Gaozu of Han and Nanyue was referred to by Han leaders as a "foreign servant", synecdoche for a vassal state. Around 183 BC, relations between the Nanyue and the Han Dynasty soured, and Zhao Tuo began to refer to himself as an emperor (suggesting Nanyue's sovereignty). The kingdoms of Minyue, Yelang, Ouluo and Tongshi declared their allegiance to Nanyue rule, greatly expanding Nanyue's territory and control. In 179 BC, relations between the Han and Nanyue improved, and Zhao Tuo once again made submission, this time to Emperor Wen of Han as an subject state. The submission was somewhat superficial, as Nanyue seems to have retained autonomy from the Han, and Zhao Tuo was referred as "Emperor" throughout Nanyue until his death. In 113 BC, fourth-generation leader Zhao Xing sought to have Nanyue formally included as part of the Han Empire. His prime minister Lü Jia objected vehemently and subsequently killed Zhao Xing, installing his elder brother Zhao Jiande on the throne and forcing a confrontation with the Han Dynasty. The next year, Emperor Wu of Han sent 100,000 troops to war against Nanyue. By the end of the year and the beginning of 111 BC, the army had destroyed Nanyue. The kingdom lasted 93 years in total and had five generations of kings.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Kingdom of Nanyue's founding preserved the Lingnan region's societal order and stability during the chaos surrounding the collapse of the Qin Dynasty, and allowed the southern region to avoid much of the hardship experienced by the northern, predominantly Han Chinese regions. The kingdom was founded by leaders originally from the Chinese heartland, and was responsible for bringing Chinese bureaucracy and more advanced agriculture and handicraft techniques to the inhabitants of the southern regions, as well as knowledge of the Chinese language and writing system. Nanyue leaders promoted a policy of "Harmonizing and Gathering the Hundred Yue Tribes", and encouraged fellow Han Chinese to immigrate from their Yellow River homeland to the south. They supported mutual assimilation of the two cultures and peoples, and promulgated Han culture and the Chinese language throughout the region, though many elements of original Yue culture were preserved.[PARAGRAPH:1]In Vietnam, the rulers of Nanyue are referred to as the Trieu Dynasty. The name "Vietnam" is derived from Nam Viet, the Vietnamese pronunciation of Nanyue.</English>
		<French>in French</French>
		<German>in German</German>
		<Italian>in Italian</Italian>
		<Spanish>in Spanish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WEI_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Wei</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Wei</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Wei</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Wei</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Wei</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHENLA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Chenla</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Chenla</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Chenla</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Chenla</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Chenla</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHENLA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Chenla</English>
		<French>Chenla</French>
		<German>Chenla</German>
		<Italian>Chenla</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chenla</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHENLA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Chenla:Chenla</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Chenla:Chenla</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Chenla:Chenla</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Chenla:Chenla</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Chenla:Chenla</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHENLA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Chenla is the Chinese designation for Cambodia after the fall of Funan. That name was still used in the 13th century by the Chinese envoy Zhou Daguan, author of The Manners and Customs of Cambodia . Some modern scholars used the name exclusively for Khmer states of the period from the late 6th to the early 9th centuries.[PARAGRAPH:2]The beginnings of the so-called "Dangrek Chieftains" small chiefdoms north and south of the Dangrek Mountains are obscure. The first known princes are mentioned in some early inscriptions. The Sanskrit inscription of Val Kantel, Stung Treng province names a king Viravarman as father of a princess whose name was not mentioned, married to a Brahmin called Somasarman and sister of a certain Bhavavarman. According to the inscription from Can Nak'on in Basak/Laos Viravarman was also father of prince Citrasena who was the younger brother of Bhavavarman. Obviously both princes had the same mother, but different fathers, which was corroborated by the Si T'ep inscription giving the information that Bhavavarman was the son of a Prathivindravarman and grandson of a Cakravartin whereas the inscription from Pak Mun in Ubon/Thailand informs us that the name of the father of Viravarman was called Sarvabhauma. All these inscriptions refer to a large territory ruled by these kings. It is recorded in the inscription from Roban Romas at Isanapura (the archaeological site of Sambor Prei Kuk) that a certain Narasimhagupta, who was vassal (sam­an­tanrpa) of the successive kings Bhavavarman, Mahendravarman (the ruling name of Citrasena) and Isanavarman erected on the 13th April 598 during the reign of Bhavavarman a figure of Kalpavasudeva. This coincides with the oldest Chinese text that mentions Zhenla, the Sui shu (Annals of the Sui Dynasty), compiled by Wei Zheng (580-643) in AD 636, which gives the information that at the beginning of the 7th century Zhenla was ruled by Zhiduosina (Citrasena) and Yishenaxiandai (Isanavarman). The capital of the latter was Isanapura, while his predecessor Bhavavarman I still resided at Bhavapura, a place which probably is located in the vicinity of the modern town of Thala Borivat.</English>
		<French>in French</French>
		<German>in German</German>
		<Italian>in Italian</Italian>
		<Spanish>in Spanish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VANDALS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Vandal Kingdom</English>
		<French>Vandal Kingdom</French>
		<German>Vandal Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Vandal Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vandal Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VANDALS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Vandal Kingdom</English>
		<French>Vandal Kingdom</French>
		<German>Vandal Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Vandal Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vandal Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VANDALS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Vandal:Vandal</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Vandal:Vandals</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Vandal:Vandals</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Vandal:Vandals</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Vandal:Vandals</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VANDALS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Vandal Kingdom</English>
		<French>Vandal Kingdom</French>
		<German>Vandal Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Vandal Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vandal Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VANDALS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Vandals were a Germanic people who came into contact with the Roman empire during Emperor Marcus Aurelius' Marcomannic wars (166-80). By the 3rd century, in common with many German tribes, they had adopted the military instrument of the western steppe peoples, lance-armed cavalry. Divided into two groups, the Asdings and Silings, they were usually mentioned together with the Alans. In the 290s, they were living on the Hungarian Plain and in alliance with the Gepids against the Gothic Tervingi. Like the Goths, whom they seem to have resembled, they were driven westward by the Hunnic attacks of the 370s, and played a role both as enemies and soldiers of the empire. Stilicho, the Roman magister militum (C-in-C) in the 390s, was half-Vandal. He was the most successful opponent of the Gothic attacks on Italy, neutralizing Alaric and defeating and killing Radagaisus (406). The western Emperor Honorius feared his ambition and had him captured and executed (408).[PARAGRAPH:2]At the end of 406, the Vandals and Alans, in conjunction with the confederated Suevi, crossed the river Rhine at Mainz, and swarmed into a Gaul largely abandoned by the imperial government. They devastated the country for three years before crossing into Spain. Here they settled, mostly in the south and west, for a generation. The Siling group was dispersed by Visigoths in alliance with the Romans c.416-18, and this may have persuaded the Asdings to transfer to Africa in 429. Their king, Gaiseric, proved himself an able conqueror and great strategist. He soon seized Mauretania and Numidia (by 435), capturing Carthage in 439. He took full advantage of the city's position and resources. First, he put pressure on the Roman government to recognize his title in return for assuring the North African grain supply upon which the Italian cities depended. Secondly, he constructed fleets which enabled him to carve out a sphere of influence in the western Mediterranean. The Balearic Islands, Sicily, Corsica, and Sardinia fell under Vandal control. Extensive naval raiding against imperial territories included a sack of Rome (455). Byzantine attempts to reconquer Africa in the 460s were beaten off, and in 474, a treaty with the eastern Emperor Zeno reaffirmed Vandal legitimacy. Gaiseric established a dynasty which lasted as long as their rule in Africa.[PARAGRAPH:2]Although a very mixed group ethnically, being composed of the Asdings and remaining Silings, Alans, Goths, Suevi, and some Hispano-Romans, the Vandals formed a narrow social elite. They were divided from the local population by their adherence to the Arian form of Christianity, and by their military status. Gaiseric provided public lands, known as the sortes Vandalorum to support the warrior caste. They could fight in alliance with the local Mauri tribes, who provided light cavalry and infantry, but these had drifted out of allegiance by the early 5th century because of Vandal military decline. Reliance upon a small group of lance-armed cavalry, however socially elite and well equipped, was to prove inadequate in the face of more flexible forces. In 533, as the first stage of Justinian's plan to reconquer the western empire, the Byzantine general Belisarius invaded Africa with an expeditionary force. A fleet of 92 swift two-decker craft kept the Vandal fleet at bay. He had just 10, 000 infantry and 5, 000 cavalry (although these included his 1, 000-strong bodyguard troops and Hunnic mounted archers). Against them the Vandal King Gelimer could probably only muster comparable numbers, all cavalry. Belisarius landed five days' ride from Carthage and advanced upon the city. He did not expect Gelimer's rapid response and was surprised in line of march at Ad Decimum (the tenth milestone from Carthage). Initial Vandal success was halted by the death of the king's brother Ammatas, and resulted in them being driven off. Gelimer then withdrew, allowing the Romans to occupy Carthage, which he blockaded. The decisive encounter took place when Belisarius emerged from the city, leading only his cavalry to attack the Vandal camp at Tricamerum, 18 miles (29 km) away. Gelimer instructed his men to charge, sword in hand for close combat, but their attack was impeded by a stream. The trained Byzantine troops responded better to the situation, fought back skilfully, and once again killed the Vandal general, Tzanon. Procopius, the Byzantine historian, records the losses as 50 for his own side and 800 of the enemy. This was the end for the Vandal army in Africa. They were organized into five regiments, the Vandali Justiniani, each 400 strong, and shipped off to fight on the Persian frontier.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAKURIA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Makuria</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Makuria</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Makuria</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Makuria</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Makuria</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAKURIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Makuria</English>
		<French>Makuria</French>
		<German>Makuria</German>
		<Italian>Makuria</Italian>
		<Spanish>Makuria</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAKURIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Makurian:Makurians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>MAKURIAn:MAKURIAns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>MAKURIAn:MAKURIAns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>MAKURIAn:MAKURIAns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>MAKURIAn:MAKURIAns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAKURIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Kingdom of Makuria was a kingdom located in what is today Northern Sudan and Southern Egypt. It was one of a group of Nubian kingdoms that emerged during the decline of the Aksumite Empire, which it had been part of from approximately 4BC to AD 950. Makuria originally covered the area along the Nile River from the Third Cataract to somewhere between the Fifth and Sixth Cataracts. It also had control over the trade routes, mines, and oases to the east and west. Its capital was Dongola (Old Nubian: Tungul), and the kingdom is sometimes known by the name of its capital.[PARAGRAPH:1]By the end of the 6th century it had converted to Christianity, but in the 7th century Egypt was conquered by the Islamic armies, and Nubia was cut off from the rest of Christendom. In 651 an Arab army invaded, but it was repulsed and a treaty known as the baqt was signed creating a relative peace between the two sides that lasted until the 13th century. Makuria expanded, annexing its northern neighbour Nobatia either at the time of the Arab invasion or during the reign of King Merkurios. The period from roughly 750 to 1150 saw the kingdom stable and prosperous, in what has been called the "Golden Age". Increased aggression from Egypt, and internal discord led to the state's collapse in the 14th century.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIMYARITES_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Himyarite:Himyarites</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>HIMYARITESn:HIMYARITESns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>HIMYARITESn:HIMYARITESns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>HIMYARITESn:HIMYARITESns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>HIMYARITESn:HIMYARITESns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIMYARITES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Himyarite Kingdom or Himyar (Flourished 110 BC-520s), historically referred to as the Homerite Kingdom by the Greeks and the Romans, was a kingdom in ancient Yemen. Established in 110 BC, it took as its capital the modern day city of Sana'a after the ancient city of Zafar. The Kingdom conquered neighbouring Saba' (Sheba) in c.25 BC, Qataban in c.200 CE, and Hadramaut c.300 CE. Its political fortunes relative to Saba' changed frequently until it finally conquered the Sabaean Kingdom around 280 CE.</English>
		<French>in French</French>
		<German>in German</German>
		<Italian>in Italian</Italian>
		<Spanish>in Spanish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PALLAVAS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Pallava</English>
		<French>Pallava</French>
		<German>Pallava</German>
		<Italian>Pallava</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pallava</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PALLAVAS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Pallava:Pallavas</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>CHOLASn:CHOLASns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>CHOLASn:CHOLASns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>CHOLASn:CHOLASns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>CHOLASn:CHOLASns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OSTROGOTHS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Ostrogothic Kingdom</English>
		<French>Ostrogothic Kingdom</French>
		<German>Ostrogothic Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Ostrogothic Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ostrogothic Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OSTROGOTHS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Ostrogothic Kingdom</English>
		<French>Ostrogothic Kingdom</French>
		<German>Ostrogothic Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Ostrogothic Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ostrogothic Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OSTROGOTHS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Ostrogothic Kingdom</English>
		<French>Ostrogothic Kingdom</French>
		<German>Ostrogothic Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Ostrogothic Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ostrogothic Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OSTROGOTHS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Ostrogoth:Ostrogoths</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>OSTROGOTHSn:OSTROGOTHSns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>OSTROGOTHSn:OSTROGOTHSns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>OSTROGOTHSn:OSTROGOTHSns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>OSTROGOTHSn:OSTROGOTHSns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OSTROGOTHS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Ostrogoths (Latin: Ostrogothi or Austrogothi) were a branch of the later Goths (the other major branch being the Visigoths). The Ostrogoths, under Theodoric the Great, established a kingdom in Italy in the late 5th and 6th centuries. The Ostrogoths traced their origins to the Greutungi and a semi-legendary kingdom north of the Black Sea in the 3rd and 4th centuries.[PARAGRAPH:2]Invading southward from the Baltic Sea, the Ostrogoths, at the time known as the Greuthungi, built up a huge empire stretching from the Dniester to the Volga river and from the Black Sea to the Baltic shores. The Ostrogoths were probably literate in the 3rd century, and their trade with the Romans was highly developed. Their Danubian kingdom reached its zenith under King Ermanaric, who is said to have committed suicide at an old age when the Huns attacked his people and subjugated them about 370.[PARAGRAPH:2]After their subjugation by the Huns, little is heard of the Ostrogoths for about 80 years, after which they reappear in Pannonia on the middle Danube River as federates of the Romans. However, a pocket remained behind in the Crimea when the bulk of them moved to central Europe, and these Crimean Ostrogoths existed until at least the 16th century. After the collapse of the Hun empire after the Battle of Nedao (453), the Ostrogoths under Theodoric the Great first moved to Moesia (c. 475-488) and later conquered the Italian Kingdom of the German warrior Odoacer. Theodoric became king of the Ostrogothic Kingdom in 493 and died in 526. A period of instability then ensued, tempting the Eastern Roman Emperor Justinian to declare war on the Ostrogoths in 535 in an effort to restore the former western provinces of the Roman Empire. Initially, the Byzantines were successful, but under the leadership of Totila, the Goths reconquered most of the lost territory until Totila's death at the Battle of Taginae. The war lasted for almost 20 years and caused enormous damage and depopulation of Italy. The remaining Ostrogoths were absorbed into the Lombards who established a kingdom in Italy in 567 AD.</English>
		<French>Ostrogoths</French>
		<German>Ostrogoths</German>
		<Italian>Ostrogoths</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ostrogoths</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VISIGOTHS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Visigothic Kingdom</English>
		<French>Visigothic Kingdom</French>
		<German>Visigothic Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Visigothic Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Visigothic Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VISIGOTHS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Visigothic Kingdom</English>
		<French>Visigothic Kingdom</French>
		<German>Visigothic Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Visigothic Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Visigothic Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VISIGOTHS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Visigothic Kingdom</English>
		<French>Visigothic Kingdom</French>
		<German>Visigothic Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Visigothic Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Visigothic Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VISIGOTHS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Visigoth:Visigoths</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>VISIGOTHSn:VISIGOTHSns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>VISIGOTHSn:VISIGOTHSns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>VISIGOTHSn:VISIGOTHSns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>VISIGOTHSn:VISIGOTHSns</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VISIGOTHS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Visigoths (Latin: Visigothi, Wisigothi, Vesi, Visi, Wesi, or Wisi) and Ostrogoths were branches of the nomadic tribes of Germanic peoples referred to collectively as the Goths. These tribes flourished and spread during the late Roman Empire in Late Antiquity, or the Migration Period. The Visigoths emerged from earlier Gothic groups who had invaded the Roman Empire beginning in 376 and had defeated the Romans at the Battle of Adrianople in 378. The Visigoths invaded Italy under Alaric I and sacked Rome in 410. Their long history of migration led the Visigoths to compare themselves to the Biblical Hebrew people who purportedly wandered for forty years in the Sinai Desert. After the Visigoths sacked Rome, they began settling down, first in southern Gaul and eventually in Spain and Portugal, where they founded the Kingdom of the Visigoths.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Visigoths first settled in southern Gaul as foederati of the Romans-a relationship established in 418. However, they soon fell out with their Roman hosts (for reasons that are now obscure) and established their own kingdom with its capital at Toulouse. They next extended their authority into Hispania at the expense of the Suevi and Vandals. In 507, however, their rule in Gaul was ended by the Franks under Clovis I, who defeated them in the Battle of Vouillé. After that, the Visigoth kingdom was limited to Hispania, and they never again held territory north of the Pyrenees other than Septimania. A small, elite group of Visigoths came to dominate the governance of that region at the expense of those who had previously ruled there, particularly in the Byzantine province of Spania and the Suebic Kingdom of Galicia.[PARAGRAPH:2]In or around 589, the Visigoths under Reccared I converted from Arianism to the Nicene faith, gradually adopting the culture of their Hispano-Roman subjects. Their legal code, the Liber iudiciorum (completed in 654) abolished the longstanding practice of applying different laws for Romans and Visigoths. Once legal distinctions were no longer being made between Romani and Gothi, they became known collectively as Hispani. In the century that followed, the region was dominated by the Councils of Toledo and the episcopacy. (Little else is known about the Visigoths' history during the 7th century, since records are relatively sparse.) In 711 or 712, a force of invading Arabs and Berbers defeated the Visigoths in the Battle of Guadalete. Their king and many members of their governing elite were killed, and their kingdom rapidly collapsed. Gothic identity survived, however, especially in Marca Hispanica and the Kingdom of Asturias, which had been founded by the Visigothic nobleman Pelagius after his victory over the Moors at the Battle of Covadonga.[PARAGRAPH:2]During their governance of the Kingdom of Hispania, the Visigoths built several churches. They also left many artifacts, which have been discovered in increasing numbers by archaeologists in recent times. They founded the only new cities in western Europe from the fall of the Roman Empire until the rise of the Carolingians. Many Visigothic names and surnames are still in use in modern Spanish and Portuguese. Their most notable legacy, however, was the Visigothic code of law, the Liber iudiciorum, which served, among other things, as the basis for court procedure in most of Christian Iberia until the Late Middle Ages, centuries after the demise of the kingdom.</English>
		<French>Visigoths</French>
		<German>Visigoths</German>
		<Italian>Visigoths</Italian>
		<Spanish>Visigoths</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NUBIA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Meroe</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Meroe</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Meroe</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Meroe</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Meroe</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NUBIA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Meroe</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Meroe</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Meroe</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Meroe</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Meroe</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NUBIA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Province of Meroe</English>
		<French>Province of Meroe</French>
		<German>Province of Meroe</German>
		<Italian>Province of Meroe</Italian>
		<Spanish>Province of Meroe</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NUBIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Nubia</English>
		<French>Nubia</French>
		<German>Nubia</German>
		<Italian>Nubia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nubia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NUBIA_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Nubian Empire</English>
		<French>Nubian Empire</French>
		<German>Nubian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Nubian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nubian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NUBIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Nubian:Nubians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Nubian:Nubians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Nubian:Nubians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Nubian:Nubians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Nubian:Nubians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NUBIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Kingdom of Nubia was a kingdom located in what is today Northern Sudan and Southern Egypt. It was one of a group of Nubian kingdoms that emerged during the decline of the Aksumite Empire, which it had been part of from approximately 4BC to AD 950. Nubia originally covered the area along the Nile River from the Third Cataract to somewhere between the Fifth and Sixth Cataracts. It also had control over the trade routes, mines, and oases to the east and west. Its capital was Dongola (Old Nubian: Tungul), and the kingdom is sometimes known by the name of its capital.[PARAGRAPH:1]By the end of the 6th century it had converted to Christianity, but in the 7th century Egypt was conquered by the Islamic armies, and Nubia was cut off from the rest of Christendom. In 651 an Arab army invaded, but it was repulsed and a treaty known as the baqt was signed creating a relative peace between the two sides that lasted until the 13th century. Nubia expanded, annexing its northern neighbour Nobatia either at the time of the Arab invasion or during the reign of King Merkurios. The period from roughly 750 to 1150 saw the kingdom stable and prosperous, in what has been called the "Golden Age". Increased aggression from Egypt, and internal discord led to the state's collapse in the 14th century.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CARTHAGE_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Carthaginian Empire</English>
		<French>Carthaginian Empire</French>
		<German>Carthaginian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Carthaginian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Carthaginian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CARTHAGE_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Carthaginian Empire</English>
		<French>Carthaginian Empire</French>
		<German>Carthaginian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Carthaginian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Carthaginian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CARTHAGE_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Carthaginian Cities</English>
		<French>Carthaginian Empire</French>
		<German>Carthaginian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Carthaginian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Carthaginian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CARTHAGE_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Carthage</English>
		<French>Carthage</French>
		<German>Carthage</German>
		<Italian>Carthage</Italian>
		<Spanish>Carthage</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CARTHAGE__ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Carthaginian</English>
		<French>Carthaginian</French>
		<German>Carthaginian</German>
		<Italian>Carthaginian</Italian>
		<Spanish>Carthaginian</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FUNAN_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Kambuja</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Kambuja</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Kambuja</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Kambuja</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Kambuja</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FUNAN_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Kambuja</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Kambuja</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Kambuja</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Kambuja</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Kambuja</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FUNAN_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Province of Kambuja</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Kambuja</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Kambuja</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Kambuja</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Kambuja</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FUNAN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kambuja</English>
		<French>Kambuja</French>
		<German>Kambuja</German>
		<Italian>Kambuja</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kambuja</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FUNAN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Kambujan:Kambujans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Kambujan:Kambujans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Kambujan:Kambujans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Kambujan:Kambujans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Kambujan:Kambujans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FUNAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Kingdom of Kambuja was the Sanskrit name of an ancient kingdom located around the Mekong Delta of southern Vietnam and in southern Indochina. This name is the ancestor of the modern "Kampuchea" and "Cambodia". The kingdom was known to the Chinese as "Funan". The most extensive descriptions of this area come from the report of two Chinese diplomats representing the Wu Kingdom of Nanking who sojourned in Funan in the mid-3rd century A.D.; however, the name "Funan" is not found in any texts of local origin, and it is not known what name the people of Funan gave to their country.[PARAGRAPH:2]Some scholars have advanced speculative proposals regarding the origin and meaning of the word "Funan." It is often said that the name "Funan" represents a transcription from some local language into Chinese. For example, French scholar George Coedès advanced the theory that in using the word "Funan" ancient Chinese scholars were transcribing a word related to the Khmer word bnam or vnam (modern: phnom, meaning "mountain"). However, a Chinese character is frequently used in geographical terms to mean "South;" Chinese scholars used it in this sense in naming other locations or regions of Southeast Asia, such as "Annam." Thus, "Funan" may be an originally Chinese word meaning something like "Pacified South," and may not be a transcription at all.[PARAGRAPH:2]Like the very name of the country, the ethno-linguistic nature of the people is the subject of much discussion among specialists. The leading hypotheses are that the Funanese were mostly Mon-Khmer, or that they were mostly Austronesian, or that they constituted a multi-ethnic society. The available evidence is inconclusive on this issue.[PARAGRAPH:2]Based on the testimony of the Chinese historians, the polity Funan is believed to have been established in the 1st century C.E. in the Mekong delta, but archeological research has shown that extensive human settlement in the region may have gone back as far as the 4th century B.C.E. Though regarded by Chinese authors as a single unified polity, some modern scholars suspect that Funan may have been a collection of city-states that sometimes warred with one another and at other times constituted a political unity. From archeological evidence, which includes Roman, Chinese, and Indian goods excavated at the ancient mercantile center of Oc Eo (meaning "glass canal") in southern Vietnam, we know that Funan must have been a powerful trading state. Excavations at Angkor Borei in southern Cambodia have likewise delivered evidence of an important settlement. Since Oc Eo was linked to a port on the coast and to Angkor Borei by a system of canals, it is possible that all of these locations together constituted the heartland of Funan.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>

	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_YAMATO_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Yamato</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Yamato</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Yamato</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Yamato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Yamato</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_YAMATO_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Yamato</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Yamato</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Yamato</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Yamato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Yamato</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_YAMATO_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Yamato</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Yamato</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Yamato</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Yamato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Yamato</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_YAMATO_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Yamato</English>
		<French>Yamato</French>
		<German>Yamato</German>
		<Italian>Yamato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Yamato</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SABA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Saba</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Saba</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Saba</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Saba</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Saba</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SABA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Saba</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Saba</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Saba</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Saba</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Saba</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SABA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Region of Saba</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Saba</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Saba</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Saba</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Saba</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SABA_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Sabean Empire</English>
		<French>Sabean Empire</French>
		<German>Sabean Empire</German>
		<Italian>Sabean Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sabean Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SABA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Saba</English>
		<French>Saba</French>
		<German>Saba</German>
		<Italian>Saba</Italian>
		<Spanish>Saba</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SABA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Sabean:Sabeans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Sabean:Sabeans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Sabean:Sabeans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Sabean:Sabeans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Sabean:Sabeans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SABA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Sabaeans or Sabeans were an ancient people speaking an Old South Arabian language who lived in what is today Yemen, in the south west of the Arabian Peninsula.[PARAGRAPH:2]Some scholars suggest a link between the Sabaeans and the Biblical land of Sheba, and would dismiss any link or confusion with the Sabians.[PARAGRAPH:2]The ancient Sabaean Kingdom established power in the early 1st millennium BC. In the 1st century BC it was conquered by the Himyarites, but after the disintegration of the first Himyarite empire of the Kings of Saba' and Dhu-Raydan, the Middle Sabaean Kingdom reappeared in the early 2nd century. It was finally conquered by the Himyarites in the late 3rd century. Its capital was Ma'rib. The kingdom was located along the strip of desert called Sayhad by medieval Arab geographers, which is now named Ramlat al-Sab'atayn.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Sabaean people were South Arabian people. Each of these had regional kingdoms in ancient Yemen, with the Minaeans in the north along the Red sea, the Sabeans on the south western tip, stretching from the highlands to the sea, the Qatabanians to the east of them and the Hadramites east of them.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Sabaeans, like the other Yemenite kingdoms of the same period, were involved in the extremely lucrative spice trade, especially frankincense and myrrh.[PARAGRAPH:2]They left behind many inscriptions in the monumental Musnad (Old South Arabian) alphabet, as well as numerous documents in the cursive Zabur script.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Arabian Empire</English>
		<French>Arabian Empire</French>
		<German>Arabian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Arabian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Arabian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Arabian Empire</English>
		<French>Arabian Empire</French>
		<German>Arabian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Arabian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Arabian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Arabian Provinces</English>
		<French>Arab Empire</French>
		<German>Arab Empire</German>
		<Italian>Arab Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Arab Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Arabian Empire</English>
		<French>Arabian Empire</French>
		<German>Arabian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Arabian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Arabian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAURYANS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Mauryan Empire</English>
		<French>Mauryan Empire</French>
		<German>Mauryan Empire</German>
		<Italian>Mauryan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mauryan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAURYANS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Mauryan Empire</English>
		<French>Mauryan Empire</French>
		<German>Mauryan Empire</German>
		<Italian>Mauryan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mauryan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAURYANS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Mauryan Empire</English>
		<French>Mauryan Empire</French>
		<German>Mauryan Empire</German>
		<Italian>Mauryan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mauryan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAURYANS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Magadhan Kingdom</English>
		<French>Mauryan Kingdom</French>
		<German>Mauryan Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Mauryan Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mauryan Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAURYANS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Mauryan Empire</English>
		<French>Mauryan Empire</French>
		<German>Mauryan Empire</German>
		<Italian>Mauryan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mauryan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAURYANS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Mauryan:Mauryans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Mauryan:Mauryans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Mauryan:Mauryans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Mauryan:Mauryans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Mauryan:Mauryans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAURYANS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Maurya Empire was a geographically extensive Iron Age historical power in ancient India, ruled by the Mauryan dynasty from 321 to 185 BC. Originating from the kingdom of Magadha in the Indo-Gangetic plains (modern Bihar, eastern Uttar Pradesh and Bengal) in the eastern side of the Indian subcontinent, the empire had its capital city at Pataliputra (modern Patna). The Empire was founded in 322 BC by Chandragupta Maurya, who had overthrown the Nanda Dynasty and rapidly expanded his power westwards across central and western India taking advantage of the disruptions of local powers in the wake of the withdrawal westward by Alexander the Great 's Greek and Persian armies. By 320 BC the empire had fully occupied Northwestern India, defeating and conquering the satraps left by Alexander.[NEWLINE][TAB]With an area of 5,000,000 sq km, it was one of the world's largest empires in its time, and the largest ever in the Indian subcontinent. At its greatest extent, the empire stretched to the north along the natural boundaries of the Himalayas, and to the east stretching into what is now Assam. To the west, it conquered beyond modern Pakistan, annexing Balochistan, south eastern parts of Iran and much of what is now Afghanistan, including the modern Herat and Kandahar provinces. The Empire was expanded into India's central and southern regions by the emperors Chandragupta and Bindusara, but it excluded a small portion of unexplored tribal and forested regions near Kalinka (modern Orissa), till it was conquered by Ashoka. Its decline began 60 years after Ashoka's rule ended, and it dissolved in 185 BC with the foundation of the Sunga Dynasty in Magadha.[NEWLINE][TAB]Under Chandragupta, the Mauryan Empire conquered the trans-Indus region, which was under Macedonian rule. Chandragupta then defeated the invasion led by Seleucus I, a Greek general from Alexander's army. Under Chandragupta and his successors, internal and external trade, agriculture and economic activities, all thrived and expanded across India thanks to the creation of a single and efficient system of finance, administration, and security.[NEWLINE][TAB]After the Kalinka War, the Empire experienced half a century of peace and security under Ashoka. Mauryan India also enjoyed an era of social harmony, religious transformation, and expansion of the sciences and of knowledge. Chandragupta Maurya's embrace of Jainism increased social and religious renewal and reform across his society, while Ashoka's embrace of Buddhism has been said to have been the foundation of the reign of social and political peace and non-violence across all of India. Ashoka sponsored the spreading of Buddhist ideals into Sri Lanka, Southeast Asia, West Asia and Mediterranean Europe.[NEWLINE][TAB]The population of the empire has been estimated to be about 50-60 million making the Mauryan Empire one of the most populous empires of the time.[NEWLINE][TAB]Archaeologically, the period of Mauryan rule in South Asia falls into the era of Northern Black Polished Ware (NBPW). The Arthashastra and the Edicts of Ashoka are the primary sources of written records of Mauryan times. The Lion Capital of Asoka at Sarnath, has been made the national emblem of India.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WESTERN_ROME</Tag>
		<English>Western Roman Empire</English>
		<French>Western Roman Empire</French>
		<German>Western Roman Empire</German>
		<Italian>Western Roman Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Western Roman Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_EASTERN_ROME</Tag>
		<English>Eastern Roman Empire</English>
		<French>Eastern Roman Empire</French>
		<German>Eastern Roman Empire</German>
		<Italian>Eastern Roman Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Eastern Roman Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	
	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SUNGA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Sunga Kingdom</English>
		<French>Sunga Kingdom</French>
		<German>Sunga Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Sunga Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sunga Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SUNGAS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Sunga Kingdom</English>
		<French>Sunga Kingdom</French>
		<German>Sunga Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Sunga Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sunga Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SUNGA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Sunga Kingdom</English>
		<French>Sunga Kingdom</French>
		<German>Sunga Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Sunga Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sunga Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SUNGA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Sunga Kingdom</English>
		<French>Sunga Kingdom</French>
		<German>Sunga Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Sunga Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sunga Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SUNGA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Sunga Empire</English>
		<French>Sunga Empire</French>
		<German>Sunga Empire</German>
		<Italian>Sunga Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sunga Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SUNGA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Sunga Kingdom</English>
		<French>Sunga Kingdom</French>
		<German>Sunga Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Sunga Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sunga Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SUNGAS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Sunga Empire</English>
		<French>Sunga Empire</French>
		<German>Sunga Empire</German>
		<Italian>Sunga Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sunga Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SUNGA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Sungan</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Sungan</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Sungan</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Sungan</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Sungan</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SUNGA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Sungas were a Magadhan dynasty who rebelled against the Mauryans and took control of their empire around 185BC.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PARTHIA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Parthian Empire</English>
		<French>Parthian Empire</French>
		<German>Parthian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Parthian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Parthian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PARTHIA_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Parthian Empire</English>
		<French>Parthian Empire</French>
		<German>Parthian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Parthian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Parthian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PARTHIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Parthia</English>
		<French>Parthian</French>
		<German>Parthian</German>
		<Italian>Parthian</Italian>
		<Spanish>Parthian</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PARTHIA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Parthian Empire</English>
		<French>Parthian Empire</French>
		<German>Parthian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Parthian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Parthian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PARTHIA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Parthian Satrapy</English>
		<French>Parthian Satrapy</French>
		<German>Parthian Satrapy</German>
		<Italian>Parthian Satrapy</Italian>
		<Spanish>Parthian Satrapy</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PARTHIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Parthian:Parthians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Parthian:Parthians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Parthian:Parthians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Parthian:Parthians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Parthian:Parthians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PARTHIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Parthian Empire, also known as the Arsacid Empire, was a major Iranian political and cultural power in ancient Persia. Its latter name comes from Arsaces I of Parthia who, as leader of the Parni tribe, founded it in the mid-3rd century BC when he conquered the Parthia region in Iran's northeast, then a satrapy (province) in rebellion against the Seleucid Empire. Mithridates I of Parthia greatly expanded the empire by seizing Media and Mesopotamia from the Seleucids. At its height, the Parthian Empire stretched from the northern reaches of the Euphrates, in what is now south-eastern Turkey, to eastern Iran. The empire, located on the Silk Road trade route between the Roman Empire in the Mediterranean Basin and Han Empire of China, became a center of trade and commerce.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Parthians largely adopted the art, architecture, religious beliefs, and royal insignia of their culturally heterogeneous empire, which encompassed Persian, Hellenistic, and regional cultures. For about the first half of its existence, the Arsacid court adopted elements of Greek culture, though it eventually saw a gradual revival of Iranian traditions. The Arsacid rulers were titled the "King of Kings", as a claim to be the heirs to the Achaemenid Empire; indeed, they accepted many local kings as vassals where the Achaemenids would have had centrally appointed, albeit largely autonomous, satraps. The court did appoint a small number of satraps, largely outside Iran, but these satrapies were smaller and less powerful than the Achaemenid potentates. With the expansion of Arsacid power, the seat of central government shifted from Nisa, Turkmenistan to Ctesiphon along the Tigris (south of modern Baghdad, Iraq), although several other sites also served as capitals.[PARAGRAPH:1]The earliest enemies of the Parthians were the Seleucids in the west and the Scythians in the east. However, as Parthia expanded westward, they came into conflict with the Kingdom of Armenia, and eventually the late Roman Republic. Rome and Parthia competed with each other to establish the kings of Armenia as their subordinate clients. The Parthians soundly defeated Marcus Licinius Crassus at the Battle of Carrhae in 53 BC, and in 40-39 BC, Parthian forces captured the whole of the Levant, excepting Tyre, from the Romans. However, Mark Antony led a counterattack against Parthia and several Roman emperors invaded Mesopotamia during the Roman-Parthian Wars. The Romans captured the cities of Seleucia and Ctesiphon on multiple occasions during these conflicts, but were never able to hold onto them. Frequent civil war between Parthian contenders to the throne proved more dangerous than foreign invasion, and Parthian power evaporated when Ardashir I, ruler of Estakhr in Fars, revolted against the Arsacids and killed their last ruler, Artabanus IV, in 224 AD. Ardashir established the Sassanid Empire, which ruled Iran and much of the Near East until the Muslim conquests of the 7th century AD, although the Arsacid dynasty lived on through the Arsacid Dynasty of Armenia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Native Parthian sources, written in Parthian, Greek and other languages, are scarce when compared to Sassanid and even earlier Achaemenid sources. Aside from scattered cuneiform tablets, fragmentary ostraca, rock inscriptions, drachma coins, and the chance survival of some parchment documents, much of Parthian history is only known through external sources. These include mainly Greek and Roman histories, but also Chinese histories prompted by the market for Chinese goods in Parthia. Parthian artwork is viewed by historians as a valid source for understanding aspects of society and culture that are otherwise absent in textual sources.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARMENIA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Armenia</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Armenia</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Armenia</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Armenia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Armenia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARMENIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Armenia</English>
		<French>Armenia</French>
		<German>Armenia</German>
		<Italian>Armenia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Armenia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARMENIA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Armenia</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Armenia</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Armenia</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Armenia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Armenia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIMYARITE_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Himyarite Kingdom</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Armenia</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Armenia</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Armenia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Armenia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARMENIA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Principality of Armenia</English>
		<French>Principality of Armenia</French>
		<German>Principality of Armenia</German>
		<Italian>Principality of Armenia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Principality of Armenia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARMENIA_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Armenian Empire</English>
		<French>Armenian Empire</French>
		<German>Armenian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Armenian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Armenian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARMENIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Armenian:Armenians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Armenian:Armenians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Armenian:Armenians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Armenian:Armenians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Armenian:Armenians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARMENIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Armenia has been populated since prehistoric times, and has been proposed as the site of the Biblical Garden of Eden. Armenia lies in the highlands surrounding the Biblical mountains of Ararat, upon which, as tradition states, Noah's Ark came to rest after the flood.[PARAGRAPH:1]Around 600 BC, the Kingdom of Armenia was established under the Orontid Dynasty, which existed under several local dynasties till AD 428. The kingdom reached its height between 95 - 66 BC under Tigranes the Great, becoming one of the most powerful kingdoms of its time. Throughout its history, the kingdom of Armenia enjoyed periods of independence intermitted with periods of autonomy subject to contemporary empires. Armenia's strategic location between two continents has subjected it to invasions by many peoples, including the Assyrians, Greeks, Romans, Byzantines, Arabs, Mongols, Persians, Ottoman Turks and Russians.[PARAGRAPH:1]In 301, Armenia became the first country in the world to adopt Christianity as its official state religion, while a number of Christian communities have been established in Armenia since 40 AD There had been various pagan communities before Christianity, but they were converted by an influx of Christian missionaries.[PARAGRAPH:1]After the fall of the Armenian kingdom in 428, most of Armenia was incorporated as a marzpanate within the Sassanid Empire. After the marzpanate period, Armenia emerged as an autonomous principality within the Arabic Empire, reuniting Armenian lands previously taken by the Ptolemaic Egyptian Empire as well. The principality was ruled by the Prince of Armenia, recognized by the Caliph and the Ptolemaic Egyptian Emperor. The Principality of Armenia lasted till 884, when it regained its independence from the weakened Arabic Empire.[PARAGRAPH:1]The reemerged Armenian kingdom was ruled by the Bagratuni dynasty, and lasted till 1045. In time, several areas of the Bagratid Armenia separated as independent kingdoms and principalities such as the Kingdom of Vaspurakan ruled by the House of Artsruni, while still recognizing the supremacy of the Bagratid kings.[PARAGRAPH:1]In 1045, the Ptolemaic Egyptian Empire conquered Bagratid Armenia. Soon, the other Armenian states fell under Ptolemaic Egyptian control as well. The Ptolemaic Egyptian rule was short lived, as in 1071 Seljuk Turks defeated the Byzantines and conquered Armenia at the Battle of Manzikert, establishing the Seljuk Empire. To escape death or servitude at the hands of those who had assassinated his relative, Gagik II, King of Ani, an Armenian named Roupen with some of his countrymen went into the gorges of the Taurus Mountains and then into Tarsus of Cilicia. Here the Ptolemaic Egyptian governor of the place gave them shelter where the Armenian Kingdom of Cilicia was eventually established.[PARAGRAPH:1]In 1230s Mongol Ilkhanate conquered the Zakaryan Principality, as well as the rest of Armenia. The Mongolian invasions were soon followed by those of other Central Asian tribes, which continued from 1200s till 1400s. After incessant invasions, each bringing destruction to the country, Armenia in time became weakened. In 1500s, the Ottoman Empire and Safavid Persia divided Armenia among themselves.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOGURYEO_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Goguryeo</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Goguryeo</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Goguryeo</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Goguryeo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Goguryeo</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOGURYEO_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Goguryeo</English>
		<French>Goguryeo</French>
		<German>Goguryeo</German>
		<Italian>Goguryeo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Goguryeo</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOGURYEO_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Empire of Goguryeo</English>
		<French>Empire of Goguryeo</French>
		<German>Empire of Goguryeo</German>
		<Italian>Empire of Goguryeo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Empire of Goguryeo</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOGURYEO_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Province of Goguryeo</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Goguryeo</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Goguryeo</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Goguryeo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Goguryeo</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOGURYEO_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Empire of Goguryeo</English>
		<French>Empire of Goguryeo</French>
		<German>Empire of Goguryeo</German>
		<Italian>Empire of Goguryeo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Empire of Goguryeo</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOGURYEO_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Korean:Koreans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Korean:Koreans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Korean:Koreans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Korean:Koreans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Korean:Koreans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOGURYEO_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Goguryeo or Koguryo was an ancient Korean kingdom located in present day northern and central parts of the Korean Peninsula, southern Manchuria, and southern Russian Maritime province.[PARAGRAPH:2]Along with Baekje and Silla, Goguryeo was one of the Three Kingdoms of Korea. Goguryeo was an active participant in the power struggle for control of the Korean peninsula as well as associated with the foreign affairs of neighboring polities in China and Japan.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Samguk Sagi, a 12th century CE Goryeo text, indicates that Goguryeo was founded in 37 BC by Jumong, a prince from Buyeo, although there is archaeological and textual evidence that suggests Goguryeo culture was in existence since the 2nd century BCE around the fall of Gojoseon, an earlier kingdom that also occupied southern Manchuria and northern Korea.[PARAGRAPH:2]Goguryeo was a major dynasty in Northeast Asia, until it was defeated by a Silla-Tang alliance in 668 CE. After its defeat, its territory was divided among the Unified Silla, Balhae, and Tang dynasty.[PARAGRAPH:2]Goguryeo changed its name into Goryeo (Koryo) during the reign of King Jangsu, and such name was succeeded by Goryeo Dynasty (918-1392), from which the English word "Korea" stemmed.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HAN_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Han Empire</English>
		<French>Han Empire</French>
		<German>Han Empire</German>
		<Italian>Han Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Han Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HAN_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Han Empire</English>
		<French>Han Empire</French>
		<German>Han Empire</German>
		<Italian>Han Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Han Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HAN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Han</English>
		<French>Han</French>
		<German>Han</German>
		<Italian>Han</Italian>
		<Spanish>Han</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HAN_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Han Empire</English>
		<French>Han Empire</French>
		<German>Han Empire</German>
		<Italian>Han Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Han Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HAN_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Duchy of Han</English>
		<French>Duchy of Han</French>
		<German>Duchy of Han</German>
		<Italian>Duchy of Han</Italian>
		<Spanish>Duchy of Han</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HAN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Han:Han</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Han:Han</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Han:Han</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Han:Han</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Han:Han</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Han Dynasty was the second imperial dynasty of China, preceded by the Qin Dynasty (221-207 BC) and succeeded by the Three Kingdoms (220-280 AD). It was founded by the peasant rebel leader Liu Bang, known posthumously as Emperor Gaozu of Han. It was briefly interrupted by the Xin Dynasty (9-23 AD) of the former regent Wang Mang. This interregnum separates the Han into two periods: the Western Han (206 BC-9 AD) and Eastern Han (25-220 AD). Spanning over four centuries, the period of the Han Dynasty is considered a golden age in Chinese history. To this day, China's majority ethnic group refers to itself as the "Han people" and Chinese characters are referred to as "Han characters".[PARAGRAPH:2]The Han Empire was divided into areas directly controlled by the central government, known as commanderies, and a number of semi-autonomous kingdoms. These kingdoms gradually lost all vestiges of their independence, particularly following the Rebellion of the Seven States. The Xiongnu, a nomadic confederation which dominated the eastern Eurasian Steppe, defeated the Han army in battle in 200 BC. Following the defeat, a political marriage alliance was negotiated in which the Han became the de facto inferior partner. When, despite the treaty, the Xiongnu continued to raid Han borders, Emperor Wu of Han (r. 141-87 BC) launched several military campaigns against them. The ultimate Han victory in these wars eventually forced the Xiongnu to accept vassal status as Han tributaries. These campaigns expanded Han sovereignty into the Tarim Basin of Central Asia and helped establish the vast trade network known as the Silk Road, which reached as far as the Mediterranean world. Han forces managed to divide the Xiongnu into two competing nations, the Southern and Northern Xiongnu, and forced the Northern Xiongnu across the Ili River. Despite these victories, the territories north of Han's borders were quickly overrun by the nomadic Xianbei Confederation.[NEWLINE][TAB]After 92 AD, the palace eunuchs increasingly involved themselves in court politics, engaging in violent power struggles between the various consort clans of the empresses and empress dowagers, causing the Han's ultimate downfall. Imperial authority was also seriously challenged by large Daoist religious societies which instigated the Yellow Turban Rebellion and the Five Pecks of Rice Rebellion. Following the death of Emperor Ling (r. 168-189 AD), the palace eunuchs suffered wholesale massacre by military officers, allowing members of the aristocracy and military governors to become warlords and divide the empire. When Cao Pi, King of Wei, usurped the throne from Emperor Xian, the Han Dynasty ceased to exist.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Han Dynasty was an age of economic prosperity and saw a significant growth of the money economy first established during the Zhou Dynasty (c. 1050-256 BC). The coinage issued by the central government mint in 119 BC remained the standard coinage of China until the Tang Dynasty (618-907 AD). To pay for its military campaigns and the settlement of newly conquered frontier territories, the government nationalized the private salt and iron industries in 117 BC. These government monopolies were repealed during the Eastern Han period, and the lost revenue was recouped through heavily taxing private entrepreneurs. The emperor was at the pinnacle of Han society. He presided over the Han government but shared power with both the nobility and appointed ministers who came largely from the scholarly gentry class. From the reign of Emperor Wu onward, the Chinese court officially sponsored Confucianism in education and court politics, synthesized with the cosmology of later scholars such as Dong Zhongshu. This policy endured until the fall of the Qing Dynasty in 1911 AD. Science and technology during the Han period saw significant advances, including papermaking, the nautical steering rudder, the use of negative numbers in mathematics, the raised-relief map, the hydraulic -powered armillary sphere for astronomy, and a seismometer employing an inverted pendulum.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>

	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_JIN_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Jin Empire</English>
		<French>Jin Empire</French>
		<German>Jin Empire</German>
		<Italian>Jin Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Jin Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_JIN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Jin</English>
		<French>Jin</French>
		<German>Jin</German>
		<Italian>Jin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Jin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_JIN_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Jin Empire</English>
		<French>Jin Empire</French>
		<German>Jin Empire</German>
		<Italian>Jin Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Jin Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_JIN_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Duchy of Jin</English>
		<French>Duchy of Jin</French>
		<German>Duchy of Jin</German>
		<Italian>Duchy of Jin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Duchy of Jin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_JIN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Jin:Jin</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Jin:Jin</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Jin:Jin</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Jin:Jin</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Jin:Jin</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_JIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Jin Dynasty was a dynasty in Chinese history, lasting between the years 265 and 420 CE. There are two main divisions in the history of the Dynasty, the first being Western Jin (265-316) and the second Eastern Jin (317-420). Western Jin was founded by Sima Yan, with its capital at Luoyang, while Eastern Jin was begun by Sima Rui, with its capital at Jiankang. The two periods are also known as Liang Jin (lit, two Jin) and Sima Jin by scholars, to distinguish this dynasty from other dynasties that use the same Chinese character, such as the Later Jin Dynasty.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Western Jin Dynasty was founded by Emperor Wu, better known as Sima Yan. Although it provided a brief period of unity after conquering Eastern Wu in 280, the Jin suffered a devastating civil war, War of the Eight Princes, after which they could not contain the revolt of nomadic tribes known as the Wu Hu. The capital, Luoyang was captured in 311, and Emperor Huai was captured. His successor, Emperor Min was also captured in Chang'an in 316.[PARAGRAPH:2]The remnants of the Jin court fled to the east and reestablished the government at Jiankang, near modern-day Nanjing, under a member of the royal family named the Prince of Langye. The prince was proclaimed Emperor Yuan of the Eastern Jin Dynasty (317-420) when news of the fall of Chang'an reached the south. (The rival Wu Hu states in the north, which did not recognize the legitimacy of Jin, would sometimes refer to it as "Langye.")[PARAGRAPH:2]Military crises, such as the rebellions of generals Wang Dun and Su Jun, plagued the Eastern Jin throughout its 104 years of existence. Another general, Huan Wen died in 373 before he could attempt to usurp the throne. However, the Battle of Fei River turned out to be a major Jin victory, due to the short-lived cooperation of Huan Chong, brother of Huan Wen, and Prime Minister Xie An. Later, Huan Xuan, son of Huan Wen, usurped the throne and changed the dynasty's name to Chu. He, in turn, was toppled by Liu Yu, who after reinstating Emperor An, ordered him strangled and installed his brother, Emperor Gong, in 419.[PARAGRAPH:2]Emperor Gong abdicated in 420 in favor of Liu Yu, ushering in the Liu Song Dynasty the first of the Southern Dynasties. The Jin Dynasty thus came to an end.[PARAGRAPH:2]Meanwhile, North China was ruled by the Sixteen Kingdoms, many of which were founded by the Wu Hu. The last of these, Northern Liang, was conquered by the Northern Wei Dynasty in 439, ushering in the Northern Dynasties period.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_QIN_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Qin Empire</English>
		<French>Qin Empire</French>
		<German>Qin Empire</German>
		<Italian>Qin Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Qin Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_QIN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Qin</English>
		<French>Qin</French>
		<German>Qin</German>
		<Italian>Qin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Qin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_QIN_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Qin Empire</English>
		<French>Qin Empire</French>
		<German>Qin Empire</German>
		<Italian>Qin Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Qin Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_QIN_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Qin Empire</English>
		<French>Qin Empire</French>
		<German>Qin Empire</German>
		<Italian>Qin Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Qin Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_QIN_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Duchy of Qin</English>
		<French>Duchy of Qin</French>
		<German>Duchy of Qin</German>
		<Italian>Duchy of Qin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Duchy of Qin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_QIN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SHU_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Shu</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Shu</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Shu</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Shu</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Shu</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SHU_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Shu</English>
		<French>Shu</French>
		<German>Shu</German>
		<Italian>Shu</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shu</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SHU_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Shu</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Shu</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Shu</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Shu</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Shu</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SHU_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Duchy of Shu</English>
		<French>Duchy of Shu</French>
		<German>Duchy of Shu</German>
		<Italian>Duchy of Shu</Italian>
		<Spanish>Duchy of Shu</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SHU_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Shu</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Shu</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Shu</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Shu</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Shu</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SHU_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Shu-Han was one of the three states competing for control of China during the Three Kingdoms period, after the fall of the Han Dynasty. The state was based on areas around Sichuan, which was then known as Shu. Some historians argue it was the last Han Dynasty because its founding emperor Liu Bei was directly related to the sovereign family of the original Han Dynasty, and bore their surname. The other two states were Cao Wei in central and northern China and Eastern Wu in southeastern China. The state is sometimes known as the Kingdom of Shu, though this usage is ambiguous as it was the name of the older Shu state in the area (ca. 1046 BC - 316 BC).</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WU_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Wu</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Wu</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Wu</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Wu</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Wu</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WU_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Wu</English>
		<French>Wu</French>
		<German>Wu</German>
		<Italian>Wu</Italian>
		<Spanish>Wu</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WU_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Wu</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Wu</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Wu</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Wu</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Wu</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WU_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Duchy of Wu</English>
		<French>Duchy of Wu</French>
		<German>Duchy of Wu</German>
		<Italian>Duchy of Wu</Italian>
		<Spanish>Duchy of Wu</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WU_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Wu</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Wu</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Wu</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Wu</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Wu:Wu</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WU_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Eastern Wu also known as Sun Wu, was one the three states competing for control of China during the Three Kingdoms period after the fall of the Han Dynasty. It was based in the Jiangnan (Yangtze River Delta) region of China. During its existence, its capital was at Jianye (present-day Nanjing, Jiangsu), but at times it was also at Wuchang (present-day Ezhou, Hubei).</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GUPTA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Gupta Empire</English>
		<French>Gupta Empire</French>
		<German>Gupta Empire</German>
		<Italian>Gupta Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gupta Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GUPTA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Gupta Empire</English>
		<French>Gupta Empire</French>
		<German>Gupta Empire</German>
		<Italian>Gupta Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gupta Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GUPTA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Gupta Empire</English>
		<French>Gupta Empire</French>
		<German>Gupta Empire</German>
		<Italian>Gupta Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gupta Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GUPTA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Gupta Kingdom</English>
		<French>Gupta Kingdom</French>
		<German>Gupta Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Gupta Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gupta Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GUPTA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Guptan:Guptans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Guptan:Guptans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Guptan:Guptans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Guptan:Guptans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Guptan:Guptans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GUPTA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Gupta Empire was an Ancient Indian empire which existed approximately from 320 to 550 AD and covered much of the Indian Subcontinent. Founded by Maharaja Sri-Gupta, the dynasty was the model of a classical civilization. The peace and prosperity created under leadership of Guptas enabled the pursuit of scientific and artistic endeavors. This period is called the Golden Age of India and was marked by extensive inventions and discoveries in science, technology, engineering, art, dialectic, literature, logic, mathematics, astronomy, religion and philosophy that crystallized the elements of what is generally known as Hindu culture. Chandragupta I, Samudragupta, and Chandragupta II were the most notable rulers of the Gupta dynasty.[PARAGRAPH:2]The high points of this cultural creativity are magnificent architecture, sculptures and paintings. The Gupta period produced scholars such as Kalidasa, Aryabhata, Varahamihira, Vishnu Sharma and Vatsyayana who made great advancements in many academic fields. Science and political administration reached new heights during the Gupta era. Strong trade ties also made the region an important cultural center and set the region up as a base that would influence nearby kingdoms and regions in Burma, Sri Lanka, Malay Archipelago and Indochina.[PARAGRAPH:2]The earliest available Puranas are also thought to have been written around this period. The empire gradually declined because of many factors like the substantial loss of territory and imperial authority caused by their own erstwhile feudatories and the invasion by the Hunas from Central Asia. After the collapse of the Gupta Empire in the 6th century, India was again ruled by numerous regional kingdoms. A minor line of the Gupta clan continued to rule Magadha after the disintegration of the empire. These Guptas were ultimately ousted by the Vardhana ruler Harsha, who established an empire in the first half of the 7th century.[PARAGRAPH:2]A study of the epigraphical records of the Gupta empire shows that there was a hierarchy of administrative divisions from top to bottom. The empire was called by various names such as Rajya, Rashtra, Desha, Mandala, Prithvi and Avani. It was divided in to 26 provinces, which were styled as Bhukti, Pradesha and Bhoga. Provinces were also divided into Vishayas and put under the control of the Vishayapatis. A Vishayapati administered the Vishaya with the help of the Adhikarana (council of representatives), which comprised four representatives: Nagarasreshesthi, Sarthavaha, Prathamakulika and Prathama Kayastha. A part of the Vishaya was called Vithi.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ajanta paintings were made during the Gupta period. Scholars of this period include Varahamihira and Aryabhata, who is believed to be the first to come up with the concept of zero, postulated the theory that the Earth moves round the Sun, and studied solar and lunar eclipses. Kalidasa, who was a great playwright, who wrote plays such as Shakuntala, which is said to have inspired Goethe, and marked the highest point of Sanskrit literature is also said to have belonged to this period.The famous Sushruta Samhita, which is a Sanskrit redaction text on all of the major concepts of ayurvedic medicine with innovative chapters on surgery, dates to the Gupta period.[PARAGRAPH:2]The flow of invasions from the Huns from central Asia aided in accelerating the demise of the glorious Gupta dynasty rule in India, although the effects of its fall was far less devastating than that of the Han or Roman at the same time. According to historian's work, the Gupta Empire is considered by many scholars to be the "classical age" of Hindu and Buddhist art and literature. The Rulers of the Gupta Empire were strong supporters of developments in the arts, architecture, science, and literature. The Gupta Empire circulated a large number of gold coins, called dinars, and supported the Universities of Nalanda and Vikramasila.[PARAGRAPH:2]Chess is said to have originated in this period, where its early form in the 6th century was known as caturaga, which translates as "four divisions (of the military)" infantry, cavalry, elephants, and chariotry represented by the pieces that would evolve into the modern pawn, knight, bishop, and rook, respectively. Doctors also invented several medical instruments, and even performed operations. The Indian numerals which were the first positional base 10 numeral systems in the world originated from Gupta India. The ancient Gupta text Kama Sutra is widely considered to be the standard work on human sexual behavior in Sanskrit literature written by the Indian scholar Vatsyayana. Aryabhata, a noted mathematician-astronomer of the Gupta period proposed that the earth is not flat, but is instead round and rotates about its own axis. He also discovered that the Moon and planets shine by reflected sunlight. Instead of the prevailing cosmogony in which eclipses were caused by pseudo-planetary nodes Rahu and Ketu, he explained eclipses in terms of shadows cast by and falling on Earth. These and the other scientific discoveries made by Indians during this period about gravity and the planets of the solar system spread throughout the world through trade.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SATAVAHANA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Satavahana Empire</English>
		<French>Satavahana Empire</French>
		<German>Satavahana Empire</German>
		<Italian>Satavahana Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Satavahana Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SATAVAHANA_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Satavahana Empire</English>
		<French>Satavahana Empire</French>
		<German>Satavahana Empire</German>
		<Italian>Satavahana Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Satavahana Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SATAVAHANA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Satavahana</English>
		<French>Satavahana</French>
		<German>Satavahana</German>
		<Italian>Satavahana</Italian>
		<Spanish>Satavahana</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SATAVAHANA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Satavahana Empire</English>
		<French>Satavahana Empire</French>
		<German>Satavahana Empire</German>
		<Italian>Satavahana Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Satavahana Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SATAVAHANA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Satavahana Empire</English>
		<French>Satavahana Empire</French>
		<German>Satavahana Empire</German>
		<Italian>Satavahana Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Satavahana Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SATAVAHANA_SULTANATE_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Sultanate of Satavahana</English>
		<French>Sultanate of Satavahana</French>
		<German>Sultanate of Satavahana</German>
		<Italian>Sultanate of Satavahana</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sultanate of Satavahana</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SATAVAHANA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Satavahanan:Satavahanans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Satavahanan:Satavahanans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Satavahanan:Satavahanans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>v
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Satavahanan:Satavahanans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SATAVAHANA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Satavahana Empire or Andhra Empire, was a royal Indian dynasty based from Dharanikota and Amaravati in Andhra Pradesh as well as Junnar (Pune) and Prathisthan (Paithan) in Maharashtra. The territory of the empire covered much of India from 230 BCE onward. Although there is some controversy about when the dynasty came to an end, the most liberal estimates suggest that it lasted about 450 years, until around 220 CE. The Satavahanas are credited for establishing peace in the country, resisting the onslaught of foreigners after the decline of Mauryan Empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]Satavahanas started out as feudatories to the Mauryan dynasty, but declared independence with its decline. They are known for their patronage of Buddhism which resulted in Buddhist monuments from Ellora (a UNESCO World Heritage Site) to Amaravati. The Satavahanas were one of the first Indian state to issue coins struck with their rulers embossed. They formed a cultural bridge and played a vital role in trade as well as the transfer of ideas and culture to and from the Indo-Gangetic Plain to the southern tip of India.[PARAGRAPH:2]They had to compete with the Sungas and then the Kanvas of Magadha to establish their rule. Later, they had to contend in protecting their domain from the incursions of Sakas, Yavanas and Pahlavas. In particular their struggles with the Western Kshatrapas weakened them and the empire split into smaller states.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VAKATAKA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Vakataka Kingdom</English>
		<French>Vakataka Kingdom</French>
		<German>Vakataka Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Vakataka Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vakataka Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VAKATAKA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Vakataka Kingdom</English>
		<French>Vakataka Kingdom</French>
		<German>Vakataka Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Vakataka Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vakataka Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VAKATAKA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Vakataka Kingdom</English>
		<French>Vakataka Kingdom</French>
		<German>Vakataka Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Vakataka Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vakataka Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VAKATAKA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Vakataka Princedom</English>
		<French>Vakataka Princedom</French>
		<German>Vakataka Princedom</German>
		<Italian>Vakataka Princedom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vakataka Princedom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VAKATAKA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Vakataka:Vakatakas</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Vakataka:Vakatakas</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Vakataka:Vakatakas</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>v
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Vakataka:Vakatakas</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VAKATAKA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Vakataka Empire was an Indian dynasty that originated from the Deccan in the mid-third century CE. Their state is believed to have extended from the southern edges of Malwa and Gujarat in the north to the Tungabhadra River in the south as well as from the Arabian Sea in the western to the edges of Chhattisgarh in the east. They were the most important successors of the Satavahanas in the Deccan and contemporaneous with the Guptas in northern India.The Vakatakas, like many coeval dynasties of the Deccan, claimed Brahmanical origin. Little is known about Vindhyasakti (c. 250-270 CE), the founder of the family, whose name occurs in the Puranas. Territorial expansion began in the reign of his son Pravarasena I. It is generally believed that the Vakataka dynasty was divided into four branches after Pravarsena I. Two branches are known and two are unknown. The known branches are the Pravarpura-Nandivardhana branch and the Vatsagulma branch. The Gupta emperor Chandragupta II married his daughter into Vakataka royal family and with their support annexed Gujarat from the Saka Satraps in fourth century CE. The Vakataka power was followed by that of the Chalukyas of Badami in Deccan. The Vakatakas are noted for having been great patrons of arts, architecture and literature. They led great amount of public work and their monuments are a visible legacy. The rock-cut Buddhist viharas and chaityas of Ajanta Caves (a UNESCO World Heritage Site) was built under the patronage of Vakataka Emperor Harishena.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SONG_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Liu Song Empire</English>
		<French>Liu Song Empire</French>
		<German>Liu Song Empire</German>
		<Italian>Liu Song Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Liu Song Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SONG_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Liu Song</English>
		<French>Liu Song</French>
		<German>Liu Song</German>
		<Italian>Liu Song</Italian>
		<Spanish>Liu Song</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SONG_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Liu Song Empire</English>
		<French>Liu Song Empire</French>
		<German>Liu Song Empire</German>
		<Italian>Liu Song Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Liu Song Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SONG_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Liu Song Princedom</English>
		<French>Liu Song Princedom</French>
		<German>Liu Song Princedom</German>
		<Italian>Liu Song Princedom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Liu Song Princedom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SONG_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Liu Song:Liu Song</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Liu Song:Liu Song</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Liu Song:Liu Song</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>v
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Liu Song:Liu Song</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SONG_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Liu Song Dynasty, also known as Former Song Dynasty (420-479 CE), was first of the four Southern Dynasties in China, succeeding the Eastern Jin Dynasty and followed by the Southern Qi Dynasty.The dynasty was founded by Liu Yu (363-422), whose surname together with "Song" forms the most commonly used name for the dynasty, the Liu Song. This appellation is used to distinguish it from a later dynasty of the same name, the Song Dynasty (960-1279), which is much more famous and significant. The Liu Song is also at times referred to as the "Southern Song Dynasty", as it is one of the Southern Dynasties period, i.e., one of those with its capital at Jiankang (modern Nanjing). However, the later Song Dynasty, after 1127, when it moved its capital south to Lin'an (modern Hangzhou, Zhejiang), is most commonly referred to as "Southern Song Dynasty". Thus, for the shorter dynasty which is the subject of this article, "Liu Song" has become the term preferred in most contexts.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PANDYANS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Tamil Kingdoms</English>
		<French>Tamil Kingdoms</French>
		<German>Tamil Kingdoms</German>
		<Italian>Tamil Kingdoms</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tamil Kingdoms</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PANDYANS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Tamils</English>
		<French>Tamils</French>
		<German>Tamils</German>
		<Italian>Tamils</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tamils</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PANDYANS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Tamil Kingdoms</English>
		<French>Tamil Kingdoms</French>
		<German>Tamil Kingdoms</German>
		<Italian>Tamil Kingdoms</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tamil Kingdoms</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PANDYANS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Pandyan Empire</English>
		<French>Pandyan Empire</French>
		<German>Pandyan Empire</German>
		<Italian>Pandyan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pandyan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PANDYANS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Princedom of Pandya</English>
		<French>Princedom of Pandya</French>
		<German>Princedom of Pandya</German>
		<Italian>Princedom of Pandya</Italian>
		<Spanish>Princedom of Pandya</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PANDYANS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Tamil:Tamils</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Tamil:Tamils</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Tamil:Tamils</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Tamil:Tamils</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Pandyan:Pandyans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PANDYANS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Pandyan dynasty was an ancient Tamil dynasty. The Pandyas were one of the four Tamil dynasties (the other three being Chola, Chera and Pallava ), which ruled South India until the 15th century CE. They initially ruled their country Pandya Nadu from Korkai, a seaport on the southernmost tip of the Indian Peninsula, and in later times moved to Madurai. Pandyan was well known since ancient times, with contacts, even diplomatic, reaching the Roman Empire. During the 13th century AD, Marco Polo mentioned it as the richest empire in existence. The Pandyan empire was home to temples including Meenakshi Amman Temple in Madurai, and Nellaiappar Temple built on the bank of the river Thamirabarani in Tirunelveli. The Pandya kings were called either Jatavarman or Maravarman Pandyan. From being Jains in their early ages, they became Shaivaits after some centuries of rule.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Pandyas of Southern India are believed to have been founded at least five to six centuries before the Christian Era with a very strong possibility of a more ancient date of establishment. Their recorded existence and mention are found in records dating to as early as 550 BCE. Emperor Augustus of Rome at Antioch knew of the Pandyan of Dramira and received a Pandyan ambassador with letters and gifts from this ancient Tamil Kingdom. Strabo described an ambassador to emperor Augustus Caesar from a South Indian King called Pandyan. The country of the Pandyas, Pandi Mandala, was described as Pandyan Mediterranea by Periplus and Modura Regia Pandyan by Ptolemy.[PARAGRAPH:2]The early Pandyan Dynasty of the Sangam Literature faded into obscurity upon the invasion of the Kalabhras. The dynasty revived under Kadungon in the early 6th century, pushed the Kalabhras out of the Tamil country and ruled from Madurai They again went into decline with the rise of the Cholas in the 9th century and were in constant conflict with them. The Pandyas allied themselves with the Sinhalese and the Cheras in harassing the Chola empire until they found an opportunity for reviving their fortunes during the late 13th century.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Later Pandyas (1150-1350) entered their golden age under Maravman Sundara Pandyan and Jatavarman Sundara Pandyan (c. 1251), who expanded the empire into Telugu country, conquered Kalinka (Orissa) and invaded and conquered Sri Lanka. They also had extensive trade links with the Southeast Asian maritime empires of Srivijaya and their successors. During their history, the Pandyas were repeatedly in conflict with the Pallavas, Cholas, Hoysalas and finally the Muslim invaders from the Delhi Sultanate. The Pandyan Kingdom finally became extinct after the establishment of the Madurai Sultanate in the 16th century.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Pandyas excelled in both trade and literature before the Christian Era. They controlled the pearl fisheries along the South Indian coast, between Sri Lanka and India, which produced some of the finest pearls in the known ancient world. Traditionally, the legendary Sangams were held in Madurai under their patronage, and some of the Pandya Kings were poets themselves.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CELTS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Celtic Kingdom</English>
		<French>Celtic Kingdom</French>
		<German>Celtic Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Celtic Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Celtic Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CELTS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Celtic Kingdom</English>
		<French>Celtic Kingdom</French>
		<German>Celtic Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Celtic Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Celtic Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CELTS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Celtic</English>
		<French>Celtic</French>
		<German>Celtic</German>
		<Italian>Celtic</Italian>
		<Spanish>Celtic</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CELTS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Celtic Kingdom</English>
		<French>Celtic Kingdom</French>
		<German>Celtic Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Celtic Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Celtic Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CELTS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Celtic Kingdom</English>
		<French>Celtic Kingdom</French>
		<German>Celtic Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Celtic Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Celtic Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CELTS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Celtic Empire</English>
		<French>Celtic Empire</French>
		<German>Celtic Empire</German>
		<Italian>Celtic Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Celtic Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SELEUCIDS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Seleucid Empire</English>
		<French>Seleucid Empire</French>
		<German>Seleucid Empire</German>
		<Italian>Seleucid Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Seleucid Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SELEUCIDS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Seleucid Empire</English>
		<French>Seleucid Empire</French>
		<German>Seleucid Empire</German>
		<Italian>Seleucid Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Seleucid Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SELEUCIDS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Seleucid Empire</English>
		<French>Seleucid Empire</French>
		<German>Seleucid Empire</German>
		<Italian>Seleucid Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Seleucid Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SELEUCIDS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Seleucid Kingdom</English>
		<French>Seleucid Kingdom</French>
		<German>Seleucid Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Seleucid Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Seleucid Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SELEUCIDS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Seleucid Kingdom</English>
		<French>Seleucid Kingdom</French>
		<German>Seleucid Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Seleucid Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Seleucid Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SELEUCIDS_SULTANATE_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Seleucid Kingdom Sultanate</English>
		<French>Seleucid Kingdom Sultanate</French>
		<German>Seleucid Kingdom Sultanate</German>
		<Italian>Seleucid Kingdom Sultanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Seleucid Kingdom Sultanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SELEUCIDS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Seleucid:Seleucids</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>v</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Seleucid:Seleucids</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Seleucid:Seleucids</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Seleucid:Seleucids</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SELEUCIDS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]After the death of Alexander the Great in the afternoon of 11 June 323 BCE, his empire was divided by his generals, the Diadochi. One of them was his friend Seleucus, who became king of the eastern provinces - more or less modern Afghanistan, Iran, Iraq, Syria, and Lebanon, together with parts of Turkey, Armenia, Turkmenistan, Uzbekistan, and Tajikistan. His kingdom had two capitals, which he founded in c.300: Antioch in Syria (pictures) and Seleucia in Mesopotamia. Babylon was another important city. The empire was, like the empire of Alexander, actually the continuation of the empires before: the Assyrian, Babylonian, and the Achaemenid Empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]Seleucus' reign lasted from 312 to 281 (more...), and he was succeeded by his descendants, who continued to govern this assembly of countries for more than two centuries. However, in the mid-240's, during a brief interregnum, the Seleucids started to lose territory in the east, where the Parni nomads settled themselves in the satrapy of Parthia in northeastern Iran. At the same time, the satrapy of Bactria (northern Afghanistan) became independent. Later, the Seleucid king Antiochus III the Great was able to reconquer these territories, during a series of eastern wars between 209 and 204. In the southwest, the Seleucid kings fought several "Syrian wars" with the Egyptians; in 200, their king was forced to cede Palestine to Antiochus III. Seleucid power had reached its zenith. Yet, Antiochus was also forced to witness the beginning of its demise.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 196, he crossed the Hellespont in order to add Thrace to his empire (which happened in 194). Seleucid influence in Europe, however, was something that the Romans could not allow to happen, and the inevitable war between the two superpowers broke out in 192. (One of our sources, the Syriaca by the Greek historian Appian of Alexandria, can be read here.) Antiochus received support from many Greek towns and help from the famous Carthaginian general Hannibal, but was defeated and forced to pay a tremendous sum of money. Moreover, the Seleucid empire lost its possessions in what is now Turkey.[PARAGRAPH:2]The tide was now turning against the Seleucid monarchy. In the west, Rome became too powerful to resist. Worse, they backed the Jews, who liberated themselves in the years after 165 (the Maccabaean revolt). At the same time, the Parni founded the Parthian empire, which snatched away the eastern provinces. The towns in Babylonia, a.o. Seleucia and Babylon, were captured between April and June 141. New losses followed, civil wars between two rival factions of the Seleucid family were inevitable, and in the second quarter of the first century, the Roman generals Lucullus and Pompey the Great made an end to the Seleucid kingdom. The last king was dethroned in 64.[PARAGRAPH:2]The official name of the kingdom was Asia, but the Romans called it Syria.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SASSANIDS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Sassanid Empire</English>
		<French>Sassanid Empire</French>
		<German>Sassanid Empire</German>
		<Italian>Sassanid Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sassanid Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SASSANIDS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Sassanid Empire</English>
		<French>Sassanid Empire</French>
		<German>Sassanid Empire</German>
		<Italian>Sassanid Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sassanid Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SASSANIDS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Sassanid Kingdom</English>
		<French>Sassanid Kingdom</French>
		<German>Sassanid Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Sassanid Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sassanid Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SASSANIDS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Sassanid Empire</English>
		<French>Sassanid Empire</French>
		<German>Sassanid Empire</German>
		<Italian>Sassanid Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sassanid Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SASSANIDS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Sassanid Kingdom</English>
		<French>Sassanid Kingdom</French>
		<German>Sassanid Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Sassanid Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sassanid Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SASSANIDS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Sassanid:Sassanids</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Sassanid:Sassanids</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Sassanid:Sassanids</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Sassanid:Sassanids</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Sassanid:Sassanids</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SASSANIDS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Sassanid Empire or Sasanian Empire, known to its inhabitants as Eranshahr, was the last pre-Islamic Persian Empire, ruled by the Sasanian Dynasty from 224 to 651. The Sassanid Empire was recognized as one of the two main powers in Western Asia and Europe alongside the Roman Empire and later the Byzantine Empire for a period of more than 400 years.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Empire was founded by Ardashir I, after the fall of the Arsacids and the defeat of the last Arsacid king, Artabanus IV. The Empire lasted till Yazdegerd III lost control of his empire in a series of invasions from the Arab Caliphate. During its existence, the Sassanid Empire encompassed all of today's Iran, Afghanistan, Iraq, Syria, the Caucasus (Armenia, Georgia, Azerbaijan and Dagestan), southwestern Central Asia, part of Turkey, certain coastal parts of the Arabian Peninsula, the Persian Gulf area, and areas of southwestern Pakistan.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Sassanid era, during Late Antiquity, is considered to have been one of Iran's most important and influential historical periods. In many ways the Sassanid period witnessed the highest achievement of ancient Persian civilization, and constituted the last great Iranian empire before the Muslim conquest and the adoption of Islam. Persia influenced Roman civilization considerably during the Sassanids' times, and the empires regarded one another as equals, as exemplified in the letters written by the rulers of the two states addressing each other as "brother". The Sassanids' cultural influence extended far beyond the empire's territorial borders, reaching as far as Western Europe, Africa, China, and India. It played a prominent role in the formation of both European and Asiatic medieval art.[PARAGRAPH:2]This influence, and especially the dynasty's unique, aristocratic culture, carried forward to the early Islamic world after the Muslim conquest of Iran. An Iranian scholar, Zarinkoob, found that much of what later came to be known as Islamic culture, architecture, writing and other skills, were borrowed mainly from the Sassanids, then propagated throughout the broader Muslim world. In modern Iran and the regions of the Iranosphere the Sassanid period is regarded as one of the high points of Iranian civilization.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROME_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Roman Empire</English>
		<French>Roman Empire</French>
		<German>Roman Empire</German>
		<Italian>Roman Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Roman Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROME_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Roman</English>
		<French>Roman</French>
		<German>Roman</German>
		<Italian>Roman</Italian>
		<Spanish>Roman</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROME_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Roman Empire</English>
		<French>Roman Empire</French>
		<German>Roman Empire</German>
		<Italian>Roman Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Roman Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROME_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Rome</English>
		<French>Rome</French>
		<German>Rome</German>
		<Italian>Rome</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rome</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROME_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Roman Empire</English>
		<French>Roman Empire</French>
		<German>Roman Empire</German>
		<Italian>Roman Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Roman Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROME_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Province of the Romans</English>
		<French>Roman Empire</French>
		<German>Roman Empire</German>
		<Italian>Roman Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Roman Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TANG_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Tang Empire</English>
		<French>Tang Empire</French>
		<German>Tang Empire</German>
		<Italian>Tang Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tang Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TANG_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Tang Empire</English>
		<French>Tang Empire</French>
		<German>Tang Empire</German>
		<Italian>Tang Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tang Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TANG_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Tang Empire</English>
		<French>Tang Empire</French>
		<German>Tang Empire</German>
		<Italian>Tang Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tang Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TANG_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Duchy of Tang</English>
		<French>Duchy of Tang</French>
		<German>Duchy of Tang</German>
		<Italian>Duchy of Tang</Italian>
		<Spanish>Duchy of Tang</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TANG_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Tang:Tang</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Tang:Tang</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Tang:Tang</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Tang:Tang</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Tang:Tang</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TANG_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Tang Dynasty (June 18, 618 - June 1, 907) was an imperial dynasty of China preceded by the Sui Dynasty and followed by the Five Dynasties and Ten Kingdoms Period. It was founded by the Li family, who seized power during the decline and collapse of the Sui Empire. The dynasty was interrupted briefly by the Second Zhou Dynasty (October 8, 690 - March 3, 705) when Empress Wu Zetian seized the throne, becoming the first and only Chinese empress regnant, ruling in her own right.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Tang Dynasty, with its capital at Chang'an (present-day Xi'an), the most populous city in the world at the time, is generally regarded as a high point in Chinese civilization-equal to, or surpassing that of, the earlier Han Dynasty -a golden age of cosmopolitan culture. Its territory, acquired through the military campaigns of its early rulers, was greater than that of the Han period, and it rivalled that of the later Yuan Dynasty and Qing Dynasty. In two censuses of the 7th and 8th centuries, the Tang records estimated the population by number of registered households at about 50 million people. Yet, even when the central government was breaking down and unable to compile an accurate census of the population in the 9th century, it is estimated that the population had grown by then to about 80 million people. With its large population base, the dynasty was able to raise professional and conscripted armies of hundreds of thousands of troops to contend with nomadic powers in dominating Inner Asia and the lucrative trade routes along the Silk Road. Various kingdoms and states paid tribute to the Tang court, while the Tang also conquered or subdued several regions which it indirectly controlled through a protectorate system. Besides political hegemony, the Tang also exerted a powerful cultural influence over neighboring states such as those in Korea, Japan, and Vietnam.[NEWLINE][TAB]The Tang Dynasty was largely a period of progress and stability, except during the An Shi Rebellion and the decline of central authority in the latter half of the dynasty. Like the previous Sui Dynasty, the Tang Dynasty maintained a civil service system by drafting officials through standardized examinations and recommendations to office. This civil order was undermined by the rise of regional military governors known as jiedushi during the 9th century. Chinese culture flourished and further matured during the Tang era; it is considered the greatest age for Chinese poetry. Two of China's most famous poets, Li Bai and Du Fu, belonged to this age, as did many famous painters such as Han Gan, Zhang Xuan, and Zhou Fang. There was a rich variety of historical literature compiled by scholars, as well as encyclopedias and geographical works.[PARAGRAPH:2]There were many notable innovations during the Tang, including the development of woodblock printing. Buddhism became a major influence in Chinese culture, with native Chinese sects gaining prominence. However, Buddhism would later be persecuted by the state and decline in influence. Although the dynasty and central government were in decline by the 9th century, art and culture continued to flourish. The weakened central government largely withdrew from managing the economy, though the country's mercantile affairs stayed intact and commercial trade continued to thrive regardless.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SRIVAJAYA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Sri Vijayan Empire</English>
		<French>Sri Vijayan Empire</French>
		<German>Reich von Sri Vijaya</German>
		<Italian>Sri Vijayan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sri Vijayan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SRIVAJAYA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Sri Vijaya</English>
		<French>Sri Vijaya</French>
		<German>Sri Vijaya</German>
		<Italian>Sri Vijaya</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sri Vijaya</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SRIVAJAYA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Sri Vijayan Empire</English>
		<French>Sri Vijayan Empire</French>
		<German>Reich von Sri Vijaya</German>
		<Italian>Sri Vijayan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sri Vijayan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SRIVAJAYA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Sri Vijayan Empire</English>
		<French>Sri Vijayan Empire</French>
		<German>Reich von Sri Vijaya</German>
		<Italian>Sri Vijayan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sri Vijayan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SRIVAJAYA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Srivajayan:Srivajayans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Srivajayan:Srivajayans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Srivajayan:Srivajayans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>v
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Srivajayan:Srivajayans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SRIVAJAYA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Sri Vijaya was a powerful ancient thalassocratic Malay empire based on the island of Sumatra, modern day Indonesia, which influenced much of Southeast Asia. The earliest solid proof of its existence dates from the 7th century; a Chinese monk, I-Tsing, wrote that he visited Srivijaya in 671 for 6 months. The first inscription in which the name Srivijaya appears also dates from the 7th century, namely the Kedukan Bukit Inscription around Palembang in Sumatra, dated 683. The kingdom ceased to exist in the 13th century due to various factors, including the expansion of the Javanese Majapahit empire. Srivijaya was an important center for Buddhist expansion in the 8th to 12th centuries. In Sanskrit, sri means "shining" or "radiant" and vijaya means "victory" or "excellence".[PARAGRAPH:2]After Srivijaya fell, it was largely forgotten and historians had not even considered that a large united kingdom could have been present in Southeast Asia. The existence of Srivijaya was only formally suspected in 1918, when French historian George Coedass of the acole francaise d'Extreme-Orient postulated its existence. By 1993, Pierre-Yves Manguin had proven that the centre of Srivijaya was along the Musi River between Bukit Seguntang and Sabokingking (situated in what is now the province of South Sumatra, Indonesia).[PARAGRAPH:2]There was no continuous knowledge of Srivijaya even in Indonesian histories; its forgotten past has been recreated by foreign scholars. No modern Indonesians, not even those of the Palembang area around which the kingdom was based, had heard of Srivijaya until the 1920s, when French scholar George CoedÃss published his discoveries and interpretations in Dutch and Indonesian-language newspapers. CoedÃss noted that the Chinese references to "Sanfoqi", previously read as "Sribhoja", and the inscriptions in Old Malay refer to the same empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]Srivijaya has become a symbol of early Sumatran importance as a great empire to balance Java's Majapahit in the east. In the twentieth century, both empires were referred to by nationalist intellectuals to argue for an Indonesian identity within an Indonesian state prior to the Dutch colonial state.[PARAGRAPH:2]Srivijaya and by extension Sumatra had been known by different names to different peoples. The Chinese called it Sanfotsi or San Fo Qi, and there was an even older kingdom of Kantoli that could be considered the predecessor of Srivijaya. Sanskrit and Pali referred to it as Yavadesh and Javadeh, respectively. The Arabs called it Zabag and the Khmer called it Melayu. This is another reason why the discovery of Srivijaya was so difficult. While some of these names are strongly reminiscent of the name of Java, there is a distinct possibility that they may have referred to Sumatra instead.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first part "Sri " comes from Sanskrit and is an honourific place name, similar to Sri Lanka. "Vijaya" can mean "victory", a similarly named empire in India was called Vijayanagara. The name of the empire can therefore also be written "Sri Vijaya".</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ANTIGONIDS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Antigonid Kingdom</English>
		<French>Antigonid Kingdom</French>
		<German>Antigonid Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Antigonid Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Antigonid Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ANTIGONIDS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Antigonid Kingdom</English>
		<French>Antigonid Kingdom</French>
		<German>Antigonid Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Antigonid Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Antigonid Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ANTIGONIDS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Antigonid Empire</English>
		<French>Antigonid Empire</French>
		<German>Antigonid Empire</German>
		<Italian>Antigonid Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Antigonid Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ANTIGONIDS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Antigonid Kingdom</English>
		<French>Antigonid Kingdom</French>
		<German>Antigonid Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Antigonid Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Antigonid Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ANTIGONIDS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Antigonid Empire</English>
		<French>Antigonid Empire</French>
		<German>Antigonid Empire</German>
		<Italian>Antigonid Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Antigonid Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ANTIGONIDS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Antigonid:Antigonids</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>courdouan:courdouanne:courdouans:courdouannes</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Cordobanisch:cordobanischen:cordobanische</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter:Neuter:Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Cordoban:Cordobans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Cordoban:Cordobans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ANTIGONIDS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Antigonid dynasty was a dynasty of Hellenistic kings descended from Alexander the Great's general Antigonus I Monophthalmus ("the One-eyed").[PARAGRAPH:2]Succeeding the Antipatrid dynasty in much of Macedonia, Antigonus ruled mostly over Asia Minor and northern Syria. His attempts to take control of the whole of Alexander's empire led to his defeat and death at the Battle of Ipsus in 301 BC. Antigonus's son Demetrius I Poliorcetes survived the battle, and managed to seize control of Macedon itself a few years later, but eventually lost his throne, dying as a prisoner of Seleucus I. After a period of confusion, Demetrius's son Antigonus II Gonatas was able to establish the family's control over the old Kingdom of Macedon, as well as over most of the Greek city-states, by 276 BC.[PARAGRAPH:2]It was one of four dynasties established by Alexander's successors, the others being the Seleucid dynasty, Ptolemaic dynasty and Attalid dynasty. The last scion of the dynasty, Perseus of Macedon, who reigned between 179-168 BC, proved unable to stop the advancing Roman legions and Macedon's defeat at the Battle of Pydna signaled the end of the dynasty.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GHANA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Ghana Empire</English>
		<French>Ghana Empire</French>
		<German>Ghana Empire</German>
		<Italian>Ghana Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ghana Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GHANA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Ghana</English>
		<French>Ghana</French>
		<German>Ghana</German>
		<Italian>Ghana</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ghana</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GHANA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Ghana Empire</English>
		<French>Ghana Empire</French>
		<German>Ghana Empire</German>
		<Italian>Ghana Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ghana Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GHANA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Ghana</English>
		<French>Ghana</French>
		<German>Ghana</German>
		<Italian>Ghana</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ghana</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GHANA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Ghanan:Ghanans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Ghanan:Ghanans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Ghanan:Ghanans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Ghanan:Ghanans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Ghanan:Ghanans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GHANA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Ghana Empire or Wagadou Empire was located in what is now southeastern Mauritania, and Western Mali. Complex societies had existed in the region since about 1500 BCE, and around Ghana's core region since about 300 CE. When Ghana's ruling dynasty began is uncertain, it is first mentioned in documentary sources around 830 CE by Al-Kwarizmi. The domestication of the camel, which preceded Muslims and Islam by several centuries, brought about a gradual change in trade, and for the first time, the extensive gold, ivory trade, and salt resources of the region could be sent north and east to population centers in North Africa, the Middle East and Europe in exchange for manufactured goods.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Empire grew rich from the trans-Saharan trade in gold and salt. This trade produced an increasing surplus, allowing for larger urban centres. It also encouraged territorial expansion to gain control over the lucrative trade routes.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first written mention of the kingdom comes from Arabic-language sources some time after the conquest of North Africa by Muslims, when geographers began compiling comprehensive accounts of the world known to Islam around 800. The sources for the earlier periods are very strange as to its society, government or culture, though they do describe its location and note its commercial relations. The Cordoban scholar Abu Ubayd al-Bakri collected stories from a number of travelers to the region, and gave a detailed description of the kingdom in 1067/1068. He claimed that the Ghana could "put 200,000 men into the field, more than 40,000 of them archers" and noted they had cavalry forces as well.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Gold Coast achieved independence from the United Kingdom in 1957, becoming the first sub-Saharan African nation to do so, and the name Ghana was chosen for the new nation to reflect the ancient Empire of Ghana, which once extended throughout much of west Africa. Ghana is a member of the South Atlantic Peace and Cooperation Zone, the Commonwealth of Nations, the Economic Community of West African States, the African Union, and an associate member of La Francophonie. Ghana is the second largest producer of cocoa in the world and is home to Lake Volta, the largest artificial lake in the world by surface area. The economy of Ghana has been listed as The World's Fastest Growing Economy in 2011 with an economic growth of about 20.146 % for the year 2011 in economic research led by Economy Watch with data coming from the IMF's tracker of GDP Growth in constant prices in the national currency.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANKS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Frankish Empire</English>
		<French>Frankish Empire</French>
		<German>Frankish Empire</German>
		<Italian>Frankish Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frankish Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANKS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Frankish Empire</English>
		<French>Frankish Empire</French>
		<German>Frankish Empire</German>
		<Italian>Frankish Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frankish Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANKS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Frankish Kingdom</English>
		<French>Frankish Kingdom</French>
		<German>Frankish Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Frankish Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frankish Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANKS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Frankish Kingdom</English>
		<French>Frankish Kingdom</French>
		<German>Frankish Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Frankish Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frankish Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANKS_KINGDOM_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Frankish Kingdom</English>
		<French>Frankish Kingdom</French>
		<German>Frankish Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Frankish Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frankish Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANKS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>County of Francia</English>
		<French>Frankish Kingdom</French>
		<German>Frankish Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Frankish Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frankish Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANKS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Frankish:Franks</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Frankish:Franks</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Frankish:Franks</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Frankish:Franks</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Frankish:Franks</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANKS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Francia or Frankia, later also called the Frankish Empire (Latin: imperium Francorum), Frankish Kingdom (Latin: regnum Francorum, "Kingdom of the Franks"), Frankish Realm or occasionally Frankland, was the territory inhabited and ruled by the Franks from the 3rd to the 10th century. Under the nearly continuous campaigns of Charles Martel, Pepin the Short, and Charlemagne-father, son, grandson-the greatest expansion of the Frankish empire was secured by the early 9th century.[PARAGRAPH:2]The tradition of dividing patrimonies among brothers meant that the Frankish realm was ruled, nominally, as one polity subdivided into several regna (kingdoms or subkingdoms). The geography and number of subkingdoms varied over time, but the particular term Francia came generally to refer to just one regnum, that of Austrasia, centred on the Rhine and Meuse rivers in northern Europe; even so, sometimes the term was used as well to encompass Neustria north of the Loire and west of the Seine. Eventually, the singular use of the name Francia shifted towards Paris, and settled on the region of the Seine basin surrounding Paris, which still today bears the name Ile-de-France, and which region gave its name to the entire Kingdom of France.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DACIA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Dacian Kingdom</English>
		<French>Dacian Kingdom</French>
		<German>Dacian Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Dacian Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dacian Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DACIA_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Dacian Empire</English>
		<French>Dacian Empire</French>
		<German>Dacian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Dacian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dacian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DACIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Dacia</English>
		<French>Dacia</French>
		<German>Dacia</German>
		<Italian>Dacia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dacia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DACIA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Dacian Kingdom</English>
		<French>Dacian Kingdom</French>
		<German>Dacian Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Dacian Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dacian Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DACIA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Dacia</English>
		<French>Dacia</French>
		<German>Dacia</German>
		<Italian>Dacia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dacia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DACIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Dacian:Dacians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Dacian:Dacians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Dacian:Dacians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Dacian:Dacians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Dacian:Dacians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DACIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]According to Herodotus, the Getae were "the noblest as well as the most just of all the Thracian tribes." Getae was the name by which ancient Greek writers referred to the tribes later known as the Dacians (Romanians). When Darius led the Persians in war against the Scythians, the Thracian tribes in the Balkans all surrendered. Only Getae fought the great Persian king.[PARAGRAPH:1]Although frequently considered a war-like people, the Getae were also cunning diplomats. When the king of Macedon Lysimachus tried to conquer the Getae living North of Danube, he was defeated. The Getae king Dromichaetes took Lysimachus prisoner but treated him well. He convinced Lysimachus that there was more to gain as an ally of Getae and released him.[PARAGRAPH:1]From 85 to 89 AD, the Dacians were engaged in two wars with the Romans, under their the great king Decebalus. In 87 AD, the Roman troops under Cormelius Fuscus were defeated, and Cornelius Fuscus was killed by the Dacians under the authority of their ruler, Diurpaneus. After this victory, Diurpaneus took the name of Decebalus. The next year, 88 AD, new Roman troops under Tettius Iullianus, gained a signal advantage, but were obliged to make peace owing to the defeat of Domitian by the Marcomanni, so the Dacians were really left independent. Although receiving the title "king client to Rome," Decebalus received military instructors, craftsmen and even money from Rome, begging the question of who had surrendered to whom.[PARAGRAPH:1]It took the great Roman general Trajan to end this shameful negotiated peace. His first campaign 101-102) was the siege of the Dacian capital Sarmizegetusa and the occupation of a part of the country. His second campaign (105-106) ended with the suicide of Decebalus, and the conquest of the territory that was to form the Roman province Dacia Traiana.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La Dacia, antica terra dei Daci o Geti, era un'ampia regione dell'Europa centrale, delimitata a nord dai monti Carpazi ed a sud dal Danubio, corrispondente pertanto all'area delle odierne Romania e Moldavia. Gli abitanti di questa regione, appartenenti al ceppo tracico, erano conosciuti come Geton (al plurale, Getae) dai greci, e come Dacus (al plurale, Daci) dai romani. Gli scrittori antichi sono unanimi nel considerare i Geti e i Daci uno stesso popolo.[PARAGRAPH:1]I Daci avevano già raggiunto un considerevole grado di civilizzazione nel momento in cui vennero a contatto con i Romani. Le principali occupazioni dei Daci erano agricoltura, apicoltura, viticoltura, allevamento del bestiame, produzione di ceramica e metallurgia. La provincia romana di Dacia è rappresentata su un sesterzio (moneta romana), come una donna seduta su una roccia con un bambino piccolo su un ginocchio, che tiene delle spighe di grano, e un altro bambino seduto davanti a lei che tiene dei grappoli d'uva. I Daci lavoravano anche l'oro e l'argento proveniente dalle miniere in Transilvania, e portavano avanti un considerevole commercio con altri popoli, come dimostrano le molte monete straniere trovate nel paese.[PARAGRAPH:1]Secondo Erodoto, i Geti erano "la più nobile e la più giusta di tutte le tribù traciche". Quando i Persiani, guidati da Dario, attuarono una campagna contro gli Sciti, le tribù traciche dei Balcani si arresero a Dario e lo lasciarono passare sui loro territori; solo i Geti offrirono resistenza. Le due principali divinità dei Geti erano Zalmoxis e Gebeleixis. Sempre secondo Erodoto "queste persone, sotto i tuoni e i fulmini, puntano le loro frecce al cielo, minacciando gli dei; e loro non credono che ci sia alcun dio tranne che il loro".[PARAGRAPH:1]I Daci avevano anche sviluppato il murus dacicus, caratteristico dei loro complessi di città fortificate, come la loro capitale Sarmizegetusa, oggi Hunedoara in Romania. I Romani riuscirono a prendere la città solo identificando e distruggendo i condotti dell'acqua, ponendo così fine ad un lungo assedio. Traiano decise di conquistare la Dacia, guadagnando così il controllo sulle miniere d'oro, ed il risultato delle sue due campagne fu la sconfitta del re dacio Decebalo, la conquista della capitale e l'occupazione del territorio che avrebbe formato la provincia romana della Dacia Traiana. Molte informazioni su questa guerra che pose fine al regno dacio, sono deducibili dalle raffigurazioni scolpite sulla Colonna di Traiano a Roma.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MINOR_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Independent Cities</English>
		<French>Independent Cities</French>
		<German>Independent Cities</German>
		<Italian>Independent Cities</Italian>
		<Spanish>Independent Cities</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MINOR_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Independent Cities</English>
		<French>Independent Cities</French>
		<German>Independent Cities</German>
		<Italian>Independent Cities</Italian>
		<Spanish>Independent Cities</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MINOR_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Independent</English>
		<French>Independent</French>
		<German>Independent</German>
		<Italian>Independent</Italian>
		<Spanish>Independent</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MINOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>There are various independent city-states scattered around the map. They act similarly to barbarians, but remain peaceful to neighbors, as long as they are not attacked.</English>
		<French>There are various independent city-states scattered around the map. They act similarly to barbarians, but remain peaceful to neighbors, as long as they are not attacked.</French>
		<German>There are various independent city-states scattered around the map. They act similarly to barbarians, but remain peaceful to neighbors, as long as they are not attacked.</German>
		<Italian>There are various independent city-states scattered around the map. They act similarly to barbarians, but remain peaceful to neighbors, as long as they are not attacked.</Italian>
		<Spanish>There are various independent city-states scattered around the map. They act similarly to barbarians, but remain peaceful to neighbors, as long as they are not attacked.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AXUM_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Axum</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Axum</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Axum</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Axum</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Axum</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AXUM_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Axum</English>
		<French>Axum</French>
		<German>Axum</German>
		<Italian>Axum</Italian>
		<Spanish>Axum</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AXUM_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Axum</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Axum</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Axum</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Axum</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Axum</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AXUM_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Axum</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Axum</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Axum</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Axum</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Axum</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AXUM_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Axumite Empire</English>
		<French>Axumite Empire</French>
		<German>Axumite Empire</German>
		<Italian>Axumite Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Axumite Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AXUM_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Axumite:Axumites</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Axumite:Axumites</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Axumite:Axumites</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Axumite:Axumites</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Axumite:Axumites</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KUSHANS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kushan Empire</English>
		<French>Kushan Empire</French>
		<German>Kushan Empire</German>
		<Italian>Kushan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kushan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KUSHANS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kushan Empire</English>
		<French>Kushan Empire</French>
		<German>Kushan Empire</German>
		<Italian>Kushan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kushan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KUSHANS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kushan Kingdom</English>
		<French>Kushan Kingdom</French>
		<German>Kushan Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Kushan Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kushan Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KUSHANS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kushan Empire</English>
		<French>Kushan Empire</French>
		<German>Kushan Empire</German>
		<Italian>Kushan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kushan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KUSHANS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Duchy of Kushan</English>
		<French>Duchy of Kushan</French>
		<German>Duchy of Kushan</German>
		<Italian>Duchy of Kushan</Italian>
		<Spanish>Duchy of Kushan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KUSHANS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Kushan:Kushans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Kushan:Kushans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Kushan:Kushans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Kushan:Kushans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Kushan:Kushans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KUSHANS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The name Kushan derives from the Chinese term, traditionally transliterated Guishang, that described a branch of the Yuezhi: a loose confederation of Indo-European peoples speaking versions of the Tocharian language. They were the easternmost Indo-Europeans, who had been living in the arid grasslands of the Tarim Basin in modern-day Xinjiang, until they were driven west by the Xiongnu in 176-160 BCE. The Yuezhi reached the Hellenic kingdom of Greco-Bactria, in the Bactrian territory (northernmost Afghanistan and Uzbekistan) around 135 BCE, and displaced the Greek dynasties there, who resettled in Indus basin (in present day Pakistan) in the western part of the Indo-Greek Kingdom.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the following century, charismatic leaders welded the group into a tight confederation. Gradually wresting control of the area from the Scythian tribes, the Yuezhi expanded south into the region traditionally known as Gandhara and established twin capitals near present-day Kabul and Peshawar then known as Kapisa and Pushklavati respectively. The Kushans adopted many elements of the Hellenistic culture of Bactria, where they had settled. They adapted the Greek alphabet to suit their own language and soon began minting coinage on the Greek model.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the middle of the 2nd century, the Kushan empire under king Kanishka expanded into Central Asia and went as far as taking control of Kashgar, Khotan and Yarkand, which were Chinese dependencies in the Tarim Basin, modern Xinjiang. As a consequence, cultural exhanges greatly increased, and Central-Asian Buddhist missionaries became active shortly after in the Chinese capital cities of Loyang and sometimes Nanjing, where they particularly distinguished themselves by their translation work. They were the first promoters of Hinayana and Mahayana scriptures in China, greatly contributing to the Silk Road transmission of Buddhism.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the 3rd century the Kushan empire began to fragment. Around 225 Vasudeva I died and the Kushan empire was divided into western and eastern halves. Around 224-240, the Sasanians invaded Bactria and Northern India. Around 270, the Kushans lost their territories on the Gangetic plain. Remants of the Kushan empire were ultimately wiped out in the 5th century by the invasions of the White Huns, and later the expansion of Islam.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BACTRIA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Bactrian Kingdom</English>
		<French>Bactrian Kingdom</French>
		<German>Bactrian Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Bactrian Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bactrian Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BACTRIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Bactria</English>
		<French>Bactria</French>
		<German>Bactria</German>
		<Italian>Bactria</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bactria</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BACTRIA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Bactrian Kingdom</English>
		<French>Bactrian Kingdom</French>
		<German>Bactrian Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Bactrian Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bactrian Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BACTRIA_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Bactrian Kingdom</English>
		<French>Bactrian Kingdom</French>
		<German>Bactrian Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Bactrian Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bactrian Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BACTRIA_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Bactrian Empire</English>
		<French>Bactrian Empire</French>
		<German>Bactrian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Bactrian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bactrian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BACTRIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Bactrian:Bactrian</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Bactrian:Bactrian</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Bactrian:Bactrian</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Bactrian:Bactrian</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Bactrian:Bactrian</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BACTRIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Greco-Bactrian Kingdom was (along with the Indo-Greek Kingdom) the easternmost part of the Hellenistic world, covering Bactria and Sogdiana in Central Asia from 250 to 125 BC. The expansion of the Greco-Bactrians into northern India from 180 BC established the Indo-Greek Kingdom, which was to last until around 10 AD.[PARAGRAPH:2]Diodotus, the satrap of Bactria (and probably the surrounding provinces) founded the Greco-Bactrian Kingdom when he seceded from the Seleucid Empire around 250 BC and became King Diodotus I of Bactria. The preserved ancient sources (see below) are somewhat contradictory and the exact date of Bactrian independence has not been settled. Somewhat simplified, there is a high chronology (c. 255 BC) and a low chronology (c. 246 BC) for Diodotos' secession. The high chronology has the advantage of explaining why the Seleucid king Antiochus II issued very few coins in Bactria, as Diodotos would have become independent there early in Antiochus' reign. On the other hand, the low chronology, from the mid-240s BC, has the advantage of connecting the secession of Diodotus I with the Third Syrian War, a catastrophic conflict for the Seleucid Empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]"Diodotus, the governor of the thousand cities of Bactria (Latin: Theodotus, mille urbium Bactrianarum praefectus), defected and proclaimed himself king; all the other people of the Orient followed his example and seceded from the Macedonians." (Justin, XLI,4)[PARAGRAPH:2]The new kingdom, highly urbanized and considered as one of the richest of the Orient (opulentissimum illud mille urbium Bactrianum imperium "The extremely prosperous Bactrian empire of the thousand cities" Justin, XLI,1), was to further grow in power and engage into territorial expansion to the east and the west:[PARAGRAPH:1]"The Greeks who caused Bactria to revolt grew so powerful on account of the fertility of the country that they became masters, not only of Ariana, but also of India, as Apollodorus of Artemita says: and more tribes were subdued by them than by Alexander... Their cities were Bactra (also called Zariaspa, through which flows a river bearing the same name and emptying into the Oxus), and Darapsa, and several others. Among these was Eucratidia, which was named after its ruler." (Strabo, XI.XI.I)[PARAGRAPH:2]When the ruler of neighbouring Parthia, the former satrap and self-proclaimed king Andragoras, was defeated and killed by Arsaces, the rise of the Parthian Empire cut off the Greco-Bactrians from direct contact with the Greek world. Overland trade continued at a reduced rate, while sea trade between Greek Egypt and Bactria developed.[PARAGRAPH:2]Diodotus was succeeded by his son Diodotus II, who allied himself with the Parthian Arsaces in his fight against Seleucus II:[PARAGRAPH:1]"Soon after, relieved by the death of Diodotus, Arsaces made peace and concluded an alliance with his son, also by the name of Diodotus; some time later he fought against Seleucos who came to punish the rebels, and he prevailed: the Parthians celebrated this day as the one that marked the beginning of their freedom" (Justin, XLI,4)</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHALUKYANS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Chalukyan Kingdom</English>
		<French>Chalukyan Kingdom</French>
		<German>Chalukyan Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Chalukyan Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chalukyan Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHALUKYANS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Chalukyan Empire</English>
		<French>Chalukyan Empire</French>
		<German>Chalukyan Empire</German>
		<Italian>Chalukyan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chalukyan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHALUKYANS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Chalukyan Kingdom</English>
		<French>Chalukyan Kingdom</French>
		<German>Chalukyan Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Chalukyan Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chalukyan Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHALUKYANS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Chalukyan Kingdom</English>
		<French>Chalukyan Kingdom</French>
		<German>Chalukyan Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Chalukyan Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chalukyan Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHALUKYANS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Chalukyan Kingdom</English>
		<French>Chalukyan Kingdom</French>
		<German>Chalukyan Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Chalukyan Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chalukyan Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHALUKYANS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Chalukyan:Chalukyans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Chalukyan:Chalukyans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Chalukyan:Chalukyans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Chalukyan:Chalukyans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Chalukyan:Chalukyans</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHALUKYANS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]During the 6th and the 8th century, the empire that ruled the Deccan region of India was the Chalukya dynasty. After fading away for some time, they came back to power during the 10th century and ruled till 12th century. The Chalukyas are essentially divided into three broad categories: The Eastern Chalukyas, ruled from the Vengi region, the Western Chalukyas who ruled from the Badami region and the Later Western Chalukyas, which ruled from Kalyani region.[NEWLINE][TAB]The most famous rulers in the empire of the Chalukyas were Pulakesin I and Pulakesin II. The ruler Pulakesin II is said to have defeated emperor Harshavardhana in a battle on the banks of the River Narmada. He also waged a battle against Mahendravarman, the Pallava ruler and conquered him and his kingdom.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Chalukya dynasty is famous for developing and encouraging art and architecture during its era. The rulers of the Chalukya dynasty were great enthusiasts of art. This is evident from the fact that they built many temples near the region of Badami. A famous example of their architecture is the Virupaksha Temple in Karnataka. The sculptures that adorn the temples are beautifully carved and sculpted and represent scenes from the famous epic Ramayana. Some of the paintings at Ajanta and Ellora cave temples are considered to belong to this period.[PARAGRAPH:2]Pulakesin II was an admirer of art and always encouraged any art form to flourish in his kingdom. He was also fond of literature and encouraged poetry to flourish in his kingdom. The three famous poets of Kannada literature Adikavi Pampa, Sri Ponna and Ranna were from this era. Pulakesin was an able administrator and his subjects were devoted to him. Though he was Hindu by religion Pulakesin was tolerant towards Buddhism as well as Jainism. He built many monasteries in his kingdom that provided shelter to almost 5000 monks. The Chalukya kingdom was truly flourishing till it declined after the 12th century.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TOCHARIANS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Tocharian Kingdom</English>
		<French>Tocharian Kingdom</French>
		<German>Tocharian Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Tocharian Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tocharian Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TOCHARIANS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Tocharian Empire</English>
		<French>Tocharian Empire</French>
		<German>Tocharian Empire</German>
		<Italian>Tocharian Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tocharian Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TOCHARIANS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Tocharian Kingdom</English>
		<French>Tocharian Kingdom</French>
		<German>Tocharian Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Tocharian Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tocharian Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TOCHARIANS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Tocharian Kingdom</English>
		<French>Tocharian Kingdom</French>
		<German>Tocharian Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Tocharian Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tocharian Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TOCHARIANS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Tocharian Kingdom</English>
		<French>Tocharian Kingdom</French>
		<German>Tocharian Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Tocharian Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tocharian Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TOCHARIANS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Tocharian:Tocharians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Tocharian:Tocharians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Tocharian:Tocharians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Tocharian:Tocharians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Tocharian:Tocharians</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TOCHARIANS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The term Tocharian or Tokharian has a complex history. It is based on the ethnonym Tokharoi used by Greek historians. The first Greek mention of the Tocharians appeared in the 1st century BC, when Strabo presented them as a Scythian tribe, and explained that the Tocharians together with the Assianis, Passianis and Sakaraulis took part in the destruction of the Greco-Bactrian kingdom in the second half of the 2nd century BC. These Tocharians have frequently been identified with the Yuezhi and the later (and probably related) Kushan peoples. Many scholars believe the Yuezhi originally spoke a Tocharian language. However, the debate about the origins and original language(s) of the Yuezhi and the Kushan continues, and there is no general consensus. Regardless, it is generally accepted that the Tocharians were inhabitants of the Tarim Basin who spoke Tocharian, an Indo-European language, making them the easternmost speakers of Indo-European languages in antiquity.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Tarim mummies suggest that precursors of these easternmost speakers of an Indo-European language may have lived in the region of the Tarim Basin from around 1800 BC until finally being assimilated by Uyghur Turks in the 9th century AD. This is evidenced by both the mummies and Chinese writings.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Tocharians, living along the Silk Road, had contacts with the Chinese, Persians, Indian and Turkic tribes.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Tocharians who remained in the Tarim Basin adopted Buddhism, which, like their alphabet, came from northern India in the first century of the 1st millennium, through the proselytism of Kushan monks. The Kushans and the Tocharians seem to have played a part in the Silk Road transmission of Buddhism to China. Many apparently also practised some variant of Manichaeanism.[PARAGRAPH:2]Protected by the Taklamakan Desert from steppe nomads, the Tocharian culture survived past the 7th century. It was then, during the rise of the Islamic and Turkic Empires, that the Tocharians finally vanished from history and were assimilated into various other Central Asian peoples.</English>
		<French>.</French>
		<German>Der Begriff tocharisch hat eine eher komplizierte Geschichte. Er kommt von Tocharoi, den griechische Historiker benutzten. Die Griechen erwähnten die Tocharer zum ersten Mal im 1. Jahrhundert v.Chr., als Strabo sie als skytischen Stamm beschrieb, die zusammen mit anderen, kleinen Stämmen das griechisch-baktrische Königreich im 2. Jahrhundert v.Chr. eroberte. Das Volk, dass sich selbst Arshi oder Arshoi nannte, wird immer mit den Yuezhi und den später auftretenden Kuschana in Verbindung gebracht. Inwzischen ist man sich einig, dass die Yuezhi tatsächlich tocharisch, ein eigentständiges Glied der indogermanischen Sprachfamilie, gesprochen haben, bei den Kuschanen hingegen weiß man es nicht mit Sicherheit. Man weiß auch, dass die Tocharer im Tarimbecken, im heutigen Uiguristan im Westen Chinas angesiedelt waren. Damit war das Tocharische die indogermanische Sprache, die in der Antike am weitesten nach Osten verbreitet war.[PARAGRAPH:2]Im Tarimbecken wurden Mumien entdeckt, die darauf schließen lassen, dass die Tocharer von etwa 1800 v.Chr. bis ins 9. Jahrhundert n.Chr. dort siedelten, bis sie mehr und mehr von den eingefallenen Uighuren assimiliert wurden. Ähnliches behaupten chinesische Quellen.[PARAGRAPH:2]Da die Tocharer entlang der Seidenstraße gelebt haben, hatten im Lauf der Zeit Kontakte mit Chinesen, Persern, Indern und türkischen Stämmen. Wie ihr Alphabet, eine Silbenschrift, kam wie der Buddhismus aus Indien nach Tocharistan. Es gibt auch Theorien, dass sich nur durch die Handelsbeziehungen der Tocharer nach Indien und China, der Buddhismus in Letzterem ausgebreitet hat. Manche haben wohl auch eine Form des Manichäimus praktiziert.[PARAGRAPH:2]Geschützt durch die Taklamakan, hat es die tocharische Kultur geschafft, bis zum Aufstieg der türkischen und islamischen Reiche zu überleben, bis sie schließlich im Laufe der Zeit von zentralasiatischen Völkern assimiliert wurde.</German>
		<Italian>.</Italian>
		<Spanish>.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTINES_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Byzantine Empire</English>
		<French>Byzantine Empire</French>
		<German>Byzantine Empire</German>
		<Italian>Byzantine Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Byzantine Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTINES_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Eastern Rome</English>
		<French>Eastern Rome</French>
		<German>Eastern Rome</German>
		<Italian>Eastern Rome</Italian>
		<Spanish>Eastern Rome</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTINES_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Byzantine Empire</English>
		<French>Byzantine Empire</French>
		<German>Byzantine Empire</German>
		<Italian>Byzantine Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Byzantine Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTINES_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Byzantine Empire</English>
		<French>Byzantine Empire</French>
		<German>Byzantine Empire</German>
		<Italian>Byzantine Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Byzantine Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTIUM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Byzantine Empire, centered around the city of Constantinople, was the successor to the Roman Empire. At its height, the Byzantine Empire reached from Persia to Spain, controlling nearly all the territory that felt the lap of the Mediterranean's warm waters.[PARAGRAPH:1]When the Byzantine Empire began and the Roman Empire ceased is a point of much contention. Some historians place the beginning of the Byzantine Empire in 300 AD, when Constantine I moved the capital of the Roman Empire from Rome to a city called Byzantium (later know as Constantinople). Others place the birth of the Byzantine Empire at the end of the reign of Theodosius I, who at his death split the Roman Empire into the Western Empire, ruled from Rome, and the Eastern Empire, ruled from Constantinople.[PARAGRAPH:1]Regardless of historic debate, after the sacking of Rome in 476 AD, the Byzantine Empire was to become the foremost European nation in art, trade and stability - although not necessarily all at once. Taking the throne in 527 AD, Justinian I extended the grip of the Byzantine Empire from Constantinople to the furthest coasts of the Mediterranean Sea. However the Empire would not be able to enjoy the benefits of such territorial expansions for long, as Justinian's successor, Justin II, would begin a trend of placating the various enemies of the Empire - the Sassanid Persians, the Bulgars, and the Arabs, newly organized under Mohammed - with territory in exchange for peace.[PARAGRAPH:1]Territorial losses would continue to weaken the Byzantines until a new lineage of emperors, known as the Macedonian Emperors, arose to invigorate the Empire once again. Basil I founded the Macedonian line in 869. Under the Macedonians, the Byzantine Empire once again began to reach outwards, solidifying its hold on much of the territory neighboring Constantinople. Art flourished in their roughly two centuries of rule, as did the Greek Orthodox Church.[PARAGRAPH:1]The new millennium would be a painful one for Byzantium. Relations between the Roman Catholic Church and the Eastern Orthodox Church had been deteriorating for many years, and the conflict came to a head with the Great Schism (1054), which finally split the two religions. Militarily, increased assaults by the Seljuk Turks culminated in a resounding defeat for the Empire at the Battle of Manzikert, the Empire losing much of its freshly-gained holdings.[PARAGRAPH:1]But once again, the rise of a powerful new dynasty reversed the Empire's decline. This new dynasty, the Comnenius, sent the call to Western Europe for aid in fighting the Seljuk Turks. Pope Urban II, seeing a chance to reconquer the Holy Lands of Antioch and Jerusalem, as well as halt the squabbling of the European Kings, spread the word for the First Crusade.[PARAGRAPH:1]Through the Crusaders' efforts, the Byzantine Empire regained a portion of its lost territory. But the holy warriors of Western Europe became difficult to control, often threatening to assault the very Empire that had requested their aid. John II and Manuel I, the two most prestigious of the Comnenius emperors, held off the Crusaders and safeguarded the empire from a host of external foes, while ushering in a new era of Byzantine artistic and economic prowess.[PARAGRAPH:1]Manuel I Comnenius was the last great emperor of the Byzantines and the last Comneni. The Angeloi dynasty, successors to the Comneni, proved unable to halt the Empire's slow collapse. In 1204, the knights of the Fourth Crusade, summoned by a disposed Angeloi prince, sacked Constantinople and split the Byzantine Empire into three smaller kingdoms. Nicaea, one of these ex-Byzantine states, recaptured Constantinople years later, but all hopes of reviving the Byzantine Empire would be ended with the capture of the city by the Ottoman leader Mehmed II in 1461.</English>
		<French>vL'empire byzantin, centr&#233; autour de la ville de Constantinople, est le successeur de l'empire romain. A son apog&#233;e, l'empire byzantin s'&#233;tend de la Perse &#224; l'Espagne, contr&#244;lant presque tous les territoires qui bordent les eaux chaudes de la M&#233;diterran&#233;e.[PARAGRAPH:1]La question de savoir quand d&#233;bute l'empire byzantin et quand cesse l'empire romain fait l'objet de nombreux d&#233;bats. Certains historiens situent le d&#233;but de l'empire byzantin en 300 ap. J.C, quand Constantin Ier transf&#232;re la capitale de l'empire romain de Rome &#224; une ville nomm&#233;e Byzance (qui deviendra ensuite Constantinople). D'autres situent la naissance de l'empire byzantin &#224; la fin du r&#232;gne de Th&#233;odose Ier qui, &#224; sa mort, divise l'empire romain entre empire occidental (gouvern&#233; par Rome) et empire oriental (gouvern&#233; par Constantinople). Quoi qu'il en soit, apr&#232;s le sac de Rome en 476 ap . J.C. l'empire byzantin va devenir progressivement une nation stable, extr&#234;mement influente dans les domaines artistiques et commerciaux. Acc&#233;dant au tr&#244;ne en 527 ap. J.C., Justinien Ier &#233;tend l'empire byzantin de Constantinople jusqu'aux c&#244;tes les plus recul&#233;es de la mer M&#233;diterran&#233;e. Cependant, l'empire ne jouit pas longtemps des b&#233;n&#233;fices d'une telle expansion territoriale : le successeur de Justinien Ier, Justin II, entreprend d'apaiser les divers ennemis de l'empire (les Perses sassanides, les Bulgares et les Arabes, nouvellement organis&#233;s sous le commandement de Mohammed) en leur offrant des territoires en &#233;change de la paix.[PARAGRAPH:1]Affaiblissant les Byzantins, les pertes territoriales continuent jusqu'&#224; ce qu'une nouvelle lign&#233;e d'empereurs (les empereurs mac&#233;doniens) surgisse pour revigorer l'empire. Basile Ier fonde la lign&#233;e mac&#233;donienne en 869. Sous les Mac&#233;doniens, l'empire byzantin reprend son expansion, consolidant son emprise dans une grande partie du territoire voisin de Constantinople. L'art et l'Eglise orthodoxe grecque connaissent un grand essor au cours de leurs deux si&#232;cles de r&#232;gne.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le nouveau mill&#233;naire va s'av&#233;rer p&#233;nible pour Byzance. Les relations avec l'Eglise catholique romaine et l'Eglise orthodoxe orientale s'&#233;tant d&#233;t&#233;rior&#233;es depuis des ann&#233;es, le conflit &#233;clate &#224; l'occasion du Grand schisme (1054), qui divise les deux religions. Sur le plan militaire, l'intensification des assauts par les Turcs seldjoukides se solde par une d&#233;faite &#233;crasante pour l'empire lors de la bataille de Manzikert. L'empire y perd une grande partie de ses territoires fra&#238;chement conquis.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mais une nouvelle fois, l'apparition d'une nouvelle dynastie inverse le d&#233;clin de l'empire. Cette nouvelle dynastie, la dynastie des Comn&#232;nes, fait appel &#224; l'Europe occidentale pour les aider &#224; combattre les Turcs seldjoukides. Le pape Urbain II, voyant l&#224; une occasion de reconqu&#233;rir les terres sacr&#233;es d'Antioche et de J&#233;rusalem, ainsi que d'interrompre les querelles entre les rois europ&#233;ens, proclame la premi&#232;re croisade.[PARAGRAPH:1]Gr&#226;ce aux efforts des crois&#233;s, l'empire byzantin reprend une partie de ses territoires perdus. Mais les guerriers saints de l'Europe occidentale deviennent difficiles &#224; contr&#244;ler : ils menacent &#224; plusieurs reprises d'attaquer l'empire qui avait demand&#233; leur aide. Jean II et Manuel Ier, les deux plus prestigieux empereurs Comn&#232;nes, parviennent &#224; tenir les crois&#233;s &#224; distance et &#224; prot&#233;ger l'empire d'une foule d'ennemis &#233;trangers, tout en inaugurant une nouvelle &#232;re de prouesses artistiques et &#233;conomiques.[PARAGRAPH:1]Manuel Ier Comn&#232;ne est le dernier grand empereur des Byzantins et le dernier Comn&#232;ne. La dynastie des Anges, succ&#233;dant aux Comn&#232;nes, s'av&#232;re incapable d'arr&#234;ter le lent d&#233;clin de l'empire. En 1204, les chevaliers de la quatri&#232;me croisade, appel&#233;s par un prince d&#233;chu, pillent Constantinople et divisent l'empire byzantin en trois Etats. Nic&#233;e, l'un de ces empires anciennement byzantins, reconquiert Constantinople des ann&#233;es plus tard, mais tout espoir de faire rena&#238;tre l'empire byzantin s'envole lors de la capture de la ville par le chef ottoman Mehmet II en 1461.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Das Byzantinische Reich, in dessen Zentrum die Stadt Konstantinopel lag, war der Nachfolger des R&#246;mischen Reichs. Zu seiner Bl&#252;tezeit erstreckte sich das Byzantinische Reich von Persien nach Spanien und kontrollierte beinahe alle Gebiete, die von den warmen Wellen des Mittelmeers besp&#252;lt wurden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wann das Byzantinische Reich begann und wann das R&#246;mische Reich aufh&#246;rte, ist stark umstritten. Manche Historiker legen den Beginn des Byzantinischen Reiches auf das Jahr 300 n. Chr., als Konstantin I. die Hauptstadt des R&#246;mischen Reiches aus Rom in eine Stadt namens Byzanz verlegte (das sp&#228;tere Konstantinopel). Andere verlegen die Geburt des Byzantinischen Reiches an das Ende der Herrschaft Theodosius I., der bei seinem Tod das R&#246;mische Reich in ein von Rom aus regiertes Westreich und ein von Konstantinopel aus regiertes Ostreich aufteilte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Welches Ende die historische Debatte auch nehmen mag, nach der Pl&#252;nderung Roms im Jahr 476 n. Chr. wurde das Byzantinische Reich zur f&#252;hrenden europ&#228;ischen Nation in Sachen Kunst, Handel und Stabilit&#228;t - jedoch nicht unbedingt alles gleichzeitig. Justinian bestieg den Thron im Jahr 527 n. Chr. und erweiterte den Machtbereich des Byzantinischen Reiches von Konstantinopel aus auf die entlegensten K&#252;sten des Mittelmeers. Das Reich konnte sich jedoch nicht lange an den Vorteilen dieser Gebietserweiterungen erfreuen, da Justinians Nachfolger, Justin II., den sp&#228;teren Brauch begr&#252;ndete, verschiedene Feinde des Reiches zu bes&#228;nftigen - die Sassanidischen Perser, die Bulgaren und die unter Mohammed neu organisierten Araber - indem man jeweils Landbesitz gegen Frieden tauschte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Gebietsverluste schw&#228;chten die Byzantiner weiter, bis ein neues Kaisergeschlecht, bekannt als die Makedonischen Kaiser, sich erhob, um dem Reich neues Leben einzuhauchen. Basileos I. begr&#252;ndete im Jahr 869 die Makedonische Dynastie. Unter den Makedonen erweiterte sich das Byzantinische Reich erneut nach au&#223;en und festigte seinen Zugriff auf den Gro&#223;teil des Konstantinopel umgebenden Gebiets. In den ungef&#228;hr zweihundert Jahren ihrer Herrschaft erlebte die Kunst eine Bl&#252;tezeit, ebenso die Griechisch-Orthodoxe Kirche.[PARAGRAPH:1]Das neue Jahrtausend sollte f&#252;r Byzanz schmerzhaft sein. Die Beziehungen zwischen der R&#246;misch-Katholischen und der &#214;stlich-Orthodoxen Kirche hatten sich seit vielen Jahren verschlechtert und der Streit erreichte seinen H&#246;hepunkt mit dem Morgenl&#228;ndischen Schisma (1054), das die zwei Religionen endg&#252;ltig voneinander trennte. Auf der milit&#228;rischen Seite gipfelten die zunehmenden Angriffe der seldschukischen T&#252;rken in der Schlacht von Manzikert in einer vernichtenden Niederlage f&#252;r das Reich, das viel von seinen frisch eroberten Besitzungen wieder verlor.[PARAGRAPH:1]Jedoch kehrte erneut der Aufstieg einer m&#228;chtigen neuen Dynastie den Abstieg des Reiches um. Diese neue Dynastie, die Komnenen, sandte den Ruf mit der Bitte um Unterst&#252;tzung gegen die seldschukischen T&#252;rken nach Westeuropa. Papst Urban II., der darin die M&#246;glichkeit sah, das Heilige Land in Antiochia und Jerusalem zur&#252;ckzuerobern und gleichzeitig die inneren Querelen der europ&#228;ischen K&#246;nige zu beenden, rief daraufhin zum Ersten Kreuzzug auf.[PARAGRAPH:1]Durch die Anstrengungen der Kreuzfahrer gewann das Byzantinische Reich einen Teil seiner verlorenen Gebiete zur&#252;ck. Doch die heiligen Krieger Westeuropas wurden immer schwerer zu b&#228;ndigen und drohten oft, eben jenes Reich, das um ihre Hilfe gebeten hatte, anzugreifen. Johannes II. und Manuel I., die zwei bedeutendsten Komnenischen Kaiser, wehrten die Kreuzfahrer ab und sicherten das Reich vor einer F&#252;lle &#228;u&#223;erer Feinde, w&#228;hrend sie gleichzeitig eine neue Bl&#252;tezeit der Byzantinischen Kunst und der Wirtschaft einl&#228;uteten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Manuel I. Komnenos war der letzte gro&#223;e Kaiser der Byzantiner und der letzte Komnene. Die Dynastie der Angeloi, der Nachfolger der Komnenen, erwies sich als nicht in der Lage, den langsamen Zerfall des Reichs aufzuhalten. 1204 pl&#252;nderten die Ritter des Vierten Kreuzzugs auf Gehei&#223; eines abgesetzten Angeloi-Prinzen Konstantinopel und teilten das Byzantinische Reich auf drei kleinere K&#246;nigreiche auf. Nikaia, einer dieser ehemals byzantinischen Staaten, eroberte Jahre sp&#228;ter Konstantinopel zur&#252;ck, doch alle Hoffnung auf eine Neubelebung des Byzantinischen Reiches sollte 1453 mit der Eroberung der Stadt durch den osmanischen Herrscher Mehmet II. zu Ende gehen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]L'Impero Bizantino, costruito attorno alla citt&#224; di Costantinopoli, succedette all'Impero Romano. Al suo culmine l'Impero Bizantino si estendeva dalla Persia alla Spagna e controllava quasi tutto il territorio che si affacciava sulle calde acque del Mediterraneo.[PARAGRAPH:1]La questione su quando sia iniziato l'Impero Bizantino e quando sia finito quello Romano &#232; molto controversa. Alcuni storici pongono l'inizio dell'Impero Bizantino nel 300 d.C., quando Costantino spost&#242; la capitale dell'impero da Roma a una citt&#224; chiamata Bisanzio (pi&#249; tardi conosciuta come Costantinopoli). Altri pongono la nascita dell'Impero Bizantino alla fine del regno di Teodosio, che alla sua morte divise l'Impero Romano in Occidentale, comandato da Roma, e Orientale, governato da Costantinopoli.[PARAGRAPH:1]A prescindere dai dibattiti storici, dopo il sacco di Roma nel 476 d.C., l'Impero Bizantino divenne la nazione pi&#249; importante in Europa per l'arte, il commercio e la stabilit&#224;. Salito al trono nel 527 d.C., Giustiniano estese il dominio dell'Impero Bizantino da Costantinopoli alla costa pi&#249; lontana del Mar Mediterraneo. L'impero per&#242; non godette a lungo dei benefici di una tale espansione territoriale, visto che il successore di Giustiniano, Giustino II, inizi&#242; la tendenza a placare i diversi nemici dell'impero (i Persiani Sasanidi, i Bulgari e gli Arabi, di recente organizzatisi sotto Maometto) scambiando territori con la pace.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le perdite territoriali avrebbero continuato a indebolire i Bizantini fino a quando una nuova stirpe di imperatori, i Macedoni, sorse a rinvigorire ancora una volta l'impero. Basilio I fond&#242; la stirpe macedone nell'869 d.C.; sotto i Macedoni l'Impero Bizantino cominci&#242; ancora una volta a espandersi, consolidando il proprio dominio su gran parte del territorio attorno a Costantinopoli. Nei circa due secoli in cui regnarono i Macedoni fiorirono l'arte e la Chiesa greca ortodossa.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il nuovo millennio sarebbe stato doloroso per Bisanzio. Le relazioni tra la Chiesa Cattolica Romana e la Chiesa Orientale Ortodossa andavano peggiorando da molti anni, e il conflitto arriv&#242; al culmine con il Grande Scisma (1054), che divise le due religioni. Dal punto di vista militare, si andarono moltiplicando gli assalti da parte dei Turchi selgiuchidi, che culminarono in una cocente sconfitta nella Battaglia di Manzikert, per cui l'impero perse gran parte delle terre da poco conquistate.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ma ancora una volta, l'ascesa di una nuova potente dinastia rovesci&#242; le sorti dell'impero. La nuova dinastia, quella dei Comneni, invi&#242; una richiesta di aiuto all'Europa occidentale per combattere i Turchi selgiuchidi. Il papa Urbano II intravide la possibilit&#224; di riconquistare le Sacre Terre di Antiochia e Gerusalemme, e di fermare gli scontri dei re europei e istitu&#236; cos&#236; la Prima Crociata.[PARAGRAPH:1]Grazie agli sforzi dei crociati, l'Impero Bizantino riacquist&#242; una parte dei territori perduti. Ma i guerrieri religiosi dell'Europa occidentale divennero difficili da controllare e spesso minacciavano di attaccare lo stesso impero che aveva richiesto il loro aiuto. Giovanni II e Manuele I, i due pi&#249; importanti imperatori Comneni, tennero a bada i crociati e salvaguardarono l'impero da molti nemici, mentre introducevano una nuova era di valore artistico ed economico per Bisanzio.[PARAGRAPH:1]Manuele I Comneno fu l'ultimo grande imperatore bizantino e l'ultimo dei Comneni. La dinastia degli Angelo, successa a quella dei Comneni, si dimostr&#242; incapace di fermare il lento collasso dell'impero. Nel 1204 i cavalieri della Quarta Crociata, richiamati da un principe Angelo deposto, saccheggiarono Costantinopoli e divisero l'Impero Bizantino in tre regni pi&#249; piccoli. Quello di Nicea riconquist&#242; Costantinopoli anni pi&#249; tardi, ma tutte le speranze di far rivivere l'Impero Bizantino terminarono con la cattura della citt&#224; da parte del sultano Ottomano Mehmed II, nel 1461.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El Imperio Bizantino, construido alrededor de la ciudad de Constantinopla, fue el sucesor del Imperio Romano. En su apogeo, el imperio se extend&#237;a desde Persia hasta Espa&#241;a, y controlaba casi todos los territorios ba&#241;ados por las c&#225;lidas aguas del Mediterr&#225;neo.[PARAGRAPH:1]El momento exacto en el que nace el Imperio Bizantino y desaparece el Imperio Romano es un tema muy controvertido. Algunos historiadores sit&#250;an el nacimiento del bizantino en el a&#241;o 300 d. C., cuando Constantino I traslad&#243; la capital del Imperio Romano a una ciudad llamada Bizancio(conocida m&#225;s adelante como Constantinopla). Para otros, el nacimiento del imperio se produjo al finalizar el reinado de Teodosio I, cuando se dividi&#243; el Imperio Romano en dos mitades, la occidental gobernada desde Roma, y la oriental, desde Constantinopla.[PARAGRAPH:1]Al margen de este debate hist&#243;rico, tras el saqueo de Roma (476 d. C.), el Imperio Bizantino se vio catapultado al primer lugar de Europa en los &#225;mbitos del arte, el comercio y la estabilidad... aunque no siempre al mismo tiempo. Tras subir al trono en el a&#241;o 527 d. C., Justiniano I extendi&#243; la autoridad del imperio desde Constantinopla hasta los &#250;ltimos confines del Mediterr&#225;neo. Sin embargo, el imperio no podr&#237;a disfrutar durante mucho tiempo de los beneficios de esta expansi&#243;n, puesto que el sucesor de Justiniano, Justino II, inici&#243; una pol&#237;tica de apaciguamiento con los diferentes enemigos de Bizancio (la Persia sas&#225;nida, los b&#250;lgaros, y los &#225;rabes, unidos bajo una misma bandera por Mahoma) comprando su indulgencia con tierras.[PARAGRAPH:1]Las p&#233;rdidas territoriales continuar&#237;an debilitando a los bizantinos hasta que el advenimiento de una nueva dinast&#237;a, llamada maced&#243;nica, volviera a vigorizar el imperio. Basilio I fund&#243; esta dinast&#237;a en el 869. Bajo los emperadores maced&#243;nicos, el Imperio Bizantino volvi&#243; a expandirse y consolid&#243; su autoridad sobre la mayor parte de los territorios que rodeaban Constantinopla. Durante los casi dos siglos que dur&#243; esta dinast&#237;a, florecieron el arte y la Iglesia ortodoxa griega.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sin embargo, el nuevo milenio ser&#237;a duro para Bizancio. Las relaciones entre la Iglesia cat&#243;lica romana y la Iglesia ortodoxa oriental llevaban deterior&#225;ndose muchos a&#241;os, y el conflicto lleg&#243; a su punto &#225;lgido en el Gran Cisma(1054), que dividi&#243; definitivamente ambas religiones. Desde el punto de vista militar, el aumento de los ataques de los turcos sely&#250;cidas culmin&#243; en la sonora derrota del imperio en la batalla de Manzikert, donde Bizancio perdi&#243; gran parte de las tierras que acababa de ganar.[PARAGRAPH:1]Pero, una vez m&#225;s, la aparici&#243;n de una nueva dinast&#237;a volvi&#243; a revertir el declive del imperio. Esta dinast&#237;a, la de los Comneno, recurri&#243; a Europa occidental en busca de ayuda contra los turcos sely&#250;cidas. El papa Urbano II, viendo la ocasi&#243;n de reconquistar Tierra Santa (Antioqu&#237;a y Jerusal&#233;n) y de poner fin a los mezquinos enfrentamientos entre los monarcas de Europa, empez&#243; a predicar la Primera Cruzada.[PARAGRAPH:1]Gracias a los esfuerzos de los cruzados, s, el Imperio Bizantino pudo recuperar parte de sus territorios. Pero los guerreros de Europa occidental eran muy dif&#237;ciles de controlar, y en muchas ocasiones amenazaron con atacar el mismo imperio que hab&#237;a solicitado su ayuda. Juan II y Manuel I, los dos Comneno m&#225;s prestigiosos, mantuvieron a raya a los cruzados y defendieron al imperio de un sinf&#237;n de enemigos extranjeros, al tiempo que impulsaban una nueva era de gloria art&#237;stica y desarrollo econ&#243;mico.[PARAGRAPH:1]Manuel I Comneno fue el &#250;ltimo gran emperador de Bizancio, as&#237; como el &#250;ltimo de los miembros de su dinast&#237;a. La dinast&#237;a de los Angelo, sucesores de los Comneno, fue incapaz de frenar el lento declive del imperio. En 1204, los caballeros de la Cuarta Cruzada, llamados por un depuesto pr&#237;ncipe Angelo, saquearon Constantinopla y dividieron el imperio en reinos menores. Nicea, uno de estos estados, recuper&#243; Constantinopla a&#241;os despu&#233;s, pero todas las esperanzas de reverdecer los laureles del imperio se desmoronaron tras la ca&#237;da de la ciudad en manos del sult&#225;n otomano Mehmet II en 1461.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOKTURKS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Gokturk Qaghanate</English>
		<French>Gokturk Qaghanate</French>
		<German>Gokturk Qaghanate</German>
		<Italian>Gokturk Qaghanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gokturk Qaghanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOKTURKS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Gokturk Qaghanate</English>
		<French>Gokturk Qaghanate</French>
		<German>Gokturk Qaghanate</German>
		<Italian>Gokturk Qaghanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gokturk Qaghanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOKTURKS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Gokturk</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Song:Song:Song</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter:Neuter:Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOKTURKS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Gokturk Qaghanate</English>
		<French>Gokturk Qaghanate</French>
		<German>Gokturk Qaghanate</German>
		<Italian>Gokturk Qaghanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gokturk Qaghanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOKTURKS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Gokturk Qaghanate</English>
		<French>Gokturk Qaghanate</French>
		<German>Gokturk Qaghanate</German>
		<Italian>Gokturk Qaghanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gokturk Qaghanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOKTURKS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Gokturks, who originated from the Ashina tribe who were natives of today's Xiang Uygur, were the first Turkic tribe to use the name "Turk" as a political name. The Gokturks established the first known Turkic state around 552 under the leadership of Bumin/Tuman Khan/Khaghan (died 552) and his sons, and expanded rapidly to rule wide territories in Central Asia.[PARAGRAPH:2]With the collapse of Hunnish power in Asia, leadership of the Turks was taken over by the Gokturks, who inherited their traditions and administrative experience. From 552 to 745, Gokturkish leadership bound together the nomadic Turkish tribes into an empire, which finally fell to internal conflicts and to defeats by China. The kingdom received missionaries from the Buddhists, Manicheans, and Nestorian Christians, but remained primarily shamanistic. The great difference between the Gokturkish empire and its Hunnish predecessor was that the Gokturks' temporary Khans (lords) were subordinate to a sovereign authority that was left in the hands of a dynasty of tribal chiefs.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 552, Tuman defeated the last Rouran Khan, A-na-kuei . Tuman's brother Istami (died 576) collaborated with the Persian Sassanids to defeat and destroy the White Huns, which drove the Avars into Europe. Both rival state in north China paid large tributes to the Gokturks from 581. This first Gokturkish empire split in two after the death of the last of Tuman's sons (circa 584). These were successfully played off against each other by Sui and Tang Dynasty China. The Eastern Khanate became formally subordinate to the Chinese Emperor; the Western Khan of that time was Istami's son Tardu, who almost succeeded in reuniting the Gokturkish empire around 600. However, Chinese diplomacy incited a revolt of his vassals, and Tardu's life and reign were cut short in 603. New attacks on China by the Turks of the Eastern Khanate failed, and its Khan Hsien was brought down by a revolt of his vassals (626-630), instigated by Emperor Tanng Taizong, who took him prisoner. The Western Khan Tung Sche-hu was murdered in 630 despite strong support by the Byzantine Empire against the Persians. By 659 the Tang Emperor of China could claim to rule the entire Silk Road as far as Po-sse (Persia). The Turks now carried Chinese titles and fought by their side in their wars.[PARAGRAPH:2]Nonetheless, Ilteris Sad and his brother Bakcor Qapagan Khan managed to found a new realm of "wild" Turks, which in a series of wars from 681 onward gained control of the steppes beyond the Great Wall of China, extending by 705 to threaten Arab control of Transoxiana. Their power centered at the Changai Mountains. The son of Ilteris, Bilge, was also a strong leader, but at his death in 734, the empire declined. They ultimately fell to a series of internal crises and renewed Chinese campaigns. After Kutluk (Ko-lo) Khan 's military victory in 744, the successors to the Gokturks became their more China-friendly junior partners, known as the Uighurs.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHAZARS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Khazar Qaghanate</English>
		<French>Khazar Qaghanate</French>
		<German>Khazar Qaghanate</German>
		<Italian>Khazar Qaghanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Khazar Qaghanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHAZARS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Khazar Qaghanate</English>
		<French>Khazar Qaghanate</French>
		<German>Khazar Qaghanate</German>
		<Italian>Khazar Qaghanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Khazar Qaghanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHAZARS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Khazar</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Song:Song:Song</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter:Neuter:Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHAZARS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Khazar Qaghanate</English>
		<French>Khazar Qaghanate</French>
		<German>Khazar Qaghanate</German>
		<Italian>Khazar Qaghanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Khazar Qaghanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHAZARS_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Khazar Qaghanate</English>
		<French>Khazar Qaghanate</French>
		<German>Khazar Qaghanate</German>
		<Italian>Khazar Qaghanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Khazar Qaghanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHAZARS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In the seventh century, in the region between the Black Sea and the Caspian Sea, a free Jewish state was established. Its people were a mix of Khazar Turks, whom were part of the Gok Turkic Migration, the Huns, the Bulgars, and the Caucasians. The story of the Khazar Empire begins when the infant-empire Khagan Bulan heard from an Arab mullah, a Christian priest, and a Jewish rabbi on the reasons why Khazaria should adopt each of their religions. After much thought, Bulan decided to adopt the Jewish faith. Nowhere else in the world, has a non-Jewish nation undergone such a conversion as Bulan faced the Muslim expansion of the South, and the Christian expansion to the west. A few wars between the Khazars and Arabs prevented Islam from spreading across all of eastern Europe at a time when Islam was attracting many followers. It also became a place of safety and refuge for the Jewish people, as the rest of the world were persecuted.[PARAGRAPH:2]Khazar power begins at about 650 BC, when the Turkic kingdom formed after the breakup of the Gok Turks and the collapse of their rival the Avars. Khazar culture was molded around the Gok Turks, with the Khagan holding supreme power and the Khagan Bek being the military power. The Khazars used a runic script that originated in Mongolia as their language. Most of the Turkish groups of the period used the same type of language.[PARAGRAPH:2]Arab scholars of the time provide the most knowledge of the Khazars. An 11th century Muslim chronicler elaborated on the man who brought the Jewish faith to Khazaria. His writings explain how a single Khazar Jew, who had a high military rank, converted all the other Khazars to Judaism. The chronicler went on to explain how the Khazars observed Judaism. Obadiah, one of Bulan's descendants, consolidated the newly-adopted religion with the construction of synogogues and invited Jewish scholars to confince other doubters among the aristocracy. However, it was not only the military elite and the nobles who were converted. The common people embraced the new religion with open arms. Pagan shamanism was the Khazar's original religion, remained in place as were other religions. Incredibely, a seven-strong Supreme Court with representatives of all faiths was established to ensure fair hearing for all people. Such religious tolerance was unheard of.[PARAGRAPH:2]Although the Khazars were nomadiv people, the conversion to Judaism rapidly opted for a more settled existance with Khazaria prospering from farming, the production of goods, and trading. Khazaria also did play a role in the defeat of Persia in the 7th century, allying it self with the Turks and the Byzantines. There wer also a series of wars in the 8th centurey against the Arabs that established Khazaria's souther borders at the Caucasus Mountains. However, the Khazars are associated with a period of peace along the steppe because they were more concerned with commerce than warfare.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Khazars were very coopertive with their neighbors such that the Byzantines build a wall for them at the city of Sarkel along the Don River. Byzantine emporors Justinian II and Constantine V both took a Khazar wife. Khazar also brought many new technologies in since Jews from all over the world came in search of a Jewish beacon. All this helped to strengthen Khazaria and make it into a cosmopolitan and a progressive civilization.[PARAGRAPH:2]At the empires greatest extent at 850, it stretched from the Black to the Caspian sea. The waterways were trading links and the Khazars built the city of Kiev, later becoming its capital. The most enduring of Khazar capitals was Itil. It had a trading post, an administrative center, and religious hearland for the Jews. It also had an Islamic mosque to serve the Muslim population. Khazar power ended under Svyatoslav, the ruler of Kiev. Khazaria was then taken over by the neighboring Pechenegs, Oghuz, and Byzantine peoples. Khazar traders faced difficult circumstances during these times and all mention of them ends. The Penchenegs who had much of Khazar land did not focus on trade, and distrupted the trade with Eastern Europe.</English>
		<French>Au septième siècle, dans la région entre la Mer Noire et la mer caspienne, un état juif libre a été établi. Ses personnes étaient un mélange des Turcs de Khazar, qui faisaient partie de la migration de Gok Turkic, les huns, le Bulgars, et les Caucasiens. L'histoire de l'empire de Khazar commence quand l'enfant en bas âge-empire Khagan Bulan reçu des nouvelles un mollah arabe, un prêtre chrétien, et un rabbin juif sur les raisons pour lesquelles Khazaria devrait adopter chacune de leurs religions. Après beaucoup de pensée, Bulan a décidé d'adopter la foi juive. Nulle part autrement dans le monde, a une nation non-Juive subie une telle conversion que Bulan a fait face à l'expansion musulmane des sud, et l'expansion chrétienne à l'ouest. Quelques guerres entre le Khazars et les Arabes ont empêché l'Islam d'écarter à travers toute l'Europe de l'Est à un moment où l'Islam attirait beaucoup de disciples. C'est également devenu un endroit de la sûreté et refuge pour les personnes juives, pendant que le reste du monde étaient persécutés.[PARAGRAPH:2]La puissance de Khazar commence à environ 650 AVANT JÉSUS CHRIST, quand le royaume de Turkic a formé après la dissolution des Turcs de Gok et l'effondrement de leur rival l'Avars. La culture de Khazar a été moulée autour des Turcs de Gok, avec le Khagan tenant la puissance suprême et le Khagan Bek étant la puissance militaire. Le Khazars a employé un manuscrit runic qui a provenu de la Mongolie en tant que leur langue. La plupart des groupes turcs de la période ont employé le même type de langue.[PARAGRAPH:2]Les disciples arabes du temps fournissent la plupart de connaissance du Khazars. Un chroniqueur musulman du 11ème siècle a élaboré sur l'homme qui a apporté la foi juive à Khazaria. Ses écritures expliquent comment un juif simple de Khazar, qui a eu un rang élevé de militaires, a converti tout autre Khazars en judaïsme. Le chroniqueur a continué pour expliquer comment le Khazars a observé le judaïsme. Obadiah, un des descendants de Bulan, a consolidé la religion nouveau-adoptée avec la construction des synogogues et a invité les disciples juifs au confince d'autres douteurs parmi l'aristocratie. Cependant, c'était non seulement l'élite militaire et les nobles qui ont été convertis. Les gens du commun ont embrassé la nouvelle religion avec les bras ouverts. Le shamanism païen était la religion originale du Khazar, restée en place de même que d'autres religions. Incredibely, une cour suprême sept-forte avec des représentants de toutes les fois a été établi pour assurer l'audition juste pour toutes les personnes. Une telle tolérance religieuse était inconnue.[PARAGRAPH:2]Bien que le Khazars aient été des personnes de nomadiv, la conversion en judaïsme a rapidement opté pour un existance plus arrangé avec Khazaria prospérant de l'affermage, de la production des marchandises, et du commerce. Khazaria également a joué un rôle dans la défaite de Perse au 7ème siècle, l'alliant individu avec les Turcs et le Byzantines. Là wer également qu'une série de guerres dans le 8ème centurey contre les Arabes qui ont établi le souther de Khazaria encadre aux montagnes de Caucase. Cependant, le Khazars sont associés à une période de paix le long de la steppe parce qu'elles davantage ont été concernées par le commerce que la guerre.[PARAGRAPH:2]Le Khazars étaient très coopertive avec leurs voisins tels que la construction de Byzantines un mur pour eux à la ville de Sarkel le long du fleuve de Don. Les emporors bizantins Justinian II et Constantine V tous les deux ont pris une épouse de Khazar. Khazar également a apporté beaucoup de nouvelles technologies dedans puisque les juifs de sont partout dans le monde venus à la recherche d'une balise juive. Tout ceci a aidé à renforcer Khazaria et à le transformer en une civilisation cosmopolite et progressive.[PARAGRAPH:2]À la plus grande ampleur d'empires à 850, il s'est étendu du noir à la mer caspienne. Les voies d'eau commerçaient des liens et le Khazars a construit la ville de Kiev, devenant plus tard son capital. La résistance des capitaux de Khazar était Itil. Elle a eu un comptoir commercial, un centre administratif, et le hearland religieux pour les juifs. Elle a également eu une mosquée islamique pour servir la population musulmane. La puissance de Khazar a fini sous Svyatoslav, la règle de Kiev. Khazaria a été alors succédé par le Pechenegs voisin, l'Oghuz, et les peuples bizantins. Les commerçants de Khazar ont fait face à des circonstances difficiles pendant ces périodes et toute la mention de elles des extrémités. Le Penchenegs qui a eu beaucoup de terre de Khazar ne s'est pas concentré sur le commerce, et distrupted le commerce avec l'Europe de l'Est.</French>
		<German>Im 7. Jahrhundert in der Region zwischen dem Schwarzen Meer und dem kaspischen Meer, wurde ein freier jüdischer Zustand hergestellt. Seine Leute waren eine Mischung der Khazar Türken, die ein Teil der Gok Turkic Migration, die Hunnen, das Bulgars und die Kaukasier waren. Die Geschichte des Khazar Reiches fängt wenn das Kindreich Khagan Bulan an, das von einem arabischen Mulla, von einem christlichen Priester und von einem jüdischen Rabbiner auf den Gründen gehört wird, warum Khazaria jede ihrer Religionen annehmen sollte. Nach vielem Gedanken entschied Bulan, den jüdischen Glauben anzunehmen. Nirgendwo sonst in der Welt, hat eine nicht-Jüdische Nation, die solch einer Umwandlung durchgemacht wird, der Bulan die moslemische Expansion des Südens gegenüberstellte, und der christlichen Expansion zum Westen. Einige Kriege zwischen dem Khazars und den Arabern verhinderten Islam am Verbreiten über den ganzen Osteuropa, zu einer Zeit als Islam viele Nachfolger anzog. Es wurde auch ein Ort der Sicherheit und Schutz für die jüdischen Leute, während der Rest der Welt verfolgt wurden.[PARAGRAPH:2]Khazar Energie fängt an ungefähr 650 BC an, als das Turkic Königreich nach dem Auseinanderbrechen der Gok Türken und dem Einsturz ihres Rivalen das Avars sich bildete. Khazar Kultur wurde um die Gok Türken geformt, wenn das Khagan Oberste Energie hält und dem Khagan Bek, das die militärische Energie ist. Das Khazars benutzte einen runic Index, der in Mongolei als ihre Sprache entstand. Die meisten türkischen Gruppen der Periode benutzten die gleiche Art der Sprache.[PARAGRAPH:2]Arabische Gelehrte der Zeit stellen das meiste Wissen des Khazars zur Verfügung. Ein moslemischer Chronist des 11. Jahrhunderts arbeitete auf dem Mann aus, der Khazaria den jüdischen Glauben holte. Seine Schreiben erklären, wie ein einzelner Khazar Jude, der einen hohen Militärrank hatte, alles andere Khazars in Judentum umwandelte. Der Chronist fuhr fort, zu erklären, wie das Khazars Judentum beobachtete. Obadiah, einer von Nachkommen Bulans, vereinigte die neu-angenommene Religion mit dem Aufbau von synogogues und lud jüdische Gelehrte zum confince andere Zweifler unter der Aristokratie ein. Jedoch war es nicht nur die militärische Auslese und die Adligen, die umgewandelt wurden. Die gewöhnlichen Leute umfaßten die neue Religion mit den geöffneten Armen. Heidnisches shamanism war die des Khazars ursprüngliche Religion, an der richtigen Stelle geblieben, wie andere Religionen. Incredibely, ein sieben-starkes Höchstes Gericht mit Repräsentanten aller Glauben wurde hergestellt, um angemessene Hörfähigkeit für alle Leute sicherzustellen. Solche fromme Toleranz war von ungehört.[PARAGRAPH:2]Obgleich das Khazars nomadiv Leute waren, entschied die Umwandlung zum Judentum schnell für ein vereinbartes existance mit Khazaria, das vom Bewirtschaften, von der Produktion von Waren und vom Handeln sich erweitert. Khazaria auch spielte eine Rolle in der Niederlage von Persien im 7. Jahrhundert und verband sie Selbst mit den Türken und dem Byzantines. Dort wer, auch, das eine Reihe Kriege im 8. centurey gegen die Araber, die souther Khazarias herstellten, an den Kaukasus Bergen einfaßt. Jedoch sind das Khazars mit einer Periode des Friedens entlang der Steppe verbunden, weil sie mehr mit Handel als Kriegsführung betroffen wurden.[PARAGRAPH:2]Das Khazars waren mit ihren Nachbarn so daß der Byzantines Bau eine Wand für sie an der Stadt von Sarkel entlang dem anziehenfluß sehr coopertive. Byzantinische emporors Justinian II und Constantine V beide nahmen eine Khazar Frau. Khazar holte auch viele neue Technologien innen, da Juden von auf der ganzen Erde auf der Suche nach einem jüdischen Leuchtfeuer kamen. Alles half dieses, Khazaria zu verstärken und es in eine Welt- und progressive Zivilisation zu bilden.[PARAGRAPH:2]Am größten Umfang der Reiche bei 850, dehnte er vom Schwarzen zum kaspischen Meer aus. Die Wassern-Strasse handelten Verbindungen und das Khazars errichtete die Stadt von Kiew und später wurde sein Kapital. Das Aushalten der Khazar Kapitalien war Itil. Es hatte einen handelnden Pfosten, eine Verwaltungsstelle und frommes hearland für die Juden. Es hatte auch eine islamische Moschee, zum der moslemischen Bevölkerung zu dienen. Khazar Energie beendete unter Svyatoslav, die Lehre von Kiew. Khazaria wurde dann vom benachbarten Pechenegs, vom Oghuz und von den byzantinischen Völkern übernommen. Khazar Händler stellten schwierige Umstände während dieser Zeiten und aller Erwähnung von ihnen Enden gegenüber. Das Penchenegs, das viel von Khazar Land hatte, konzentrierte nicht auf Handel und distrupted den Handel mit Osteuropa.</German>
		<Italian>Nel settimo secolo, nella regione fra il Mar Nero ed il mare caspico, un ebreo libero dichiara è stato stabilito. La relativa gente era una miscela dei Turchi di Khazar, quale facevano parte dell'espansione di Gok Turkic, i Huns, il Bulgars ed i Caucasians. La storia dell'impero di Khazar comincia quando l'infante-impero Khagan Bulan ascoltato di un mullah arabo, di un priest cristiano e di un rabbi ebreo sulle ragioni per le quali Khazaria dovrebbe adottare ciascuna delle loro religioni. Dopo molto pensiero, Bulan ha deciso adottare la fede ebrea. In nessun posto altrimenti nel mondo, ha una nazione non-Ebrea subita una tal conversione come Bulan ha affrontato l'espansione musulmana del sud e l'espansione cristiana all'ovest. Alcune guerre fra il Khazars e gli arabi hanno impedito l'Islam la diffusione attraverso tutta l'Europa Orientale in un momento in cui l'Islam stava attraendo molti seguicamme. Inoltre si è trasformato in in un posto di sicurezza ed in rifugio per la gente ebrea, mentre il resto del mondo persecuted.[PARAGRAPH:2]L'alimentazione di Khazar comincia BC a circa 650, quando il regno di Turkic ha formato dopo il disfacimento dei Turchi di Gok ed il crollo del loro rivale il Avars. La coltura di Khazar è stata modellata intorno ai Turchi di Gok, con l'alimentazione suprema della tenuta di Khagan e il Khagan Bek che è l'alimentazione militare. Il Khazars ha usato uno scritto runic che ha provenuto in Mongolia come loro lingua. La maggior parte dei gruppi turchi del periodo hanno usato lo stesso tipo di lingua.[PARAGRAPH:2]Gli eruditi arabi del tempo forniscono la maggior parte della conoscenza del Khazars. Un chronicler musulmano di undicesimo secolo ha elaborato sull'uomo che ha portato la fede ebrea a Khazaria. Le sue scritture spiegano come un singolo ebreo di Khazar, che ha avuto un alto Rank dei militari, ha convertito tutto il altro Khazars in Judaism. Il chronicler ha continuato a spiegare come il Khazars ha osservato il Judaism. Obadiah, uno dei discendenti del Bulan, ha consolidato la religione nuovo-adottata con la costruzione degli synogogues ed ha invitato gli eruditi ebrei al confince altri doubters fra il aristocracy. Tuttavia, era non solo l'elite militare ed i nobili che sono stati convertiti. La gente comune ha abbracciato la nuova religione con le armi aperte. Lo shamanism Pagan era la religione originale del Khazar, rimasta sul posto come erano altre religioni. Incredibely, una Corte suprema sette-forte con i rappresentanti di tutta la fede è stato stabilito per accertare l'udienza giusta per tutta la gente. Tale tolleranza religiosa era unheard di.[PARAGRAPH:2]Anche se il Khazars era la gente del nomadiv, la conversione a Judaism ha optato velocemente per un existance depositato con Khazaria che prospera dall'agricoltura, dalla produzione delle merci e dal commercio. Khazaria inoltre ha svolto un ruolo nella sconfitta della Persia nel settimo secolo, alleante lo auto con i Turchi e il Byzantines. Là wer inoltre che una serie di guerre nell'ottavo centurey contro gli arabi che hanno stabilito il souther del Khazaria borders alle montagne del Caucaso. Tuttavia, il Khazars è associato con un periodo di pace lungo la steppa perché di più sono state interessate del commercio che la guerra.[PARAGRAPH:2]Il Khazars era molto coopertive con i loro vicini tali che la configurazione di Byzantines una parete per loro alla città di Sarkel lungo il fiume di indoss. I emporors Byzantine Justinian II e Constantine V entrambi hanno preso una moglie di Khazar. Khazar inoltre ha portato molte nuove tecnologie dentro poiché gli ebrei da dappertutto sono venuto alla ricerca di un falò ebreo. Tutto questo ha contribuito a rinforzare Khazaria e trasformarlo una civilizzazione cosmopolita e progressiva.[PARAGRAPH:2]Al limite più grande degli imperi a 850, ha allungato dal nero al mare caspico. I canali navigabili stavano commerciando i collegamenti e il Khazars ha costruito la città di Kiev, successivamente trasformantesi nel relativo capitale. Resistere dei capitali di Khazar era Itil. Ha avuto un alberino di commercio, un centro amministrativo e hearland religioso per gli ebrei. Inoltre ha avuto un mosque islamico per servire la popolazione musulmana. L'alimentazione di Khazar si è conclusa sotto Svyatoslav, il righello di Kiev. Khazaria allora è stato rilevato dal Pechenegs vicino, dal Oghuz e dalla gente Byzantine. I commercianti di Khazar hanno affrontato le circostanze difficili durante questi periodi e tutta la menzione di loro estremità. Il Penchenegs che ha avuto molta della terra di Khazar non ha messo a fuoco su commercio e distrupted il commercio con l'Europa Orientale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>En el séptimo siglo, en la región entre el Mar Negro y el mar caspio, un estado judío libre fue establecido. Su gente era una mezcla de los turcos de Khazar, que eran parte de la migración de Gok Turkic, los Huns, el Bulgars, y los caucásicos. La historia del imperio de Khazar comienza cuando el infante-imperio Khagan Bulan recibido noticias un mullah árabe, un sacerdote cristiano, y un rabino judío en las razones por las que Khazaria debe adoptar cada uno de sus religiones. Después de mucho pensamiento, Bulan decidía a adoptar la fe judía. En ninguna parte en el mundo, tiene una nación no-Judía experimentada una conversión tal que Bulan hizo frente a la extensión musulmana del sur, y la extensión cristiana al oeste. Algunas guerras entre el Khazars y los árabes evitaron que el Islam se separara a través de toda la Europa Oriental en un momento en que el Islam atraía muchos seguidores. También se convirtió en un lugar de la seguridad y refugio para la gente judía, mientras que el resto del mundo fue perseguido.[PARAGRAPH:2]La energía de Khazar comienza aproximadamente 650 A.C., cuando el reino de Turkic formó después de la desintegración de los turcos de Gok y del derrumbamiento de su rival el Avars. La cultura de Khazar fue moldeada alrededor de los turcos de Gok, con el Khagan llevando a cabo energía suprema y el Khagan Bek que era la energía militar. El Khazars utilizó una escritura runic que originó en Mongolia como su lengua. La mayor parte de los grupos turcos del período utilizaron el mismo tipo de lengua.[PARAGRAPH:2]Los eruditos árabes del tiempo proporcionan la mayoría del conocimiento del Khazars. Un cronista musulmán del 11mo siglo elaboró en el hombre que trajo la fe judía a Khazaria. Sus escrituras explican cómo un solo judío de Khazar, que tenía una alta fila de los militares, convirtió todo el otro Khazars al judaísmo. El cronista se encendió explicar cómo el Khazars observó judaísmo. Obadiah, uno de los descendientes de Bulan, consolidó la religión nuevo-adoptada con la construcción de synogogues e invitó a eruditos judíos al confince otros doubters entre la aristocracia. Sin embargo, era no sólo la élite militar y los nobles que fueron convertidos. El pueblo abrazó la nueva religión con los brazos abiertos. El shamanism Pagan era la religión original del Khazar, permanecida en lugar al igual que otras religiones. Incredibely, un Tribunal Supremo siete-fuerte con los representantes de todas las fes fue establecido para asegurar la audiencia justa para toda la gente. Tal tolerancia religiosa era unheard de.[PARAGRAPH:2]Aunque el Khazars era gente del nomadiv, la conversión al judaísmo optó rápidamente por un existance colocado con Khazaria que prosperaba de cultivar, de la producción de mercancías, y de negociar. Khazaria también desempeñó un papel en la derrota de Persia en el 7mo siglo, aliándolo uno mismo con los turcos y el Byzantines. Allí wer también que una serie de guerras en el 8vo centurey contra los árabes que establecieron el souther de Khazaria confina en las montañas del Cáucaso. Sin embargo, el Khazars se asocia a un período de la paz a lo largo de la estepa porque fueron referidas más a comercio que la guerra.[PARAGRAPH:2]El Khazars era muy coopertive con sus vecinos tales que la estructura de Byzantines una pared para ellos en la ciudad de Sarkel a lo largo del río del poner. Los emporors Byzantine Justinian II y Constantina V ambos tomaron a esposa de Khazar. Khazar también trajo muchas nuevas tecnologías adentro puesto que los judíos de por todo el mundo vinieron en busca de un faro judío. Todo el esto ayudó a consolidar Khazaria y a hacerlo en una civilización cosmopolita y progresiva.[PARAGRAPH:2]En el grado más grande de los imperios en 850, estiró del negro al mar caspio. Los canales negociaban acoplamientos y el Khazars construyó la ciudad de Kiev, convirtiéndose en más adelante su capital. El aguantar de los capitales de Khazar era Itil. Tenía un poste que negociaba, un centro administrativo, y hearland religioso para los judíos. También tenía una mezquita islámica para servir a la población musulmana. La energía de Khazar terminó debajo de Svyatoslav, la regla de Kiev. Khazaria entonces fue asumido el control por el Pechenegs vecino, el Oghuz, y la gente Byzantine. Los comerciantes de Khazar hicieron frente a circunstancias difíciles durante estas épocas y toda la mención de ellas los extremos. El Penchenegs que tenía mucha de tierra de Khazar no se centró en comercio, y distrupted el comercio con Europa Oriental.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_QIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Qin were a dynasty that ruled China from 221 BC to 216 BC. The Qin are known as the first imperial dynasty.[PARAGRAPH:2]Feizi, a descendant of the ancient political advisor Gao Yao, was granted rule over Qin City. During the rule of King Xiao of Zhou, the eighth king of the Zhou Dynasty, this area became known as the state of Qin. In 897 BC, under the regency of Gonghe, the area became a dependency allotted for the purpose of raising and breeding horses. One of Feizi's descendants, Duke Zhuang, became favoured by King Ping of Zhou, the thirteenth king in that line. As a reward, Zhuang's son, Duke Xiang, was sent eastward as the leader of a war expedition, during which he formally established the Qin.[NEWLINE][TAB]Qin state first sent a military expedition into central China in 672 BC, though it did not engage in any serious incursions due to the threat from neighbouring tribesmen. By the dawn of the fourth century BC, however, the neighbouring tribes had all been either subdued or conquered, and the stage was set for the rise of Qin expansionism.[PARAGRAPH:2]Lord Shang Yang, a Qin statesman, introduced a number of militarily advantageous reforms from 361 BC until his death in 338 BC, and also helped construct the Qin capital, Xianyang. This latter accomplishment commenced in the mid-fourth century BC; the resulting city greatly resembled the capitals of other Warring States.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of Shang Yang's reforms, the most notable one was advocating the philosophy of Legalism, which encouraged practical and ruthless warfare. In contrast, during the Zhou Dynasty and the ensuing Warring States Period, the prevalent philosophy had dictated war as a gentleman's activity; military commanders were instructed to respect what they perceived to be Heaven's laws in battle. For example, during the Warring States Period, Duke Xiang of Song was at war with the state of Chu, and had an opportunity to attack the enemy force, commanded by Zhu, while they were crossing a river. Instead, however, he waited for them to finish crossing, and allowed them to marshal their forces. He was decisively defeated in the ensuing battle, and when, later, his advisors admonished him for such excessive courtesy to the enemy, he retorted, "The sage does not crush the feeble, nor give the order for attack until the enemy have formed their ranks." The Qin disregarded this military tradition, taking advantage of their enemy's weaknesses. A nobleman in the state of Wei accused the Qin state of being "avaricious, perverse, eager for profit, and without sincerity. It knows nothing about etiquette, proper relationships, and virtuous conduct, and if there be an opportunity for material gain, it will disregard its relatives as if they were animals." It was this Legalist thought combined with strong leadership from long-lived rulers, openness to employ talented men from other states, and little internal opposition that gave the Qin such a strong political base.[PARAGRAPH:2]Another advantage of the Qin was that they had a large, efficient army and capable generals. They utilised the newest developments in weaponry and transportation as well, which many of their enemies lacked. These latter developments allowed greater mobility over several different terrain types which were most common in many regions of China. Thus, in both ideology and practice, the Qin were militarily superior.[NEWLINE][TAB]Finally, the Qin empire had a geographical advantage due to its fertility and strategic situation, protected by mountains that made the state a natural stronghold. Its expanded agricultural output helped sustain Qin's large army with food and natural resources; the Wei River canal built in 246 BC was particularly significant in this respect.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the Warring States Period preceding the Qin Dynasty, the major states vying for dominance were Yan, Zhao, Qi, Chu, Han, Wei and Qin. The rulers of these states styled themselves as kings, rather than using the titles of lower nobility they had previously held. However, none elevated himself to believe that he had the "Mandate of Heaven," as the Zhou emperors had claimed, nor that he had the right to offer sacrificesâthey left this to the Zhou rulers.[PARAGRAPH:2]Before their conquest in the fourth and third centuries BC, the Qin suffered several setbacks. Shang Yang was executed in 338 BC due to a grudge by the leader King Wu over a student who had been executed because of Shang Yang's insistence that law applied even to nobility. There was also internal strife over the Qin succession in 307 BC, which decentralised Qin authority somewhat. Qin was defeated by an alliance of the other states in 295 BC, and shortly after suffered another defeat by the state of Zhao, because the majority of their army was then defending against the Qi. The aggressive statesman Fan Sui, however, soon came to power as prime minister even as the problem of the succession was resolved, and he began an expansionist policy that had originated in Jin and Qi, which prompted the Qin to attempt to conquer the other states.[NEWLINE][TAB]The Qin were swift in their assault on the other states. They first attacked the Han, directly east, and took the city of Yangdi in 230 BC. They then struck northward; the state of Zhao surrendered in 228 BC, and the northernmost state of Yan followed, falling in 226 BC. Next, Qin armies launched assaults to the east, and later the south as well; they took the Wei city of Daliang (now called Kaifeng) in 225 BC and forced the Chu to surrender by 223 BC. Lastly, they deposed the Zhou Dynasty's remnants in Luoyang and conquered the Qi, taking the city.[PARAGRAPH:2]When the conquests were complete in 221 BC, the leader of the Qin, King Zheng, who had first assumed the throne of the Qin state at age 13, became the effective ruler of China. He assumed his position as king with the abdication of his prime minister, Lu Buwei. He took on the name Qin Shihuang Di (meaning "First Emperor of the Qin"). The newly declared emperor ordered all weapons not in the possession of the Qin to be confiscated and melted down. The resulting metal was sufficient to build twelve large ornamental statues at the Qin's newly declared capital, Xianyang.[NEWLINE][TAB]In 214 BC Qin Shihuang secured his boundaries to the north with a fraction (100,000 men) of his large army, and sent the majority (500,000 men) south to seize still more land. Prior to the events leading to Qin dominance over China, they had gained possession of much of Sichuan to the southwest. The Qin army was unfamiliar with the jungle terrain, and it was defeated by the southern tribes' guerrilla warfare tactics with over 100,000 men lost. However, in the defeat Qin was successful in building a canal to the south, which they used heavily for supplying and reinforcing their troops during their second attack to the south. Building on these gains, the Qin armies conquered the coastal lands surrounding Guangzhou, and took the provinces of Fuzhou and Guilin. They struck as far south as Hanoi. After these victories in the south, Qin Shihuang moved over 100,000 prisoners and exiles to colonize the newly conquered area. In terms of extending the boundaries of his empire, the First Emperor was extremely successful in the south.[NEWLINE][TAB]However, while the empire at times was extended to the north, the Qin could rarely hold on to the land for long. The tribes of these locations, collectively called the Hu by the Qin, were free from Chinese rule during the majority of the Dynasty. Prohibited from trading with Qin Dynasty peasants, the Xiongnu tribe living in the Ordos region in northwest China often raided them instead, prompting the Qin to retaliate. After several campaigns and much effort, the region was conquered and agriculture was established; the peasants, however, were discontented and later revolted. The succeeding Han Dynasty also expanded into the Ordos due to overpopulation, but depleted their resources in the process. Owen Lattimore said of both Dynasties' attempts to conquer the Ordos, "conquest and expansion were illusory. There was no kind of success that did not create its own reaction." Indeed, this was true of the dynasty's borders in multiple directions; modern Xinjiang, Tibet, Manchuria, Inner Mongolia, and regions to the southeast were foreign to the Qin, and even areas over which they had military control were culturally distinct.[PARAGRAPH:2]Three assassination attempts were made on Qin Shihuang's life, leading him to become paranoid and obsessed with immortality. He died in 210 BC, while on a trip to the far eastern reaches of his empire in an attempt to procure an elixir of immortality from Taoist magicians, who claimed the elixir was stuck on an island guarded by a sea monster. The chief eunuch, Zhao Gao, and the prime minister, Li Si, hid the news of his death upon their return until they were able to alter his will to place on the throne the dead emperor's most pliable son, Huhai, who took the name of Qin Er Shi. They believed that they would be able to manipulate him to their own ends, and thus effectively control the empire. Qin Er Shi was, indeed, inept and pliable. He executed many ministers and imperial princes, continued massive building projects (one of his most extravagant projects was lacquering the city walls), enlarged the army, increased taxes, and arrested messengers who brought him bad news. As a result, men from all over China revolted, attacking officials, raising armies, and declaring themselves kings of seized territories.[NEWLINE][TAB]During this time, Li Si and Zhao Gao fell out among themselves, and Li Si was executed. Zhao Gao decided to force Qin Er Shi to commit suicide due to Qin Er Shi's incompetence. Upon this, Ziying, a nephew of Qin Er Shi, ascended the throne, and immediately executed Zhao Gao. Ziying, seeing that increasing unrest was growing among the people and that many local officials had declared themselves kings, attempted to cling to his throne by declaring himself one king among all the others. He was undermined by his ineptitude, however, and popular revolt broke out in 209 BC. When Chu rebels under the lieutenant Liu Bang attacked, a state in such turmoil could not hold for long. Ziying was defeated near the Wei River in 207 BC and surrendered shortly after; he was executed by the Chu leader Xiang Yu. The Qin capital was destroyed the next year, and this is considered by Derk Bodde, as well as other historians, to be the end of the Qin empire. Liu Bang then betrayed and defeated Xiang Yu, declaring himself Emperor Gaozu of the new Han Dynasty. Despite the short duration of the Qin Dynasty, it was very influential on the structure of future dynasties.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TIBET_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Tibetan Empire</English>
		<French>Tibetan Empire</French>
		<German>Tibetisches Reich</German>
		<Italian>Tibetan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tibetan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TIBET_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Tibet</English>
		<French>Tibet</French>
		<German>Tibet</German>
		<Italian>Tibet</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tibet</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TIBET_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Tibetan</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter:Neuter:Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TIBET_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Tibetan Empire</English>
		<French>Tibetan Empire</French>
		<German>Tibetisches Reich</German>
		<Italian>Tibetan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tibetan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TIBET_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Tibetan Empire</English>
		<French>Tibetan Empire</French>
		<German>Tibetisches Reich</German>
		<Italian>Tibetan Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tibetan Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_TIBET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Over the centuries the Yarlung Zangbo valley was the focus of ancient trade routes from India, China, and central Asia. Tibet emerged from an obscure history to flourish in the 7th cent. AD as an independent kingdom with its capital at Lhasa. Toward the end of the 12th century many Indian Buddhists, fleeing before the Muslim invasion, went to Tibet. In the 13th century Tibet fell under Mongol influence, which was to last until the 18th century. In 1270, Kublai Khan, emperor of China, was converted to Buddhism by the abbot of the Sakya lamasery. The abbot returned to Tibet to found the Sakya dynasty (1270-1340) and to become the first priest-king of Tibet. In 1720, the Ch'ing dynasty replaced Mongol rule in Tibet. China thereafter claimed suzerainty, often merely nominal.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the 18th century, British authorities in India attempted to establish relations with Lhasa, but Tibet maintained its traditional seclusion. Meanwhile, Ladakh, long part of Tibet, was lost to the rulers of Kashmir, and Sikkim was seized by Britain. In 1906, Britain recognized China's suzerainty over Tibet. However, the Tibetans were able to expel the Chinese from Tibet and reassert their independence (1912). After the death (1933) of the 13th Dalai Lama, Tibet gradually drifted back into the Chinese orbit. By a Tibetan-Chinese agreement (May, 1951), Tibet became a national autonomous region of China under the traditional rule of the Dalai Lama, but under the actual control of a Chinese Communist Commission.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Communist government introduced far-reaching land reforms and sharply curtailed the power of the monastic orders. Full-scale revolt broke out in March, 1959. The Chinese suppressed the rebellion, but the Dalai Lama managed to escape to India.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Chinese adopted brutal repressive measures, provoking charges from the Dalai Lama of genocide. Landholdings were seized, the lamaseries were virtually emptied, and thousands of monks were forced to find other work. In 1965 the Tibetan Autonomous Region was formally established. The Cultural Revolution, with its antireligious orientation, was disastrous for highly religious Tibet. Religious practices were banned and over 4,000 monasteries were destroyed. Though the ban was lifted in 1976 and some Buddhist temples have again been in operation since the early 1980s, Tibetans continue to complain of widespread discrimination by the Chinese. Several protests in Tibet in the late 1980s and early 1990s were violently suppressed by the Communist government and martial law was imposed in 1989. Demonstrations against Chinese rule have nevertheless continued. Moreover, in recent years other countries have increasingly raised the issue of human-rights violations in Tibet, and have pressured the Chinese government to moderate their stance in that region.</English>
		<French>in French</French>
		<German>in German</German>
		<Italian>in Italian</Italian>
		<Spanish>in Spanish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MACCABEES_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Judah</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Judah</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Judah</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Judah</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Judah</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MACCABEES_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Maccabean Empire</English>
		<French>Maccabean Empire</French>
		<German>Maccabean Empire</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Judah</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Judah</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MACCABEES_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Judah</English>
		<French>Judah</French>
		<German>Judah</German>
		<Italian>Judah</Italian>
		<Spanish>Judah</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MACCABEES_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Hebrew</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter:Neuter:Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MACCABEES_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Judah</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Judah</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Judah</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Judah</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Judah</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MACCABEES_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Judah</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Judah</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Judah</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Judah</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Judah</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MACCABEES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Maccabees also spelled Machabees were a Jewish rebel army that took control of Judea, which had been a client state of the Seleucid Empire. They founded the Hasmonean dynasty, which ruled from 164 BCE to 63 BCE, reasserting the Jewish religion, expanding the boundaries of the Land of Israel and reducing the influence of Hellenism and Hellenistic Judaism.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the 2nd century BCE, Judea lay between the Ptolemaic Kingdom based in Egypt and the Seleucid empire based in Syria, kingdoms formed after the death of Alexander the Great (336-323 BCE). Judea had been under Ptolemaic rule, but fell to the Seleucids around 200 BCE. Judea at that time had been affected by the Hellenization begun by Alexander. Some Jews, mainly those of the urban upper class, notably the Tobiad family, wished to dispense with Jewish law and to adopt a Greek lifestyle. According to the historian Victor Tcherikover, the main motive for the Tobiads' Hellenism was economic and political. The Hellenizing Jews built a gymnasium in Jerusalem, competed in international Greek games, "removed their marks of circumcision and repudiated the holy covenant".[PARAGRAPH:1]When Antiochus IV Epiphanes (ca. 215164 BCE), became ruler of the Seleucid Empire in 175 BCE, the High Priest in Jerusalem was Onias III. To Antiochus, the High Priest was merely a local governor within his realm, who could be appointed or dismissed at will, while to orthodox Jews he was divinely appointed. Jason, the brother of Onias, bribed Antiochus to make him High Priest instead. Jason abolished the traditional theocracy and constituted Jerusalem as a Greek polis. Menelaus then bribed Antiochus and was appointed High Priest in place of Jason. Menelaus had Onias assassinated. Menelaus' brother Lysimachus stole holy vessels from the Temple, causing riots that led to his death. Menelaus was arrested for Onias' murder, and was arraigned before Antiochus, but he bribed his way out of trouble. Jason subsequently drove out Menelaus and became High Priest again. Antiochus pillaged the Temple, attacked Jerusalem and "led captive the women and children". From this point onwards, Antiochus pursued a zealous Hellenizing policy. He made possession of the Torah a capital offense and burned the copies he could find. He banned many traditional Jewish religious practices: Jewish sacrifice was forbidden, sabbaths and feasts were banned. Circumcision was outlawed, and mothers who circumcised their babies were killed along with their families. Altars to Greek gods were set up and animals prohibited to Jews were sacrificed on them. The idol of Olympian Zeus was placed on the altar of the Temple. The motives of Antiochus are unclear. He may have been incensed at the overthrow of his appointee, Menelaus, or he may have been responding to an orthodox Jewish revolt that drew on the Temple and the Torah for its strength and encouraged by a group of radical Hellenizers among the Jews.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the narrative of I Maccabees, after Antiochus issued his decrees forbidding Jewish religious practice, a rural Jewish priest from Modiin, Mattathias the Hasmonean, sparked the revolt against the Seleucid Empire by refusing to worship the Greek gods. Mattathias killed a Hellenistic Jew who stepped forward to offer a sacrifice to an idol in Mattathias' place. He and his five sons fled to the wilderness of Judah. After Mattathias' death about one year later in 166 BCE, his son Judas Maccabee led an army of Jewish dissidents to victory over the Seleucid dynasty in guerrilla warfare, which at first was directed against Hellenizing Jews, of whom there were many. The Maccabees destroyed pagan altars in the villages, circumcised boys and forced Jews into outlawry. The term Maccabees as used to describe the Jewish army is taken from the Hebrew word for "hammer".[PARAGRAPH:1]The revolt itself involved many battles, in which the Maccabean forces gained notoriety among the Syrian army for their use of guerrilla tactics. After the victory, the Maccabees entered Jerusalem in triumph and ritually cleansed the Temple, reestablishing traditional Jewish worship there and installing Jonathan Maccabee as high priest. A large Syrian army was sent to quash the revolt, but returned to Syria on the death of Antiochus IV. Its commander Lysias, preoccupied with internal Syrian affairs, agreed to a political compromise that restored religious freedom.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Jewish festival of Hanukkah celebrates the re-dedication of the Temple following Judah Maccabee's victory over the Seleucids. According to Rabbinic tradition, the victorious Maccabees could only find a small jug of oil that had remained uncontaminated by virtue of a seal, and although it only contained enough oil to sustain the Menorah for one day, it miraculously lasted for eight days, by which time further oil could be procured.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following the re-dedication of the temple, the supporters of the Maccabees were divided over the question of whether to continue fighting or not. When the revolt began under the leadership of Mattathias, it was seen as a war for religious freedom to end the oppression of the Seleucids. However, as the Maccabees realized how successful they had been, many wanted to continue the revolt and conquer other lands with Jewish populations or to convert their peoples. This policy exacerbated the divide between the Pharisees and Sadducees under later Hasmonean monarchs such as Alexander Jannaeus. Those who sought the continuation of the war were led by Judah Maccabee.[PARAGRAPH:1]On his death in battle in 160 BCE, Judah was succeeded as army commander by his younger brother, Jonathan, who was already High Priest. Jonathan made treaties with various foreign states, causing further dissent between those who merely desired religious freedom and those who sought greater power.[PARAGRAPH:1]In 142 BCE Jonathan was assassinated by Diodotus Tryphon, a pretender to the Seleucid throne, and was succeeded by Simon Maccabee, the last remaining son of Mattathias. Simon gave support to Demetrius II Nicator, the Seleucid king, and in return Demetrius exempted the Maccabees from tribute. Simon conquered the port of Joppa where the Gentile population were 'forcibly removed', the fortress of Gezer and expelled the garrison from the Acra in Jerusalem. In 140 BCE, he was recognised by an assembly of the priests, leaders and elders as high priest, military commander and ruler of Israel. Their decree became the basis of the Hasmonean kingdom. Shortly after, the Roman senate renewed its alliance with the Hasmonean kingdom and commanded its allies in the eastern Mediterranean to do so also. Although the Maccabees won autonomy, the region remained a province of the Seleucid Empire and Simon was required to provide troops to Antiochus VII Sidetes, the brother of Demetrius II. When Simon refused to give up the territory he had conquered, Antiochus took them by force.[PARAGRAPH:1]Simon was murdered in 134 BCE by his son-in-law Ptolemy, and was succeeded as high priest and king by his son John Hyrcanus I. Antiochus conquered the entire district of Judea, but refrained from attacking the Temple or interfering with Jewish observances. Judea was freed from Seleucid rule on the death of Antiochus in 129 BCE.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hasmonean rule lasted until 63 BCE, when the Roman general Pompey captured Jerusalem and subjected Israel to Roman rule, while the Hasmonean dynasty itself ended in 37 BCE when the Idumean Herod the Great became king of Israel and king of the Jews.</English>
		<French>in French</French>
		<German>in German</German>
		<Italian>in Italian</Italian>
		<Spanish>in Spanish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VIETNAM_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Au Lac</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Au Lac</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Au Lac</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Au Lac</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Au Lac</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VIETNAM_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Empire of Nam Viet</English>
		<French>Empire of Nam Viet</French>
		<German>Empire of Nam Viet</German>
		<Italian>Empire of Nam Viet</Italian>
		<Spanish>Empire of Nam Viet</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VIETNAM_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Au Lac</English>
		<French>Au Lac</French>
		<German>Au Lac</German>
		<Italian>Au Lac</Italian>
		<Spanish>Au Lac</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VIETNAM_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Vietnamese</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter:Neuter:Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Qin:Qin:Qin:Qin</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VIETNAM_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Au Lac</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Au Lac</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Au Lac</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Au Lac</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Au Lac</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VIETNAM_DESC_VASSAL</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Au Lac</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Au Lac</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Au Lac</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Au Lac</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Au Lac</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VIETNAM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>au Lac was the name of the Vietnamese state from 257 BC to 207 BC, succeeding Van Lang and preceding Nam Viet. The capital was Co Loa Citadel, located 35 km north of modern Hanoi.[PARAGRAPH:2]The country was created by Thuc Phan, who served as its only monarch, ruling under the royal title of An Duong Vuong and creating the Thuc Dynasty by uniting the mountainous Au Viet region (comprising what is today northernmost Vietnam and parts of southern China) with the more southerly Lac Viet (located in the Red River Delta of what is today northern Vietnam). Around 180 to 179 BC, Au Lac was conquered by Nam Viet, a kingdom that had its capital city, Panyu, around modern Guangzhou. Nam Viet rule lasted until 111 BC. In Vietnamese history, the rule of the Nam Viet kings is referred to as the Trieu Dynasty.</English>
		<French>in French</French>
		<German>in German</German>
		<Italian>in Italian</Italian>
		<Spanish>in Spanish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HEPHTHALITES_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Hephthalite</English>
		<French>Hephthalite</French>
		<German>Hephthalite</German>
		<Italian>Hephthalite</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hephthalite</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HEPHTHALITES_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Hephthalite Kingdom</English>
		<French>Hephthalite Kingdom</French>
		<German>Hephthalite Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Hephthalite Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hephthalite Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HEPHTHALITES_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Hephthalite Kingdom</English>
		<French>Hephthalite Kingdom</French>
		<German>Hephthalite Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Hephthalite Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hephthalite Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HEPHTHALITES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Hephthalites, also known as the 'White Huns', were people of obscure origins, possibly of Tibetan or Turkish stock. They were called Ephthalites by the Greeks, and Hunas by the Indians. There is no definite evidence that they are related to the Huns. The White Huns were an agricultural people with a developed set of laws. They were first mentioned by the Chinese, who described them (A.D. 125) as living in Dzungaria. They displaced the Scythians and conquered Sogdiana and Khorasan before 425. They crossed (425) the Syr Darya (Jaxartes) River and invaded Persia. Held off at first by Bahram Gur, they later (483-85) succeeded in making Persia tributary. After a series of wars (503-13) they were driven out of Persia, permanently lost the offensive, and were finally (557) defeated by Khosru I. The White Huns also invaded India and succeeded in extending their domain to include the Ganges valley. They temporarily overthrew the Gupta empire but were eventually driven out of India in 528 by a Hindu coalition. Although in Persia they had little effect, in India the White Huns influenced society by altering the caste system and disrupting the hierarchy of the ruling families. Some of the White Huns remained in India as a distinct group.</English>
		<French>in French</French>
		<German>in German</German>
		<Italian>in Italian</Italian>
		<Spanish>in Spanish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Empire of the Huns</English>
		<French>Empire of the Huns</French>
		<German>Empire of the Huns</German>
		<Italian>Empire of the Huns</Italian>
		<Spanish>Empire of the Huns</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Huns were a group of nomadic people who, appearing from east of the Volga River, migrated into Europe c. AD 370 and established the vast Hunnic Empire there. Since de Guignes linked them with the Xiongnu, who had been northern neighbours of China 300 years prior to the emergence of the Huns, considerable scholarly effort has been devoted to investigating such a connection. However, there is no scholarly consensus on a direct connection between the dominant element of the Xiongnu and that of the Huns. Priscus mentions that the Huns had a language of their own; little of it has survived and its relationships have been the subject of debate for centuries. According to predominant theories, theirs was a Turkic language. Numerous other languages were spoken within the Hun pax including East Germanic, which was widely used as a lingua franca in the Hunnic territories.:202 Their main military technique was mounted archery.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Huns may have stimulated the Great Migration, a contributing factor in the collapse of the western Roman Empire. They formed a unified empire under Attila the Hun, who died in 453; their empire broke up the next year. Their descendants, or successors with similar names, are recorded by neighbouring populations to the south, east, and west as having occupied parts of Eastern Europe and Central Asia approximately from the 4th century to the 6th century. Variants of the Hun name are recorded in the Caucasus until the early 8th century.</English>
		<French>in French</French>
		<German>in German</German>
		<Italian>in Italian</Italian>
		<Spanish>in Spanish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AVARS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Empire of the Avars</English>
		<French>Empire of the Avars</French>
		<German>Empire of the Avars</German>
		<Italian>Empire of the Avars</Italian>
		<Spanish>Empire of the Avars</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SAXONS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Saxon</English>
		<French>Saxon</French>
		<German>Saxon</German>
		<Italian>Saxon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Saxon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SAXONS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Saxon Kingdom</English>
		<French>Saxon Kingdom</French>
		<German>Saxon Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Saxon Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Saxon Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SAXONS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Saxon Kingdom</English>
		<French>Saxon Kingdom</French>
		<German>Saxon Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Saxon Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Saxon Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SAXONS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Saxon Kingdom</English>
		<French>Saxon Kingdom</French>
		<German>Saxon Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Saxon Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Saxon Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROURAN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Rouran</English>
		<French>Rouran</French>
		<German>Rouran</German>
		<Italian>Rouran</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rouran</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROURAN_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Rouran Khanate</English>
		<French>Rouran Khanate</French>
		<German>Rouran Khanate</German>
		<Italian>Rouran Khanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rouran Khanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROURAN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Rouran Khanate</English>
		<French>Rouran Khanate</French>
		<German>Rouran Khanate</German>
		<Italian>Rouran Khanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rouran Khanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROURAN_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Rouran Khanate</English>
		<French>Rouran Khanate</French>
		<German>Rouran Khanate</German>
		<Italian>Rouran Khanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rouran Khanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROURAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Rouran, Juan-Juan or Zhu-Zhu was the name of a confederation of nomadic tribes on the northern borders of Inner China from the late 4th century until the middle 6th century. It has sometimes been hypothesized that the Rouran are identical to the Eurasian Avars who later appeared in Europe.[PARAGRAPH:2]The term Rouran is a Mandarin Chinese transcription of the pronunciation of the name the confederacy used to refer to itself. Ruanruan and Ruru remained in modern usage despite once being derogatory. They derived from orders given by the Emperor Taiwu of Northern Wei, who waged war against the Rouran and intended to intimidate the confederacy.[PARAGRAPH:2]The power of the Rouran was broken by an alliance of Göktürks, the Chinese Northern Qi and Northern Zhou dynasties and tribes in Central Asia in 552.</English>
		<French>Rouran Khanate</French>
		<German>Rouran Khanate</German>
		<Italian>Rouran Khanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rouran Khanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_REBEL_ROME_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Roman Rebellion</English>
		<French>Roman Rebellion</French>
		<German>Roman Rebellion</German>
		<Italian>Roman Rebellion</Italian>
		<Spanish>Roman Rebellion</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KALINKA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Kalinka</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Kalinka</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Kalinka</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Kalinka</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Kalinka</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KALINKA_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Empire of Kalinka</English>
		<French>Empire of Kalinka</French>
		<German>Empire of Kalinka</German>
		<Italian>Empire of Kalinka</Italian>
		<Spanish>Empire of Kalinka</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KALINKA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Kalinka</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Kalinka</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Kalinka</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Kalinka</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Kalinka</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KALINKA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Kalinkan</English>
		<French>Kalinkan</French>
		<German>Kalinkan</German>
		<Italian>Kalinkan</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kalinkan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KALINKA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kalinka</English>
		<French>Kalinka</French>
		<German>Kalinka</German>
		<Italian>Kalinka</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kalinka</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KALINKA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Kalinka was an early republic in central-eastern India, which comprised most of the modern state of Orissa/Utkal (pronounced as Orissa), as well as the Andhra region of the bordering state of Andhra Pradesh. It was a rich and fertile land that extended from the river Damodar/Ganges to Godavari and from Bay of Bengal to Amarkantak range in the West. The region was scene of the bloody Kalinka War fought by the Maurya Emperor Ashoka the Great of Magadha c. 265 BCE.[PARAGRAPH:2]Kharavela was the warrior emperor of Kalinka. He was responsible for the propagation of Jainism in the Indian Subcontinent but his importance is neglected in many accounts of Indian history. According to the Hathigumpha inscription near Bhubaneswar, Orissa, he attacked Rajagriha in Magadha, thus inducing the Indo-Greek king Demetrius to retreat to Mathura. But this inscription doesn't mean that he merged Magadha in Kalinka. But this shows his strong ties with the Shunga ruler Pushyamitra and Agnimitra who have just started their rule after uprooting the Mauryans.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Kharavelan Jain empire had a formidable maritime empire with trading routes linking it to Sri Lanka, Burma, Thailand, Vietnam, Cambodia, Borneo, Bali, Sumatra and Java. Colonists from Kalinka settled in Sri Lanka, Burma, as well as the Maldives and Malay Archipelago.[PARAGRAPH:2]The kingdom fell when Ashoka, leader of the Mauryan Empire led a war against the kingdom, leading to its bloody defeat in the Kalinka War. Some advocates of the Greater India theory claim this led to an exodus of people to Southeast Asia where they set up Indianized kingdoms, but there is no evidence for such a migration of people.</English>
		<French>in French</French>
		<German>in German</German>
		<Italian>in Italian</Italian>
		<Spanish>in Spanish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOJOSEON_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Gojoseon</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Gojoseon</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Gojoseon</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Gojoseon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Gojoseon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOJOSEON_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Empire of Gojoseon</English>
		<French>Empire of Gojoseon</French>
		<German>Empire of Gojoseon</German>
		<Italian>Empire of Gojoseon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Empire of Gojoseon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOJOSEON_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Gojoseon</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Gojoseon</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Gojoseon</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Gojoseon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Gojoseon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOJOSEON_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Gojoseon</English>
		<French>Gojoseon</French>
		<German>Gojoseon</German>
		<Italian>Gojoseon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gojoseon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOJOSEON_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Gojoseon</English>
		<French>Gojoseon</French>
		<German>Gojoseon</German>
		<Italian>Gojoseon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gojoseon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GOJOSEON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Gojoseon is said to have been an ancient Korean kingdom. The addition of Go, meaning "ancient," distinguishes it from the Joseon Dynasty; Joseon, is also romanized as Choson.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first mentioning of this name however does not appear until the Samguk Yusa and other medieval-era records, where Gojoseon is said to have been founded in 2333 BC by Dangun in the legend, who is said to be a Posterity of Heaven.[PARAGRAPH:2]Archaeological evidence of a Gojoseon-era civilization is found in the transition from the Jeulmun pottery to the Mumun pottery around 1500 BC, when groups of semi-sedentary small-scale agriculturalists occupied most of the Korean Peninsula. Local bronze production began around the 8th century BC. Based on Chinese records, some modern historians believe it developed from a loose federation into a kingdom between the 8th and 4th centuries BC, although this theory is contested.[PARAGRAPH:2]During its early phase, the capital of Gojoseon supposedly was located in Liaoning; around 400 BC, and was moved to Pyongyang, while in the south of the peninsula, the Jin state arose by the 3rd century BC.[PARAGRAPH:2]The territory of Gojoseon was invaded by the Han Dynasty of China during the Gojoseon-Han War in 108 BC, which is said to have led to the collapse of the kingdom into many small states, until the Proto-Three Kingdoms emerged and marked an own period in Korean history.[PARAGRAPH:2]The people of the Gojoseon-territory are referred to in Chinese records as Dongyi "eastern barbarians." Their language was probably a predecessor of the equally prehistoric Buyeo languages, and perhaps a form of Proto-Korean.</English>
		<French>in French</French>
		<German>in German</German>
		<Italian>in Italian</Italian>
		<Spanish>in Spanish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PONTUS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Pontus</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Pontus</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Pontus</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Pontus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Pontus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PONTUS_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Pontic Empire</English>
		<French>Pontic Empire</French>
		<German>Pontic Empire</German>
		<Italian>Pontic Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pontic Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PONTUS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Pontus</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Pontus</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Pontus</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Pontus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Pontus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PONTUS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Pontus</English>
		<French>Pontus</French>
		<German>Pontus</German>
		<Italian>Pontus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pontus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PONTUS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Pontic</English>
		<French>Pontic</French>
		<German>Pontic</German>
		<Italian>Pontic</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pontic</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PONTUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Pontus is a historical Greek designation for a region on the southern coast of the Black Sea, located in modern-day northeastern Turkey. The name was applied to the coastal region in antiquity by the Greeks who colonized the area, and derived from the Greek name of the Black Sea: Pontos Euxeinos ("Hospitable Sea"), or simply Pontos. Having originally no specific name, the region east of the river Halys was spoken of as the country en Pontoi, "on the (Euxeinos) Pontos", and hence acquired the name of Pontus, which is first found in Xenophon's Anabasis. The extent of the region varied through the ages, but generally it extended from the borders of Colchis (modern Georgia) until well into Paphlagonia in the west, with varying amounts of hinterland. Several states and provinces bearing the name of Pontus or variants thereof were established in the region in Hellenistic, Roman and Byzantine times. Pontus is known for the residence of the Amazons, with Amasia is not only applied for a city Amasya but for all of Pontus in Greek mythology.</English>
		<French>in French</French>
		<German>in German</German>
		<Italian>in Italian</Italian>
		<Spanish>in Spanish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WEI_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Wei</English>
		<French>Wei</French>
		<German>Wei</German>
		<Italian>Wei</Italian>
		<Spanish>Wei</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WEI_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Wei</English>
		<French>Wei</French>
		<German>Wei</German>
		<Italian>Wei</Italian>
		<Spanish>Wei</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WEI_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Wei</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Wei</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Wei</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Wei</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Wei</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WEI_EMPIRE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Jin Empire</English>
		<French>Jin Empire</French>
		<German>Jin Empire</German>
		<Italian>Jin Empire</Italian>
		<Spanish>Jin Empire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_WEI_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Wei</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Wei</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Wei</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Wei</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Wei</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NUMIDIA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Numidia</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Numidia</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Numidia</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Numidia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Numidia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NUMIDIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Numidia</English>
		<French>Numidia</French>
		<German>Numidia</German>
		<Italian>Numidia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Numidia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NUMIDIA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Numidia</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Numidia</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Numidia</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Numidia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Numidia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NUMIDIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Numidian</English>
		<French>Numidian</French>
		<German>Numidian</German>
		<Italian>Numidian</Italian>
		<Spanish>Numidian</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAKURIA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Makuria</English>
		<French>Makuria</French>
		<German>Makuria</German>
		<Italian>Makuria</Italian>
		<Spanish>Makuria</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAKURIA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Makuria</English>
		<French>Makuria</French>
		<German>Makuria</German>
		<Italian>Makuria</Italian>
		<Spanish>Makuria</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAKURIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Makuria</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Makuria</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Makuria</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Makuria</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Makuria</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAKURIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Makurian</English>
		<French>Makurian</French>
		<German>Makurian</German>
		<Italian>Makurian</Italian>
		<Spanish>Makurian</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIMYARITES_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Himyar</English>
		<French>Himyar</French>
		<German>Himyar</German>
		<Italian>Himyar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Himyar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIMYARITES_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Himyarite Kingdom</English>
		<French>Himyarite Kingdom</French>
		<German>Himyarite Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Himyarite Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Himyarite Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIMYARITES_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Himyar</English>
		<French>Himyar</French>
		<German>Himyar</German>
		<Italian>Himyar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Himyar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIMYARITES_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Himyarite</English>
		<French>Himyarite</French>
		<German>Himyarite</German>
		<Italian>Himyarite</Italian>
		<Spanish>Himyarite</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHENLA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Chenla</English>
		<French>Chenla</French>
		<German>Chenla</German>
		<Italian>Chenla</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chenla</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHENLA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Chenla</English>
		<French>Chenla</French>
		<German>Chenla</German>
		<Italian>Chenla</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chenla</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHENLA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Chenla</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Chenla</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Chenla</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Chenla</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Chenla</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHENLA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Chenlan</English>
		<French>Chenlan</French>
		<German>Chenlan</German>
		<Italian>Chenlan</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chenlan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Huns</English>
		<French>Huns</French>
		<German>Huns</German>
		<Italian>Huns</Italian>
		<Spanish>Huns</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Huns</English>
		<French>Huns</French>
		<German>Huns</German>
		<Italian>Huns</Italian>
		<Spanish>Huns</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of the Huns</English>
		<French>Kingdom of the Huns</French>
		<German>Kingdom of the Huns</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of the Huns</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of the Huns</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Hun</English>
		<French>Hun</French>
		<German>Hun</German>
		<Italian>Hun</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hun</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MACEDON_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Macedon</English>
		<French>Macedon</French>
		<German>Macedon</German>
		<Italian>Macedon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Macedon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MACEDON_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Macedon</English>
		<French>Macedon</French>
		<German>Macedon</German>
		<Italian>Macedon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Macedon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MACEDON_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Macedon</English>
		<French>Macedon</French>
		<German>Macedon</German>
		<Italian>Macedon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Macedon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MACEDON_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Macedonian</English>
		<French>Macedonian</French>
		<German>Macedonian</German>
		<Italian>Macedonian</Italian>
		<Spanish>Macedonian</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LOMBARDS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Lombard Kingdom</English>
		<French>Lombard Kingdom</French>
		<German>Lombard Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Lombard Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lombard Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LOMBARDS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Lombard Kingdom</English>
		<French>Lombard Kingdom</French>
		<German>Lombard Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Lombard Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lombard Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LOMBARDS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Lombard Kingdom</English>
		<French>Lombard Kingdom</French>
		<German>Lombard Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Lombard Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lombard Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LOMBARDS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Lombard</English>
		<French>Lombard</French>
		<German>Lombard</German>
		<Italian>Lombard</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lombard</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PALLAVAS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Pallava Kingdom</English>
		<French>Pallava Kingdom</French>
		<German>Pallava Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Pallava Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pallava Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PALLAVAS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Pallava Kingdom</English>
		<French>Pallava Kingdom</French>
		<German>Pallava Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Pallava Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pallava Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PALLAVAS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Pallava Kingdom</English>
		<French>Pallava Kingdom</French>
		<German>Pallava Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Pallava Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pallava Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PALLAVAS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Pallava</English>
		<French>Pallava</French>
		<German>Pallava</German>
		<Italian>Pallava</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pallava</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KALABHRAS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kalabhra Kingdom</English>
		<French>Kalabhra Kingdom</French>
		<German>Kalabhra Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Kalabhra Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kalabhra Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KALABHRAS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kalabhra Kingdom</English>
		<French>Kalabhra Kingdom</French>
		<German>Kalabhra Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Kalabhra Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kalabhra Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KALABHRAS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Kalabhra Kingdom</English>
		<French>Kalabhra Kingdom</French>
		<German>Kalabhra Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Kalabhra Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kalabhra Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KALABHRAS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Kalabhra</English>
		<French>Kalabhra</French>
		<German>Kalabhra</German>
		<Italian>Kalabhra</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kalabhra</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOORS_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Moorish Kingdom</English>
		<French>Moorish Kingdom</French>
		<German>Moorish Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Moorish Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Moorish Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOORS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Moorish Kingdom</English>
		<French>Moorish Kingdom</French>
		<German>Moorish Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Moorish Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Moorish Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOORS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Moorish Kingdom</English>
		<French>Moorish Kingdom</French>
		<German>Moorish Kingdom</German>
		<Italian>Moorish Kingdom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Moorish Kingdom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOORS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Moorish</English>
		<French>Moorish</French>
		<German>Moorish</German>
		<Italian>Moorish</Italian>
		<Spanish>Moorish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_XIONGNU_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Xiongnu Khanate</English>
		<French>Xiongnu Khanate</French>
		<German>Xiongnu Khanate</German>
		<Italian>Xiongnu Khanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Xiongnu Khanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_XIONGNU_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Xiongnu Khanate</English>
		<French>Xiongnu Khanate</French>
		<German>Xiongnu Khanate</German>
		<Italian>Xiongnu Khanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Xiongnu Khanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_XIONGNU_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Xiongnu</English>
		<French>Xiongnu</French>
		<German>Xiongnu</German>
		<Italian>Xiongnu</Italian>
		<Spanish>Xiongnu</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_XIONGNU_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Xiongnu</English>
		<French>Xiongnu</French>
		<German>Xiongnu</German>
		<Italian>Xiongnu</Italian>
		<Spanish>Xiongnu</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_XIANBEI_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Xianbei Khanate</English>
		<French>Xianbei Khanate</French>
		<German>Xianbei Khanate</German>
		<Italian>Xianbei Khanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Xianbei Khanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_XIANBEI_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Xianbei Khanate</English>
		<French>Xianbei Khanate</French>
		<German>Xianbei Khanate</German>
		<Italian>Xianbei Khanate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Xianbei Khanate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_XIANBEI_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Xianbei</English>
		<French>Xianbei</French>
		<German>Xianbei</German>
		<Italian>Xianbei</Italian>
		<Spanish>Xianbei</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_XIANBEI_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Xianbei</English>
		<French>Xianbei</French>
		<German>Xianbei</German>
		<Italian>Xianbei</Italian>
		<Spanish>Xianbei</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHAMPA_DESC_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Champa</English>
		<French>Kingdom of Champa</French>
		<German>Kingdom of Champa</German>
		<Italian>Kingdom of Champa</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kingdom of Champa</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHAMPA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Champa</English>
		<French>Champa</French>
		<German>Champa</German>
		<Italian>Champa</Italian>
		<Spanish>Champa</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHAMPA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Champa</English>
		<French>Champa</French>
		<German>Champa</German>
		<Italian>Champa</Italian>
		<Spanish>Champa</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHAMPA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Champan</English>
		<French>Champan</French>
		<German>Champan</German>
		<Italian>Champan</Italian>
		<Spanish>Champan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>